Kaoru, Tomoki. It's morning~.
Oh, you scared me.
Wake up. Hey.
-You guys sleep too much.
-Marumo, it's early and already you're so full of energy.
I'm always full of energy.
Come on, wake up and
get ready.
Tomoki, we're going.
-Gochisousama.
-Let's go.
-See you later.
Okay.
Be careful. See you later.
[Sasakura had already
forgiven Ayumi-san long time ago.]
[I'm going to return Kaoru and Tomoki to Ayumi-san.]
I'm back.
Takagi-san, the phone's ringing.
Takagi-san?
Huh? Oh.
What are you doing daydreaming?
Sorry.
Takagi-kun, maybe you're a little tired?
You have to take a break once in a while.
Raising kids wears you out, doesn't it?
Well, yes.
Takagi, can you come out for a while?
Ah...um. I'll be right there.
So, have you gotten used to this job?
Yes, I'm managing somehow.
Handling complaints must be a tough job.
What brings you here all of a sudden?
You've heard from Samejima-san, haven't you?
Yes, I heard.
So, do you think you might want to return to the Product Development Department?
Well...
You know, that ear cleaner pen.
Our department doesn't have anyone
who can come up with ideas like that right now.
Come back and do what you want to do again.
I personally think highly of your ideas.
Thank you.
Samejima-san, who's that person Takagi-san just went out with?
Ah, Umehara-kun from Product Development.
He's Takagi-kun's former boss.
-Finally, huh?
-Finally?
His return to Product Development.
Looks like Kake-Run-Run's getting favorable reviews there too.
Oh, Takagi-san,
-congratulations.
-Huh? What are you talking about?
Don't play dumb.
You got good news, didn't you?
No, nothing's been decided yet.
There you go again.
There's no reason for you to decline.
Well, no.
What are you going to do about the twins?
You may have to work a lot of overtime at Product Development.
There are things like after-school care
so you'll figure something out.
You're going to be busy, Takagi-kun.
About that...
I'm thinking of
returning the twins to their mother.
What? You're going to return them?
Yes, some things happened that made me decide.
You did well, working in an unfamiliar department while raising the kids.
Takagi-san, it's so sudden, are you going to be alright?
I'm fine, just fine.
There won't be any problems with overtime or anything anymore.
But if Takagi-san leaves,
-it's going to be quiet around here.
-We'll certainly
miss you.
But it's a great opportunity.
We'll all be rooting for you.
Huh? What's this?
I'm thinking about going to an onsen*.
(*hot spring resort)
-Why all of a sudden?
-Huh? Is it all of a sudden?
Never mind that.
I just feel like it.
Grown-ups need a break once in a while.
Right?
Surprisingly, kids need breaks too.
Kids don't need any.
But I'll let you come with me.
Yay.
Yay, Yay.
-Yay.
-Onsen, onsen.
Yay, yay.
-Thank you.
I'm planning to take the kids to an onsen over the weekend.
It's the first and last family trip.
What do you mean by last?
Oyaji-san.
I decided to return Kaoru and Tomoki to their mother.
You thought about it carefully, right?
Yes.
And what did they say?
I haven't told them yet.
But I'm sure they'll understand.
Will they really?
I don't think they'll be able to accept being told something like that all of a sudden.
After all, even though it was only for a short time,
you spent time together as a family.
How can you tell them to go to their mother all of a sudden.
But I think that's the best thing for them.
They'll have to accept it.
I see.
But you have to consider their feelings too.
You understand that, don't you?
Yes, I know.
You guys better rush.
We're barely gonna make the train.
Baggage okay, camera okay.
Twins okay, Mook okay.
Okay, okay, okay. Let's go.
Oh, Marumo. We left the laundry drying outside.
Ah~
Oh well, just leave it. Let's go.
Stop. Mook, stop.
Stop. Wait a minute.
Stop.
Tomoki, what's in here?
-Things I need for the trip.
-Marumo, we're gonna miss the train.
Let's go.
Yay.
We're here, we're here.
Okay, we're here.
Yay.
Onsen.
-Onsen, onsen.
-Okay, let's go.
Okay, here we go.
Give me a smile. Say cheese.
Here we go, Marumo.
Say cheese.
Wow, awesome.
Mook.
I wanna go in too.
-That's terrible.
-That's cruel.
What are you talking about?
This is as extravagant as you can get.
Here we go.
Smile, smile.
Say cheese.
Fish is much fresher here in Izu, isn't it?
It's same as usual anyway.
You haven't had abalone before, have you?
It's like it's still alive. Look.
Like it's still alive.
-What happened?
-Oh, no, it's nothing.
It was, what you might say, good enough to scream.
-No! No!
-I wanna eat sashimi too.
Everything's delicious.
No, Mook. No way. Hey.
M-Mook. Mook.
Stop, hey, hey.
Wait, wait a sec. Look.
Mook-san, why are you mad?
I don't get to do anything, all I get is dog food.
We're very sorry.
Forget it. I'm going to sleep.
Aw~. He's pouting.
Huh?
What's wrong?
Do you have to go bathroom?
Something's there.
What?
Is it a ghost?
No, there's no way.
Hey, it's, it's alright.
It's alright, I think.
I'm scared.
I'm scared, I'm scared.
I'm gonna open it. Here it goes.
You. What are you doing?
I was kinda starving to death.
My snack.
Ghost! It's a ghost!
Ah~ you scared me.
I heard a scream so...
-What happened?
-Well, the kids
said there's a ghost here.
-I'm sorry.
Oh, please.
Don't talk about ghosts.
Don't worry.
Ghosts won't appear in this room.
In this room? Huh?
-Wha-what? What about the others?
Others? Do they appear in other rooms?
Let's just go to sleep for now.
Sleep, sleep.
I'm scared. It's scary, scary, scary, scary
scary, scary, scary.
Can we sleep with you?
What? Hey, wait.
Alright, come on.
Feels nice.
Marumo, get that water over there.
No, it's hot.
It must feel good, huh?
Good luck.
Mook, wait. You wait here.
May all of us come to onsen again next year.
May we eat sashimi again.
May the two of them always stay healthy.
Oh, this is cute.
Okay, I'll buy you one then.
-Really?
-Yeah.
That bell's a charm against evil spirits.
If you carry that,
you won't be scared of ghosts anymore.
You can sleep alone anywhere.
"Who's scared of ghosts.
There's no such thing as ghosts."
"Someone half asleep must have made a mistake."
"But just a little,
just a little"
"I'm scared too."
We're home.
-We're back.
It's nice to be home, huh?
Marumo, can I take out the presents?
You can look at them, but don't open them, okay?
Oh, the laundry.
Not again.
I'm not buying anymore, you know.
-This is mine.
-This is Aya-chan's.
-This is Oyaji-san's.
Really, home is the best.
Sorry for calling you out on short notice.
Did something happen to the children?
No, the kids are fine.
I wanted to give this to you today.
Sasakura had it.
It was stashed away with some old pictures.
I'm sorry.
I read it without your permission.
[If it's at all possible, I want you to watch
Kaoru and Tomoki grow too.]
[I still consider Ayumi my family.]
[Can we all live together again?]
[I want you to stay by Kaoru and Tomoki.]
[That's what I wish for the most.]
Sasakura was waiting for Ayumi-san.
I made up my mind after I read that.
I'm returning Kaoru and Tomoki to you.
If that's how Sasakura felt,
I think Kaoru and Tomoki should live with you.
But...
To tell you the truth,
I want to keep on watching over them.
That was my intention when I took them in,
and that's how I lived with them.
I thought that was the thing to do.
But I decided to return them.
Are you sure?
Ayumi-san, Sasakura was carefully holding on to that letter.
Without throwing it away all this time.
Now that I know how he felt,
I have no choice but to return them.
Kaoru and Tomoki should live with Ayumi-san.
Mook-san,
how is the water temperature?
Shall I scrub your back?
Can we quit this game?
I'm tired of it.
Onee-chan, Marumo's late, huh?
Where did he go?
I don't know.
He said he had some important business.
I'm back. Both of you here?
Oh, Marumo's home.
-Welcome home.
Oh, Oba-chan's here too.
-Hello.
-Did you come for a visit?
Oba-chan, I'll show you our room. Come this way. Over here, over here.
You guys, do that later.
Come sit here.
But we wanna play.
You can play all you want later on,
so just wait a while.
-Okay?
-Alright.
Ayumi-san, please sit here.
You guys sit there.
I have something important to tell you.
Listen until I finish, okay?
-Mommy?
-Yeah.
That's a picture of your mommy.
I still think they look alike.
She looks like Oba-chan.
About that, Kaoru.
I lied.
The truth is, just like Kaoru said,
this oba-chan,
Ayumi-san, is your mommy.
What?
I'm sorry.
But Oba-chan said "No, I'm not."
Daddy said Mommy died too.
They were lies too.
Then where were you all this time, Oba-chan?
Mommy ran away from you two.
Why?
Because we were bad?
No.
Because I was a bad mommy,
I ran away from you and I was hiding all this time.
I missed not having a mommy.
Why didn't you come see us?
Why didn't you come when Daddy died too?
Listen, guys. Ayumi-san...
Abandoned us, right?
That's why you kept it from us. Liar.
Hey, Kaoru, Tomoki.
Hey, wait.
Marumo's a liar.
Liar.
Hey, Kaoru, Tomoki.
What happened?
I told them the truth.
Then they...
That's why we told you.
That you have to consider their feelings too.
I'll go.
They're confused right now, but
I'll talk to them so they'd understand.
I'm sure they'll understand.
I know what I did can't be forgiven.
-I know that.
-That's not true.
But I'm glad I got to tell them.
I'm glad I got to apologize to them.
Mamoru-san, thank you.
No, everything will be fine.
I'll make sure they understand.
What are you doing?
Aya-chan.
Is there something on your mind?
Yes. They're saying Oba-chan isn't Oba-chan
and that she's our real mommy.
You must have been surprised, huh?
Yes.
Aya-chan.
Yes?
I wonder why Oba-chan abandoned us.
Is it because she didn't like us?
If she didn't like you,
she wouldn't have come to see you again.
I don't think she abandoned you.
But everyone lied and kept it from us.
Marumo was lying too.
If you liked someone,
you wouldn't lie, would you?
It's bad to lie.
Yes, lying is bad.
I think so too.
But I think everyone had to try hard to lie to you because they love you.
That's weird, to have to try hard to lie.
If you found out,
you might not like them anymore, right?
But even then, they had to keep on lying to you.
Just think, they're lying to their loved ones.
Don't you think they had a very good reason?
Now that you know they were lying, do you dislike them now?
Really? I'm glad.
Let's go home.
Marumo-san was worried.
-I'm home.
Oh, hi.
-Where's Ayumi-san?
-She left a little while ago.
Both of them have calmed down, but
they're still a little confused.
Thank you very much.
You've been a big help.
Um...Do you really have to return them?
I know it's going to be
the hardest on you, but...
Even so, I'm going to miss them.
I enjoyed the time I spent with the three of you, and
and I realized how wonderful a family is by watching you guys.
Do you think those  guys will come to accept it?
What about you?
Are you going to be able to accept it?
When Ayumi-san first appeared,
somewhere in my mind I already knew.
That I should return those two.
Because she's their mother.
I see.
I don't really want to part with them.
I want to stay with them from now on too.
Ah~. How I wish I hadn't read that letter.
I'll miss them,
but now that I read it, I have no choice but to return them.
I have to convince myself.
It's sad, isn't it?
After all, you started out as total strangers and became a family.
But you did well.
You really did.
I'm impressed.
I'm coming, Mommy.
Tomorou, are you alright?
Kaoru-chan.
[You're alright now.
You were startled, weren't you?]
-Are you hurt?
-I'm okay.
Onee-chan, what's wrong?
Tomoki, what did you think when you found out that
-Oba-chan's our mommy?
-I don't know.
I was so surprised, I didn't know what to think.
How about you, Onee-chan?
I don't know either.
-I'm back.
-Welcome home.
Kaoru, Tomoki. Do you have a minute?
I'm going to write an okite.
Okite? The okite for today?
Yeah, watch carefully.
-Aren't you writing?
-Marumo?
I'm writing now.
We're family, even if we're apart.
Apart?
Marumo, why are you writing such an okite?
Are we going to be apart?
Because we fought?
Marumo, I'm sorry for calling you a liar.
I won't say it anymore.
So let's stay together.
Huh, Marumo?
I wanna be with Marumo.
Let's always stay together.
I don't want us to be apart.
Marumo.
You look pathetic.
What's with that "Marumo." Seriously.
-But...
-Listen. People grow up.
In the future, Kaoru will grow up to be a gal,
Tomoki will grow up to be a cool dude.
Then
you guys won't be needing this dinky house, would you?
You'd be sick and tired of this messy place.
That's not true.
That's why you should get out of here ahead of time.
You'll be sad and lonely now,
but forget about it right away.
I've made up my mind.
But Kaoru and Tomoki don't have a place to live.
If we don't have Marumo,
we won't have a place to sleep.
So let's stay together.
If Marumo doesn't fix our meals,
we'll get hungry. So...
You have your mommy, don't you?
You're going to live with your mommy.
-Mommy?
-Yeah.
Your mommy didn't abandon you.
Your mommy was sick all this time.
She was battling her illness all by herself.
Your daddy was rooting for your mommy as he was taking care of you guys.
He lied when he said she died to hide her illness from you.
But your mommy's well now.
That's why you're going back to her.
That's what your daddy wanted too.
-I don't wanna.
-Crying's not gonna work.
You're going to your mommy.
I don't care if I don't have a mommy.
If we have to be separated from Marumo,
-I don't need a mommy.
-Tomoki.
Do you know how much your mommy loves you guys?
She loved you, and loved you...
she loved you so much that her heart got sick.
Even then...
Even then, because she wanted to see you guys,
she got better all by herself,
and returned as your healthy mommy.
Don't ever say that you don't need your mommy.
Don't ever say you don't need your family.
But I'm never gonna accept it.
I don't care about any okite.
Hey, Tomoki.
Hey, can't you abide by the okite?
Hey. Don't you know that's our family's valuable okite?
What's the matter, Mook?
[Think of it as our promise so that we can live in harmony
from now on.]
[We're family, so say what we want to each other.]
[It's okay to do so, that's what it means.]
[A family stamp.
See, everyone's together, right?]
Tomoki.
Onee-chan, is Marumo mad?
I wonder if he's mad because I tore the Okite Notebook.
I don't know. He's not home yet.
I don't want to be separated from Marumo.
I want to be with him.
Onee-chan too, right?
Onee-chan, you don't mind being separated?
I do, but there's no exception to Marumo's okite.
Hey, I bought some ice cream,
Kaoru, Tomo...
We can't break the okite Marumo made.
It's the family's okite.
But today's okite is wrong.
Marumo's okite was never wrong.
Daddy died and isn't here anymore, but
we're not lonely anymore, are we?
We get along with Aya-chan and Oyaji-san and
our friends at school, right?
That's because Marumo wrote the okite for us.
That's what I think.
Okite...
If we're separated from Marumo, he won't be writing okite for us anymore, huh?
He won't be writing them anymore.
But we have to try our best.
Let's abide by the last okite too
and get praised by Marumo.
Let's say bye bye to Marumo with a smile.
Oh, but I hope Mommy doesn't get sick again.
Your mommy won't get sick again.
The 4 years she was apart from you,
your mommy never stopped thinking about you guys.
Wasn't that castella she brought for your birthday delicious?
How can she make
something that delicious if she didn't cherish you guys.
Do you still think that your mommy will get sick again?
She was watching over you guys on sports day too.
A mommy like that won't get sick again.
Even when you were apart, you guys and your mommy were always family.
We are too.
Even if we're separated from now on,
we're family even if we're apart.
But even if we're family, it's sad to be apart.
Don't say such a thing.
We were able to become a real family in such a short time.
There's no need to be sad.
Because you guys and I will be family for the rest of our lives.
Am I wrong, Kaoru?
We're family, aren't we?
Yes.
Tomoki, we're a real family, aren't we?
-Yes.
-We're family.
That doesn't change no matter where we go,
no matter if we're apart.
Marumo.
What is it?
Did you buy ice cream?
Are you kidding, at a time like this?
Shall we eat together?
It's melting.
That's okay. Ice cream's good when it's like this.
Gosh, it's way too late.
What, did everyone already leave?
That's cold.
I'm back, but one's around to hear me.
Wah!
-Takagi-kun, congratulations!
-Congratulations.
Congratulations.
-What, a farewell party?
-Were you surprised?
It's a surprise to celebrate your reassignment.
Come over here.
I'll propose a toast.
Wait, wait, wait.
Hey, wait.
Alright, everyone, in celebration of Takagi-kun's reassignment to Product Development.
Ready?
Happy send-off. Cheers.
-Cheers.
-W-w-w-w-wait.
Wait, it's not official yet, and
-a reassignment notice hasn't been issued either.
-What are you talking about?
It's a done deal.
It's better to celebrate early.
Mashima-san was concerned that Takagi-san's been down lately and planned it.
Mashima did?
Congratulations.
-Congratulations.
Everyone.
Then a word from Takagi-san, please.
Uh...ah...um...
Um...Thank you, everyone.
Really, thanks.
Although it was only for a short time, it was fun.
Everything was new to me.
[We're very sorry for what happened.]
Like having to take a middle-aged lady's caustic remarks.
[We're very sorry.]
And apologizing desperately.
I couldn't get used to the fact that it was my job to be complained at.
But the experience I got here
might be pretty invaluable to me.
[A minor complaint
may lead to a hit merchandise.]
[Customers' opinions are a mountain of gold.]
[We should cherish them.]
People's feelings go into using even one pencil or one notebook.
[Boys are pretty simple-minded, aren't they?]
[He must have felt smarter or something
just because he got a brand new notebook.]
[It's like he got motivated suddenly.]
[It means that stationery isn't just supplies.]
Like I realized many things like that.
Takagi-san, is something wrong?
-No.
-There you go, in a daze again.
Don't worry unnecessarily about us.
No, that's not it.
Ever since I heard about this reassignment,
I've had this nagging feeling.
I finally realized what that is.
I'm not going to Product Development after all.
-What?
-You're not going to Product Development?
That's right. I'm staying here.
But why?
I just remembered that I was able to change because I came here.
I finally realized that.
If I stay here, I feel I can help develop products
by coming up with ideas that aren't just self-serving.
That's my job.
Are you sure?
-Yes.
-Won't you regret it?
-Not at all.
-That's so like Takagi-san.
-I'm relieved.
-Kana-san.
I'm glad.
Mashima-kun, aren't you relieved too?
I really don't care one way or the other,
but it's true it's easier for me when we make apology visits if he stayed.
Let's not talk about that anymore.
Here's to
continued good working relationship.
-Cheers.
Cheers.
Alright, everyone.
Let's eat, let's eat.
Takagi-kun, Customer Service is a pretty interesting place, isn't it?
Yes, it's interesting and I'm also grateful.
That goes for me too.
Having a guy like you in Customer Service,
we feel reassured.
I have a feeling we can still change too.
Is there any squid left?
Okay, done.
Gochisousama.
-We're going first.
-Okay.
-Gochisousama.
-Oh, excuse me.
That will be 1,950 yen.
Oh, yes.
Keep the change.
Thank you.
-Thanks.
-Was that a boy?
Or a girl?
Okay, it's ready. Here you go.
Wow~.
That's awesome. It's a wiener zoo.
Looks like Marumo-san might be late.
-Maybe we should start without him.
-Here you go.
Itadakimasu.
How is it. Good?
Kujirice is the best.
Is this the last time I'll be making the wieners?
-Aya-chan, thank you.
Everything was delicious.
Thanks.
Ask your mommy to make it too, okay?
Kaoru, Tomoki.
You have to eat everything your mommy makes for you.
I'm home. Sorry I'm late.
-Hey.
-Welcome home.
Wow, what's this, a zoo?
The Kujirice looks fancier than usual too.
Yeah, Dad's fired up today.
Here, Mamoru.
Yours is ready too.
That's huge.
You outdid yourself on this one.
Aya, this too.
-Oh, okay.
-Itadakimasu.
-There's lots more.
-Wow, fancy. This is awesome.
It's finally tomorrow, huh?
Yes. Tomorrow.
But I'm relieved they're both in good spirits.
Yeah, I'm relieved too.
If they started crying on me,
I couldn't see them off with a smile.
Yes.
It was like that when Aya got married.
"Dad, thank you for taking care of me all these years."
She never did say anything like that.
Just as usual, we ate, took a bath,
said "good night" and went to bed
and the next day she got married.
Like she was just stepping out for a while.
That's so like Aya-chan.
To be honest, I felt lonely,
but I couldn't show that.
I understand.
But Mamoru,
you're not left with just loneliness.
After you see your child off,
you can puff up a wee bit with pride.
Puff up?
That maybe you finally attained parenthood.
You can puff up with pride.
Puff up with pride, huh?
Well, we can thank the kids for that too.
You finally become a parent after going through tough times.
Who's raising who, huh?
That's true.
But that Aya
promptly came back.
Like she just went to the convenience store or something, she said "I'm home."
That's so like Aya-chan.
I wish someone would take her one more time.
I want to puff up with pride as a parent just one more time.
Then don't chitchat and go to sleep, okay?
Good night.
-Aya-chan.
-Hm?
Look after Marumo, okay?
Marumo's no good by himself.
-Okay, got it.
-Good night.
Say, Mook.
You look after Marumo too, okay?
I know.
-Good night.
Having a hard time going to sleep?
Don't worry.
Everything will be fine if you follow the okite.
Okay, this should do it for now.
I'll send the rest a little at a time, okay?
How long are you guys gonna be eating?
-Marumo, another helping.
-No.
If you eat three bowls
you'll be a fatso for sure.
There'll be no turning back.
But I have to eat a lot while I can
because I have to say good bye to Boss.
Boss, it was only for a short time, but
thank you for your hard work.
I shall be forever be indebted to you.
Alright, then.
Take that with you.
-Really?
-Boss, please continue to treat me favorably.
-Please.
-Yup, same here.
It's time.
We gotta get going.
Clear everything for now.
Put everything away.
We'll be back.
Huh? We'll be back?
Oops, that was a mistake.
Okay, we're going.
Hmm. Would a dog understand?
-Then Kaoru next. Switch.
-Okay, switch.
Kaoru, Tomoki.
-Hello.
Hello.
For now, this is their change of clothes for today and tomorrow,
and their everyday necessities.
I'll get the rest packed up later.
Thank you.
Thank you for everything.
Kaoru, take care.
You don't have to hold back anything from your mommy and let her baby you.
Tomoki.
Tomoki, you have to stop being a baby.
You're a boy,
so you have to protect your mommy and Kaoru in place of your daddy.
Got it.
Stay close just like you've been.
Don't fight.
And...
I guess that's enough. Anyway, stay healthy.
Aw~. The bus is here.
Ayumi-san, I entrust these two to you.
Yes.
-Marumo, bye bye.
-Take care.
Yeah, you guys too.
Oh, that's right.
-Here. You can have this.
-What's this dirty thing. I don't want it.
-Mook, bye bye.
Then...
Oh, that's right. Hey, hey, the okite.
The Okite Notebook's in the bag.
Don't forget the okite.
Take care.
-Don't forget.
-Marumo!
-Mook.
-Bye bye!
See you. Listen to your mom.
Mook! Marumo!
See you. Take care.
"Tomoki/We'll always love you/
We're always family/Kaoru"
[You guys wanna come to my place?]
[If you want to be together that much, come to my place.]
[Okay,]
[Takagi Marumo.]
[It's Mamoru.  Mamoru. What the heck is a Marumo?]
-[I'm hungry.]
-[Shall we eat something on the way home?]
-[Goma shio.]
[Don't get into that stuff.]
[I'm thinking about living with these kids.]
[-I want to stay with Marumo.
-Me too.]
[Marumo, let's play catch.]
[What was that?]
[You guys, we're not here to fetch balls, you know.]
[We're gonna answer real loud
so that Marumo can hear us.]
[Are you stupid?]
[Why did you believe what I said.]
[I don't have mommy or daddy, but I'm happy because I have Marumo.]
[It's okay because Marumo's with us.]
[I hate you, Marumo!]
[Stay together if you like each other and go our separate ways if you don't.]
[A family isn't something that should be taken lightly like that.]
[To stay together whether you like it or not, that's what family's all about.]
[-Thanks, Marumo.
-I love you, Marumo.]
Let's eat.
Oba-chan.
Yes?
Tomoki,
she's not Oba-chan, she's Mommy.
It doesn't matter if you call me Oba-chan or Mommy.
But...
Call me whatever makes you comfortable.
Then I want to call you Mommy.
Me too.
Can we call you Mommy?
Really?
You'll call me Mommy?
Thank you.
Mommy.
So you didn't die.
You were surprised, weren't you? I'm sorry.
Were you really sick?
-What?
-Marumo told us.
That Mommy was battling the illness all by herself.
Mommy, you were fighting all by yourself, weren't you?
I suppose so.
Mommy, sorry we weren't there with you.
Tomoki and Kaoru didn't know that Mommy was all alone.
Even if you get sick again, this time I'll be there to fight with you.
-Me too.
-Thank you.
Do you know, Mommy?
That family's the most important thing.
Marumo taught us.
Mommy.
Yes?
Thank you for being alive.
Thank you.
-Oh, that's right.
-What?
I forgot to say thank you to Marumo.
You're right. We forgot.
He gave us the Okite Notebook too.
-What is that?
-Okite Notebook.
The okite that Marumo made are written in here.
Okite Notebook?
It's a promise we make so that we can all live in harmony.
We promise with the okite.
Marumo thought of them all.
Marumo's bossy.
We have to abide by them.
There's no exception to the okite.
But because we abided by the okite,
we were really happy every single day.
Everything was as Marumo said.
We always lived in harmony.
-Mommy.
-Yes?
Marumo easily gets mad and bossy but
he gets lonely real easily too.
And he cries easily too.
I wonder if I'll get to see Marumo again.
I wonder if I'll get to say thank you.
They're really gone.
Mamoru.
Mamoru, thanks.
Yeah.
Huh? Mamoru?
Did you say Mamoru?
Are you, by chance, Sasakura?
You're Sasakura, aren't you?
What do you mean woof?
Speak up properly.
What's that?
You're not gonna talk anymore?
Hey.
I'm really all alone now.
Aya-chan. What's up?
Oh, the kids forgot these downstairs
so I thought you could send them with their other stuff.
Oh, thanks.
They're gone, aren't they?
Yeah.
It hasn't been this quiet in a long time, makes you feel restless, doesn't it?
Until now, the kids were here,
but I guess I shouldn't come barging in like this anymore.
No, I'm okay with it.
Now that they're not here,
we probably won't be seeing each other too much.
Well, I'm not sure about that.
How will it be?
Oh, I'll take those things the kids left behind.
Ah, yes.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Marumo, we're back.
Oh! Ah, you scared me.
What is it?
-I'm home.
Welcome home.
Or rather, what are you guys doing?
We thought Marumo might be crying and felt sorry for you
so we came back.
Marumo, what are you doing with Aya-chan?
Huh? What do you mean what? We were...
Just talking. You know, chitchatting?
That's right. We were exchanging chit and chat.
Yeah, that's what you call chitchatting. Yeah.
Oh? Where's Ayumi-san?
What happened to Ayumi-san?
-She's downstairs.
-What?
Ayumi-san, I'm sorry.
I thought I talked them into it.
Don't worry, I'll return them to you.
It's alright.
I'm the one who brought them here.
What?
From the time I left those children, for 4 years until today,
I'd been apologizing to them in my heart.
Now that they were coming back to me,
even though I knew they probably wouldn't forgive me,
I wanted to atone for my sin by raising them with great care.
But those kids
said to me, "Thank you for being alive."
They said "Thank you."
My feeling of rushing to make up was relieved a bit by that.
Mamoru-san,
thank you so much.
No, I didn't do anything.
The person who raised those children to be that way
isn't just Junichirou, but you as well, Mamoru-san.
That's what I thought after I read this.
So for a little bit longer,
please take care of the children.
Are you sure?
"We're family, even if we're apart."
Right?
-Yes.
-If we're family even if we're apart,
I'll go back to being a mother slowly, one step at a time.
You can see them anytime from now on.
There's no need to rush things.
Oyaji-san, I'm hungry.
Okay, I'll fix something for you then.
-For Mommy too.
-What, for Mommy too?
The whole family's going to eat together.
Marumo and Mommy are family, right?
Onee-chan,
what about Oyaji-san and Aya-chan?
Oyaji-san and Aya-chan are family too.
We're all family.
This is fun. It gives you a warm feeling.
Okay, Kaoru, Tomoki. Give me a hand.
Mommy. Make us your castella for us too.
-What?
-The castella from "Guri and Gura."
But...
Come on over here then.
Oh, shoot.
Kaoru, Tomoki, wake up. You're gonna be late.
Really.
We're late.
Hurry, hurry. Come on, hurry.
-Marumo, tie my hair.
-Oh, okay,
Tomoki, hurry.
Don't move, Kaoru.
Hurry, Tomoki. Hurry, Tomoki.
Okay, how's that.
Huh? It's straight. Yeah.
Okay.
Okay, okay.
Tomoki, finish eating.
We're gonna be late.
Let's go, let's go.
We're going.
-See you later.
-Okay.
-Okay, Tomoki, we're going.
-See you later.
Hey, Kaoru, what are you doing?
Hurry up, we're going.
Say, Marumo.
What?
Mook's acting strange lately, isn't he?
Yeah.
He doesn't talk at all anymore.
I wonder if something happened.
I guess I hadn't explained to you guys yet.
Mook won't be talking anymore.
-How come?
-Why?
But it's alright.
The Mook that talks will always be in our heart.
Right?
You're gonna be late.
Oh, he does talk.
Okay, I'm going then.
See you later.
What are you crying for, Marumo?
What~!
There's one more announcement.
-This is my girlfriend.
-I'm Hana.
What~!
Yea!