-Marumo?
-Hm?
-What are we having for dinner tonight?
-You're
-already worried about dinner?
-We haven't even had breakfast yet.
-But...
-Let's see...
Tonight, how about stir fried meat and vegetables?
-We had that yesterday too, didn't we?
-What are you talking about?
Yesterday we had stir fried vegetables.
The day before that was stir fried meat.
-They're completely different.
-Oh, yeah.
-Huh?
-Hm?
Okay, done.
That's right. You wanna go eat
something good this weekend?
Yay~.
Are you sure?
Yeah, I'm getting my bonus.
You get tired of eating eggs all the time, right?
How about sushi?
What will you have?
Ikura*? Or uni**? (*salmon roe; **sea urchin)
-Egg.
What, so you end up getting the same thing wherever you go.
But it's so good.
-Kohada*. (*shad)
-What?
But it's so good. Kohada.
Are you really a dog?
Yeah.
-Good morning.
-Morning.
Oh, Tami-san.
Where can I buy cheap cute
-children's clothes?
-Let's see.
-Are they for the twins?
-Yeah, we're getting our bonus this week, right?
I thought I'd buy them new clothes.
Kids outgrow their clothes so fast.
That's the thing.
Plus, Tomoki gets them dirty, rips them...
I know what you mean. Boys tend to destroy their clothes.
In that respect, girls are more responsible.
Takagi-san, you sound like a real father.
What? Really?
Come to think of it, there were some ads in today's paper.
This, this, this, this.
Oh, this will be nice for Kaoru-chan.
Which one? This? This? That's nice.
-What about this one? For Tomoki-kun.
-Good.
-How about this?
-This? This is nice.
That's very Kaoru.
Oh, this is nice for Kaoru-chan too.
Wait. This isn't Kaoru's style.
Hello, this is Kujira.
This is Tomizawa... Oh, Aya?
Tatsuya?
Good night.
[It's not going to work after all, is it?]
[I'm sorry.]
Excuse me.
Makimura-san.
I hope we can go back to being the co-workers we were before.
Back to laughing and joking around as co-workers.
Takagi-san.
We should.  Yes, like before.
Aw.
I want to go to Manami-chan's house too.
Not today.
Just the girls are going to play.
Alright.
Then you be good and stay home with Mook, okay?
-See you later.
-Okay, bye bye.
Bye bye.
That's no fun.
I'm relieved you're looking well.
You look like you're doing well yourself.
Actually, I'm getting married again in the fall.
After we broke up,
I thought I'd never marry again,
but I guess you never know.
I see.
You've got to do better this time.
Yeah.
That's right.
I came to return this today.
You left it at the house.
I've been meaning to return it, but never got around to it.
Oh, Aya-chan?
-Aya-chan, are you getting married?
-What?
Hey, Tomoki.
What are you saying?
But I'm gonna be sad if she gets married.
I don't want her to go away.
I'm pretty sure I won't marry again.
Really? Who was that guy you were with?
My ex-husband. The person I divorced.
What does he want now?
Nothing important.  No need to be concerned.
So Aya-chan's not getting married.
I'm relieved.
Kaoru.
Wow, it's big.
Kaoru. Kaoru-chan, are you alright?
Oba-chan?
You're okay now.
You were startled, weren't you?
You're alright now.
Oba-chan.
Your clothes are going to get dirty.
It doesn't matter.  It doesn't matter.
I'm home.
-Hi, Marumo.
-Where's Kaoru?
She went to Manami-chan's house.
Oh.
Shall we go pick her up since it's getting kinda late?
It's cute.
How is it? Looks like it's just the right size too.
Shall we get this one?
Kaoru-chan went home already.
Where did that girl go?
Thanks, Manami-chan.
Tomoki, let's go.
Thank you for waiting.
How's Tomoki-kun? Is he doing well?
Yes, he's doing real well.
Are you getting along with Takagi-san?
Yes, Tomoki and Marumo, we're all buddies.
Marumo's not our daddy or mommy, but
he's always with us.
Because our daddy and mommy died.
Do you remember your mommy?
Not too well.
But she was really kind.
That's what Daddy said.
She was kind and very pretty
and loved Kaoru and Tomoki very much.
-Onee-chan.
-Kaoru.
-Oh, that's Onee-chan's umbrella.
-Where did Onee-chan go?
What should we do, Marumo?
-Onee-chan's gone away.
-Tomoki, come.
Excuse me
Watch out, watch out. Hey, watch it.
Kaoru's missing.
-Missing?
-She disappeared. What should we do?
Wait. First of all, calm down.
Um...so...That's
-the older sister of the twins, right?
-Yes, that's right.
What was she wearing today?
-She was wearing a white top today.
Her hair was tied in the back.
Wait. Come to think of it, seems I saw her somewhere.
-Where? Try to remember.
-Don't pull, don't pull.
Oh, it was there. By the canal. The canal.
-Kaoru.
-Onee-chan.
-That...
Huh?
It looks like Onee-chan's.
Marumo. Marumo.
What am I going to do if something happened to Kaoru?
Kaoru! Kaoru! Kaoru!
-Hello.
-Takagi-san,
Kaoru-chan's been found.
Kaoru, where were you?
I...
What are you doing here?
Oh, um..a passing car
splashed water on Kaoru-chan
and she got all dirty.
Yeah.
She saw her coincidentally on the street
and helped her.
I'm sorry. I couldn't just leave her there.
-Please leave.
-Why?
Do you remember what you said last time?
[I'll try not to
ever see those children again.]
Yes.
Wait, Marumo.
Why are you getting mad at Oba-chan?
She bought me a new dress.
There's one for Tomoki too.
Really?
-Thank you.
-Marumo, say
thank you to Oba-chan.
-Please mind your own business.
-Marumo.
-It's alright, Kaoru-chan.
-Please leave.
Wow, cool.
Wow, cool.  It fits just right, doesn't it?
It looks good on me, doesn't it?
That was awful, Marumo. What you said to Oba-chan.
I'm sorry I was late coming home.
But why did you get mad at Oba-chan?
She helped in when I didn't know what to do.
Oba-chan was really kind.
We ate pancakes together
and I had a really good time.
Don't see that Oba-chan anymore.
Why? Why can't I see her?
Because I said so.
That doesn't make any sense.
Isn't she Marumo's friend?
-Even if it doesn't make sense.
-That's strange, Marumo.
I don't care if it's strange or whatever, don't see her anymore!
No.
I don't understand.
You're terrible, Marumo.
No, no, no.
Kaoru!
Marumo. I hate you, Marumo.
I'm sorry, Aya-chan.
I don't mind you sleeping here at all, but are you sure it's okay with Marumo-san?
I don't care.
Marumo's being awful.
I used to get scolded by my dad all the time too.
Was Oyaji-san scary?
Yeah, he was scary.
He slapped me really hard one time.
But, you know, you're not going to find too many people
who cares enough to really scold you.
Although back then, I didn't realize that.
All he did was annoy me.
I hope you guys make up tomorrow.
Good night.
-Good night.
I'm the worst, aren't I?
When I heard about Ayumi-san,
I lost my head and before I knew it, I raised my hand.
What a petty guy I am.
Takagi-kun, I got a call from Product Development
-a little while ago.
-Yes.
That ball point pen with the ear cleaner.
They're thinking about marketing it for sale next year.
-What?
-Does that mean his proposal went through?
Although the final decision hasn't been made yet.
That's great, Takagi-kun.
-Awesome. I'm so happy for you.
-Thank you.
Oh, also, can I talk to you for a minute?
Yes?
Actually, although it's not like I've gotten official word,
but there appears to be
a movement at Product Development to bring you back.
What?
In your case, you have to think about the children too,
but just keep it in mind.
Yes.
Say, guys, did you have fun at school?
What do you like most at school?
Language? Music?
It's lunch time for me.
Figures. Why did I bother to ask.
Onee-chan...
what do you like most at school.
Marumo's asking.
-The 20-minute break.
-She said the 20-minute break.
Oh, so you like the 20-minute break.
Oh, that's right. What do you want to eat on Sunday?
What do you want to eat?
Onee-chan. What do you want to eat on Sunday? Marumo's asking.
-Spaghetti.
-What?
-She said hamburger.
-Spaghetti.
Busted.
You...seriously.
-Spa...
-Gochisousama.
Onee-chan.
Oh, that's right.
What's this?
"Put this against your ear.
Tomoki"
This?
Marumo, if you need something, call us with this.
-Huh?
-Put the cup to your mouth
when you want to talk.
Over.
I see.
But isn't it faster to talk directly?
Since you're in the next room. Over.
It's because you guys are fighting.
Hurry up and make up please. Over.
What's Kaoru doing? Over.
She's already asleep. Over.
What can I do to get Kaoru in a better mood. Over.
You can just say I'm sorry.
You're good at it, aren't you, Marumo?
You do it at work all the time. Over.
Work's different from home.
Over.
You're hopeless.
I'll teach you something good then.
It's a magical spell to make up.
You say, "Love ya, love ya, really love ya
Pekorinko Beam."
Huh? Huh? Love ya love ya what?
I'm totally lost. What? Over.
Love ya, love ya, really love ya
Pekorinko Beam. Over.
Wh-What are you saying?
Over. Over.
Everyone's saying that at school.
I'll teach you next time.
I'm going to sleep so I'm hanging up now.
Bye bye. Click.
W-w-w-wait. Wait.
Hello. Over.
Over. Oh.
Hey.
How about a drink?
The kids are already asleep, aren't they?
Yes.
Do you think I'm wrong?
It's making me think.
That in spite of the fact that their real parent is alive,
if it's the right thing to do to keep it a secret from those kids.
If I shouldn't let them meet properly.
While saying I'm doing this for those kids,
I'm wondering if I'm not letting them see her for my own selfish reason.
Mamoru.
I hit Kaoru.
I was surprised myself.
You know, I slapped Aya once too.
It must have been when she was in high school.
It was getting real late but she wasn't home, so
I worried and worried,
and after worrying so much, I got pissed and slapped her.
But isn't that alright?
-What?
-What I'm trying to say is
this thing with Kaoru happened because
you sincerely care for those kids, right?
You're already a good father to those kids.
Those kids are sure growing, Sasakura.
Tomoki grew 2 whole centimeters.
They learn all kinds of things at school every day.
Things like hiragana,
addition, subtraction,
new games,
and stupid jokes.
Tomoki, that kid...
he's always making us laugh by talking about
stuff like poop and butt.
Grade school boys are real fools, aren't they?
Kaoru is...she's strong-minded, isn't she?
She's stubborn
and doesn't hesitate to fight with the boys.
Really, I'd like to see their parent.
Yeah, that's you, huh?
Anyway,
the kids are doing well, so don't worry.
Sasakura.
I got in touch with Ayumi-san.
What should I do?
Should I
tell them that she's their mother and let them meet her?
Should I tell them that she was really alive and let them meet properly?
Am I being selfish if I don't let them meet?
Because those kids have become part of my life now.
Because I really love those kids.
After meeting Ayumi-san, Kaoru said she was really kind to her.
That she had a good time.
When I heard that, to be honest, I was really jealous of Ayumi-san.
Isn't that funny?
Why do I feel so shaken?
Sasakura, what do you think? Tell me.
I don't know what I should do.
What would you do?
Come on, tell me.
Tell me.
Onee-chan, Marumo's late, isn't he?
Clothes. They're circled.
I wonder if Marumo was going to buy them for us.
Onee-chan, you know that time
Marumo went splashing into the river.
What?
He jumped into the river looking for you.
He worried lots about Onee-chan.
He was yelling Kaoru, Kaoru many times.
Kaoru, are you still fighting with Mamoru?
You know, you may not understand very well right now, but
there's something I want you to remember.
When Mamoru hit Kaoru
he had his own reason.
Of course, a parent is human too, so
sometimes he may misunderstand and scold you, and
there may be times he says things only from his point of view.
But, you know,
I think Mamoru hit you because he
truly truly cherishes you.
Mamoru was really really
worried about you, you know.
Kaoru, you were sad when he hit you, weren't you?
It hurt, didn't it?
It pained Mamoru too for hitting you.
It saddened him and pained his heart.
I'm home.
Hi, Marumo.
Over.
I'm home.
You wanna go eat dinner?
Go for spaghetti? Over.
Okay. But we have to do our homework first.
Wait for a while. Over.
Homework?
I see. Good for you.
Alright. Over.
Sorry.
Let's go eat after we finish our homework, okay?
Later. Click.
Maybe I'll work on that for a change.
How's this?
Looks good.
Then let's color it.
Yeah, looking good.
Oh, must've fell asleep.
Hello. Hello. Over.
"Gold Medal
Marumo"
"To Marumo
Thank you taking care of us all the time."
"For making our meals."
"For tying my hair."
"For playing catch with us."
"Thank you."
"Even though Marumo has a face like cat,
you're the coolest in the whole world."
"Even though you're not Daddy or Mommy,
we love Marumo the most in the whole world."
"Kaoru"
"Tomoki"
Excuse me.
Are the kids here?
Oh.
They took Mook for a walk with Aya.
Thanks.
Kaoru, Tomoki.
It's Marumo.
This. This.
Yeah. We wrote it together.
I never got a gold medal before.
I never got first place in anything.
They said they were going to give it to Marumo-san
and they worked on it secretly.
I never thought I'd get something like this from you guys.
Marumo, do you know what today is?
Today is June 19. It's Father's Day.
Thanks for always taking care of us.
Marumo, thank you.
You guys...
Marumo does mommy's job too, so
we decided that Mother's Day is Marumo's day too.
Mother's Day and Father's Day are both Marumo's Day.
Oh, Marumo. What about the magical spell?
Onee-chan.
Ready.
Love ya, love ya, really love ya
Pekorinko Beam.
You finally made up, so don't fight anymore.
Okay, then today's okite is gonna be Pekorinko Beam.
-Right, Kaoru?
-Yeah, let's do that.
-Let's do that.
-You guys have okite, huh?
Yeah.
It's our promise so that we can live in harmony.
Really.
What other ones do you have?
Kids will be kids.
Dogs will be dogs.
-What's that about?
-And enryo is muryou*. (*enryo-to hold back; muryou-free)
That's supposed to be enryo is muyou*. (muyou-unnecessary)
There, all ready.
Aya's Deluxe Father's Day Special Dinner.
Wow. Looks yummy.
-Looks delicious.
-Don't they, though?
Awesome.
Did you make all this, Aya-chan?
-Yes, I did.
-Well, we won't know how they taste
until we try them, huh?
Hey, of course everything will be delicious.
Okay, let's eat, let's eat.
Oh, Tomoki.
Ready. Here you go, Oyaji-san.
-What? Oyaji-san?
-What is it?
-"Should massage coupon"
We'll do it anytime, okay?
That was nice, huh, Grandpa?
Tap tap on the shoulder...
Hey, who's a grandpa.
Thank you, thank you. I like it.
I'll make good use of them.
-Okay.
-Itadakimasu.
-Let's see...
-How did they turn out?
Yum.
Yeah, yum.
-Dad.
-Yes.
Here. Father's Day present.
You didn't have to get me anything.
-Can I open it?
-Go ahead.
-Oh, is it a hand towel?
-Yeah.
It's a kujira*. Nice design.
(*whale - name of the restaurant)
-Let's see.  How is it?
-Nice.
Is it? Thanks.
Families are amazing, aren't they?
I mean, even if they have a fight,
before you know it, they make up,
and they fight and make up again.
They'll probably keep on repeating that over and over.
I think I understand a little bit now why my marriage failed.
I was only thinking about myself.
All I could think about was things like
how much I was loved.
When I watch Takagi-san, I can see
how he's not thinking of anything but doing everything he can for those kids,
how he seriously agonizes over those kids.
And how those kids really love Takagi-san too.
I felt that they hearts are bound together.
I envy that.
It would be nice if someday if I could have a family like that too.
What?
Good night then.
Good night.
They have their memories with Sasakura.
"After a fight, it's Pekorinko Beam"
So now I'm gonna fill this up with lots of their memories.
Marumo.
Nothing.
What?
Don't you think it's kinda funny?
That I've come to have a
regular conversation with you like a friend.
But aren't we friends?
We're not friends. Are we?
Did it fall out of the photo album?
Here it is.
Here.
Mook, did I wake you up?
Sorry.
What's that?
Kaoru, no.
Mook, what is it?
Let me see.
Mook.
Oba-chan?
Daddy?
Why?
Kaoru?
What happened?
What are you doing?
Marumo.
Is Oba-chan our mommy?
Is Mommy alive?
Kaoru.