[After Daddy died,
Kaoru got separated from Tomoki.]
[But thanks to Daddy's friend, Marumo,
we got to live together again.]
-I'm Takagi Mamoru.
-Takagi Marumo.
[The dog's with us too.]
Daddy's not here anymore!
[Marumo's scary when he's mad,
but he's really very kind.]
[Kaoru and Tomoki are doing fine now.]
Goma shio.
Don't forget the canned mackerel too.
What~!
I see.
"You're the worst."
-That's what he said?
-Yes.
"You're the worst."
Out of the blue, the dog said.
[You're the worst.]
[What?]
You hear a voice you shouldn't be hearing.
That's auditory hallucination, a type of hallucination.
Auditory hallucination? But why all of a sudden?
Even healthy people can experience it temporarily.
For example, when they feel stressed or a sense of loss.
[What happened to you suddenly.]
[Why aren't you saying anything.]
In your case,
you may be hearing what you're feeling in your heart.
-Your subconscious feeling is taking the form of a voice.
Does that mean the one who said "You're the worst"
is me?
Yes.
It means that's a possibility.
I see. So that's what it was.
There's no need to rush.
Let's treat it slowly, over time.
Yes.
No, Tomoki.
You can't put on a sticker.
This isn't our house.
Alright.
Doesn't this dog look like Mook*?
His hair's shaggy. (*character in children's show)
Yeah, he does.
Let's name him Mook then.
You're Mook from today.
-Mook.
-Shaggy hair.
He feels good.
What do you think, huh?
It looks super delicious.
Thanks for letting me take the morning off.
Is your cold better now?
Cold?
Oh...yes. I went to the hospital
so I'm feeling much better.
-Don't spread it around.
-Really, please don't.
I'm going to a goukon* today.
(*matchmaking party)
Goukon again?
You really like that, don't you?
-Hello, this is Takagi.
-Hello, this is Sasakura.
Mamoru-kun,
do you have time right now?
I'm really sorry for imposing on you.
If they're too much trouble, I'll come get them right way.
No, not at all. I'm the one who brought them
home on the spur of the moment.
I'll be there to pick them up on Sunday.
I'll admonish them properly this time.
-Alright.
-Here's some change of clothes for the kids.
The top is Kaoru's and the bottom is Tomoki's.
Should be enough for 3 days.
There's no other way, right?
I mean, some way for those kids to be together.
I talked to my sister again, but
like we said before, it's hard for either one of us to take both of them.
Does that mean they have
no choice but to live separately?
What about their mother?
Were you able to contact Ayumi-san?
I called her cell phone,
but the number's no longer in use.
In any case, I wasn't going to notify her about
the funeral, even if I was able to contact her.
-But still, to those kids...
-She left home as if she was running away from them.
She abandoned those kids who were still babies.
Granted, she may have been suffering from parental neurosis, but
I can never forgive her.
Yes. You're right. Yes.
Sorry for taking so long.
Tashiro-san from Sales called.
-Okay, I'll call him back later.
-Yes, I agree.
We're very sorry.
-Yes, good bye.
-A complaint?
Yes, it was about the mechanical pencil.
He said his hands get dirty when replacing the lead
so do something about it.
What?  Do we have to apologize for something like that too?
Isn't he just a complainer?
Probably has nothing better to do.
Things can be triggered by complaints.
A minor complaint may lead to a hit merchandise.
Customers' opinions are a mountain of gold.
We should cherish them.
Takagi-kun, what happened to the report
-about that ball point pen?
-I'm working on it, but
I'm stuck on the improvement plan.
"The cap is not a ear cleaner."
We can't very well write a disclaimer like that.
There's no end to it once you start writing disclaimers like that.
Why don't we just
make the cap an actual ear cleaner.
-What?
-What are you saying, Takagi-kun?
This isn't the time to be joking.
You're right.
Sorry.
What's this?
What's a child's sock doing here?
It was in Takagi-san's area.
Takagi-san, do you have that kind of kinky taste?
No, that's not it.
-Disgusting.
-No, listen, th...this is...
this is...this is...you know, that.
Oh, iron cover.
-That's baseball.
-Oh, I mean golf...for golf...
You know, that cover is pricier than I expected.
Look, this is for the No. 6 iron.
Oh, that won't work...
Yes, yes, A..Akebono Office Supplies,
Customer Service.
Don't move, Mook.
Isn't it a good thing Marumo works for a stationery store?
There's a lot of notebooks too.
Marumo said he's here.
0210...
You're eating ice cream.
-Do you want some too?
-No. That's
-Marumo's ice cream.
-I can't eat it?
Marumo won't have any left for himself.
What should I do?
Will he get mad at me?
Tomoki, should we go buy one?
Huh?
But we're not supposed to leave the house.
Besides, what about the money?
That's right. Tomoki, take that out.
That?
Found it.
This one looks good.
We're here to buy Marumo's ice cream,
not Tomoki's, remember?
Oh, yeah.
Shall we help?
We'll push.
Oh, thank you.
Looks like I bought too much.
Thank you.
So, you're twins.
I'm the older sister and Tomoki's the younger brother.
You know, it's strange. We sneeze together too.
Is that right? You must be very close.
Oh, this is fine here.
Thank you so much.
Do you know your way home?
Bye bye.
-Bye bye.
Thank you.
Take care.  Be careful.
Oh no.  Which way was it?
This way?
Was it this way?
Onee-chan.
Don't cry. Let's try that way.
Hey, kids. What's wrong?
Wait a minute.
Pardon me? Marumo?
We don't have anyone by that name.
I'll take it.
It's alright.
Hello, this is Takagi.
Yes.
Oh, is that right?
I understand. I'll be there right away.
I'm sorry. I'm sor...
I'm sorry, but I'd like to leave early today.
What.  You don't feel well after all?
Um..no...
Yes, that's right.
Well, it's only 30 minutes till quitting time, so I guess it's alright.
You came in late and you're leaving early?
I'm really sorry.
Excuse me for leaving first.
Bye.
Oh, Takagi-san...th-that's...
This..this is...
this is...um...you know..that.
It's a necessity when washing your face.
That's it.
See you later.
Bye.
The phone call just now was from the police.
-What?
-What did he do?
He does have kinky taste after all.
-Gross
-So that's why he can't get married.
-Hello.
2nd Floor, was it?
Yes. Thanks.
-Takagi-san.
-Yes.
Don't move, okay?
Huh?
Makimura-san?
Here.
It was on the back of your suit.
Oh, thanks.
How did it get there?
You must like cute things, huh?
See you later then.
Those munchkins.
Didn't I tell you not to go out?
Do you know what I had to go through to get off early?
Plus, what's this sticker.  Don't go around
sticking these things wherever.
Thanks to you guys, I got laughed at by Makimura-san.
Now, now, calm down, Dad.
What?
I'm not their father.
-Seriously.
-Then who are you?
-Oh, a relative?
-Well, I'm not a relative either.
When I asked for their guardian's name,
they told me to call this toll free number.
Well, for the time being, I'm their guardian.
I'm taking care of them temporarily
because they ran away from their uncle's house.
Um...what I mean is...
it's the kind of running away from home
that you don't have to worry about.
Um...wait...no...
Please believe me.
I swear it's true.
There's been a few eyewitness
reports recently around here
that there's a suspicious person
who's been approaching children.
You misunderstand.
I didn't kidnap them or anything.
Then you must know a lot about these children, right?
How old are they?
Of course I know how old they are.
-Right?
-Please tell me.
Come on.
This is too much.
Please tell me.
5 years old?
Bu~.
What's their favorite food?
Hamburger?
-It's zaru soba*. -That's so old-folkish.
(*cold noodles with dipping sauce)
No, no, no, no.
I'm not...I'm not...
-Ah...finally released.
-Good thing he finally believed you, huh?
Whose fault was it
that I was suspected in the first place.
Thank god Sasakura's brother answered his phone.
What a major pain.
Why did you guys go out?
Tell me.
What's that? What is it? What is it?
Hey, let me see..
Give it here, give it to me...what is it?
What's this?
I ate up Marumo's ice cream so
we went to buy the same ice cream.
You mean the ice cream in the freezer?
Wait a minute.
I was really looking forward to eating that.
I'm sorry.
Not only that, this one's slightly different.
The one I like is premium vanilla, not vanilla.
We didn't have enough money.
Money?
Come to think of it,
where did you guys get the money?
Did you have some?
I had the 100 yen Daddy put in here.
Huh?
He told us to use it when we are in trouble.
Tomoki had 100 yen and Kaoru had 100 yen too.
But we still couldn't buy
the ice cream Marumo likes.
I'm sorry.
What? What are you doing?
Don't spend your precious money on something like this.
If you like ice cream, just say so.
Seriously, what am I gonna do with you guys.
Wanna go buy some ice cream on the way home?
What?  Can we?
-We're home
-We're home.
Yeah, that's more like it.
Dogs should say woof.  That's right.
-Hey, what about the ice cream?
-We'll have it for our snack tomorrow.
Okay, I'll put it away in the freezer then.
Oh, that's right.
-Should we write our names on the ice cream?
-Why?
So that you won't ever eat my ice cream again.
Oh.
We can read our name,
but can't write it.
Are you serious?
I guess I have no choice.
I'll write an example, so you guys practice, okay?
Here it goes.
This is KAORU.
And this is TOMOKI.
And I'm MAMORU.
What about SASAKURA?
Sasakura? This is SASAKURA.
SASAKURA.  There.
SASAKURA.  There, like this.
Okay, got it.
Oh, we decided to name that dog Mook.
Write Mook's name on his food too.
-Mook?
-Doesn't he look like Mook?
No you can't.
We're not going to keep him
so there's no need to give him a name.
He may be Mook now, but
once his owner is found,
he might have a different name, right?
Names aren't something
you give without much thought.
Your names, too, were given to you by your daddy,
who put a lot of thought into them,
along with lots of good wishes.
Anyway, he's not Mook. He's dog.
-No~ He's Mook.
-Dog.
-Mook.
-He's dog.
Can't you sleep?
It's me.  Me.
Mook? You can talk? That's amazing.
Of course I can.
Let's play a lot tomorrow.
So go to sleep.
Okay, I'll go to sleep. Good night.
-Food.
Did he talk?
Just my imagination?
Let's play, Marumo.
You don't have to work on Saturday, do you?
Wake up.
-Wake up.
-Wait, wait, wait.
It's a rule to sleep until past noon on days off.
Look, you guys go play somewhere.
Like a park.
But we don't know where anything is.
We're gonna get lost again.
Mook.
Marumo, let's play.
This way, this way.
Don't worry about me.
The two of you go play.
Onee-chan, let's play catch.
But Tomoki's really bad at it.
You couldn't even catch once
when you played with Daddy.
But I can do it now.
Here it goes.
I can't catch that.
What are they doing?
What did Sasakura teach them?
Hey Mook, wait.
Who, me?
Okay, okay.
I guess I have no choice.
You guys don't even have the fundamentals right. Listen, okay?
Never take your eyes off the ball.
Even if you get scared,
don't close your eyes.
Okay, here it goes, Tomoki.
I told you to watch the ball.
-Never mind.
-That's not for you to say.
Okay. Next, Kaoru, here it goes.
What was that?
You guys, we're not here to fetch balls, you know.
Here it goes, Marumo.
[Here it goes, Mamoru.]
What are you doing, Marumo?
Oh, sorry, sorry.
Alright, you'd better catch this time.
Yeah, bring it on.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Listen. Pets aren't allowed at our house.
If the landlord finds out, he's gonna get mad,
so go up quietly, understand?
-Okay!
-Keep it down.
Hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry.
We're home.
-We're home.
Alright, let's fix something to eat.
-What do you want?
-Hamburger.
What~?
You guys like hamburger?
Takagi-san.
Yes. Yes.
You guys hide..hide.
Where?
Huh? Huh? Huh? Where?
Take your shoes with you.
Coming.
Just a minute.
-Did you want something?
-A little while ago
-I thought I saw a dog.
-A dog?
It must have been your imagination.
You don't have a dog, do you?
I don't have anything, don't have anything.
There he is.
Oh, this, um...
I can explain .
Is it a stuffed animal?
Huh?
Ah, y-y-yes.
It's a stuffed animal.
Mook, hurry, come here.
It's made really well.
It looks so real.
Wait, what...is it moving?
-It was over there just now.
-Wait...
It's just a stuffed animal, you know?
Isn't it just your imagination?
I don't hardly think so. It was there...huh?
Why?
Something's definitely strange.
Excuse me.
Wait, wait a minute.
How can you...without permission.
Takagi-san, what in the world are you doing in here?
No, it's not what you think.
That's not what you think either.
It's best you don't go there.
It's dangerous...
Two oyako-don* up.
(*chicken and egg bowl)
Here you go.
Wow, I'm gonna eat Tako*-san for the first time. (*octopus)
Is that right?
Tako-san's delicious.
Isn't it, though? How did you know? I made that.
-It's good.
Oh, next time
I'll make you Kani*-san. (*crab)
Come on over again, okay?
Those kids are so young but
had to go through a lot, haven't they?
They're such cute good kids.
Say,
why don't you just keep them?
Hey, don't be so presumptuous.
But their relatives are so cruel.
To take the kids separately, when that time came.
You have to consider their circumstances too.
It's not easy to raise children.
You haven't even raised one, so don't talk like you know it all.
I'm saying this because I haven't, and don't ever intend to, raise one.
They could be like your grandkids, Dad,
so it's good for you too.
Plus, I have no desire to marry anymore.
What does that mean?
Are you saying that you're gonna remain single forever?
That has nothing to do with you anyway, Dad.
Excuse me, excuse me.
Excuse me.
The children will be picked up tomorrow.
In the first place, why did you come home suddenly?
What I do is my business.
Hey, hey,
calm down, both of you.
Let's chill out, shall we?
Ah~ I'm tired today.
-You want ice cream?
-Yeah.
It's good.
-Let me have some.
-No, you still have yours, Tomoki.
Oh, I do.
This notebook's pretty handy, isn't it?
Is this Tomoki's? Let's see.
What a terrible handwriting.
-Hey, this is CHICHIKURA.
-Huh?
You wrote the letters for SASA backwards.
(SA=さ; CHI=ち)
This spells CHICHIKURA.
No way. Chichikura?
He said Chichikura.
Don't be laughing at your own mistake.
Is this Kaoru's? Let's see.
Kaoru, you just practiced your first name?
-Because I won't be Sasakura soon.
-Huh?
When Uncle comes to get us tomorrow,
Kaoru's going to Auntie's house, right?
Then Kaoru's
going to be Auntie Endou's child, right?
Is that true, Marumo?
Is Onee-chan's name going to change?
We're not going to be together anymore?
-No, that can't be.
-There's nothing we can do.
Daddy's not here anymore.
What's wrong?
It's too good to eat at once,
so I'm saving the rest for tomorrow.
Me too. I'll eat the rest tomorrow.
So tiny.
They used to be like this.
[It's a good thing for the kids.]
[They've been together since they were born.]
[Even during sad times, they'll have each other.]
Thanks a lot for letting us impose on you.
We'll get going then.
Take care.
Marumo.
Marumo!
Marumo! Marumo!
Oh right, the dog's still here. What should I do?
Hey, shall we go look for someone who'll take you?
Are you really okay with this?
Huh?
[In your case, you may be hearing
what you're feeling in your heart.]
[Your subconscious feeling is taking the form of a voice.]
But I would've liked
to have seen them learn to catch the ball.
Me too.
Of course I would've liked that too.
Sasakura would've wanted to too.
[Daddy's gone, and I don't want to be separated from Tomoki too.]
[Don't be mean to Onee-chan.]
-[Takagi Marumo?]
-[It's Mamoru. Mamoru. What the heck's a Marumo?]
[Takagi Marumo.]
-[We're done with the bath.]
-[Hey, wait.
You're wet, you're wet.
Hold on, I said you're wet.]
[I'm scared.]
[It's not scary, it's not..
it's not scary]
[Are you alright?]
[It's okay to cry if you want to cry. Right?]
-[Right?]
-[Yes.]
[Let's play, Marumo.]
[What was that?]
[You guys, we're not here to fetch balls, you know.]
[Because I won't be Sasakura soon.]
[When Uncle comes to get us tomorrow,
Kaoru's going to Auntie's house, right?]
[Onee-chan, we can't be together anymore?]
[Marumo! Marumo!]
"Marumo, thanks for staying with us.
Chiyonara*" (*meant to be Sayonara)
What the heck is "Chiyonara."
(she wrote "chi" instead of "sa")
Those guys.
Marumo?
Marumo.
Marumo!
What's wrong, Mamoru-kun?
Did we forget something?
No, um...
Um...
When these two are together,
they're really cheerful and happy.
It's like, they're happy because they're together.
Are you still trying to tell me that they should stay together?
No, well, not exactly, but...
I was thinking if they could be together for a little bit longer.
I already said that was out of the question.
At least until they agree to it,
I'd like for them to be able to stay together.
You know there's no way we can do that.
Certainly, it takes a lot out of you and it could be tiring.
But since I met them,
even though it was only for a few days,
it seems I laughed and cried a lot
for the first time in a long time.
I've never felt like this before.
I wanted to spend more time with these kids.
I'm thinking about living with these kids.
What are you saying all of a sudden?
Do you realize what you're saying?
-Yes.
-They're not your children, you know.
They're not even related to you, you know.
Yes, I know.
Then I suggest you reconsider.
Even us relatives are struggling to deal with it,
so how can an unrelated person take on the burden.
It's not about the burden or whatever.
I don't know why.
It may not work out.
But I want to be watching over those two.
Like Sasakura was doing.
From now on, I want to do it in his place.
I want to stay with Marumo.
Me too.
Mook can stay with us too, can't he?
I guess I don't have a choice.
But we'll have to return him as soon as his owner's found.
We did it.
Can I keep on being Sasakura Kaoru?
Of course.
You guys will always be Sasakura's kids.
Sasakura Kaoru and Sasakura Tomoki
are precious names given to you by your dad, aren't they?
Really? Can we really have matching names with Daddy?
Yup.
From today on, this is your home.
You don't have to hold anything in.
So if you want to cry, you can cry.
But, but.
It's good.
It's goma shio.
Eat the fried egg too.
After all, I made it for you guys.
Oh, that's right.
This is important, so I'm writing it down.
"Kids will be kids."?
Yeah. This is your home.
Even though your dad and mom aren't here,
you don't have to feel uneasy.
Don't hold it in if you want to cry.
Don't hold it in even more if you want to laugh.
Kids will be kids. Okay?
Dogs will be dogs. Right?
Okite*.
(Rules/Code)
Okite?
Yeah.
Think of it as our promise so that we can live in harmony from now on.
-Can you abide by it?
-Okay.
-We'll abide by it.
-Okay, pinky promise then.
Oh, but Mook can't pinky promise.
I guess we have no choice.
We'll have to do it this way.
Okay, come here.
Come on, Mook.
Let's go!
Oh shoot. I have to go to work.
Before that, I'll stop by the municipal office
to change your address and report that you're living with me.
Marumo, are we going to attend an elementary school around here?
-Elementary school?
-We're going to be in first grade this year.
What? Is that right? First grade?
How do you enroll in elementary school?
Don't know.
Well, anyway, I'll ask about that at the municipal office.
-I'm going.
-See you later.
Hey, hey.
What?
Give me a break, will ya?
Don't forget to register me too.
What! Register!