Marumo, is Oba-chan our mommy?
Is Mommy alive?
Kaoru.
Marumo, is Oba-chan our mommy?
Wh-What are you saying.
How can that be?
Where did that come from?
Who's this? Mommy, right?
Yeah.
That's you guys' mommy.
-It's Oba-chan, right?
-No it isn't.
-But she looks just like her.
-I said it's not. Let me see that.
This does look like her, but
her hairstyle's different and she has a different aura.
They're not the same person.
Listen, Kaoru. It's said that
there are three people who look exactly alike in this world.
So it's not strange that there are people who look alike, right?
People tell me I have look-alikes too.
Like that Cat Girl*.
(*from GeGeGe no Kitaro)
And Catbus*.
(*from My Neighbor Totoro)
And an alien.
Anyway,
it's late so go to sleep for today.
Okay?
Marumo, can I have that picture?
-Huh?
-Because I don't have any pictures of Mommy.
Oh, okay.
-Don't lose it.
-Okay, thanks. Good night.
Good night.
-Hey, Kaori, Tomoki, you're gonna be late
-That's right.
Marumo, can you come to the information meeting for sports day?
Teacher said it's okay if you can't make it.
He said he'll pass out the printout later.
Today at 3, right?  That should be fine.
-I'll just take some time off and go.
-Okay.
I'm going first then.
-See you later.
Okay, I'm going.
Okay, I'm going, Mook.
-Bye bye.
Tomoki, look at this.
What is it?
I got it from Marumo. It's a picture of Mommy.
What? Is that really Mommy?
Yeah.
She looks like Oba-chan, doesn't she?
Yeah, I think so too, but
she isn't, is she?
Probably not.
You know Mommy died.
And Oba-chan's alive.
I guess.
Maybe she's a spirit.
What, a ghost?
Is this Sunday the sports day?
Yeah, that's right. I'm so looking forward to it.
The thing to remember on sports day is to secure a spot.
-Secure a spot?
-When you get there in the morning
make sure you find a spot where you can get an unobstructed view of the children.
-Wow, spoken like a true veteran.
-Thanks, I'll keep that in mind.
I'll get it.
Hello, Customer Service. This is Mashima.
Ah, how are you. Yes.
So the time's been changed from 1:00 to 3:00.
Is this Oyaji-san?
Is Aya-chan there?
She went out saying something about going to a movie with a friend.
Oh, is that right.
What? Did you need something?
Actually, there's an information meeting for the sports day today at 3.
I was planning to go, but
the time for a meeting I have to attend suddenly changed.
Ah, information meeting, huh?
The students have been practicing the song they're dancing to on sports day.
In order for them to be able to practice at home,
I'd like all of you to learn the dance as well.
Alright.
Let me show you
how it's done first.
First, pose like a monkey.
Stop. Wait a minute.
Kaoru, okay.
Tomoki, there's something wrong with yours.
You're bow legged, and
you're kinda flopping around.
Watch me, okay? Like this.
-"Ai ai" cutely.
Okay, try it.
It's still not right, but we'll let it go for now.
It'll work out if you practice.
I'm home.
-Hi.
-Oh, hi.
Oyaji-san, sorry for troubling you today and thanks.
I don't mind once in a while.
-Oh, here's the printout.
-Yes yes.
Let's see...
We can go secure a spot from 6 am.
No staking out on the school ground from the day before.
Alright, got it.
Marumo, Oyaji-san learned the dance for us.
Seriously? That's great.
You know that "Ai ai," right?
The high point of the song is a bit difficult.
Watch. Like this.
You try it.
Me?
Yeah.
Dad, customers are starting to come.
-Wh-what are you doing?
-Oh, I'll be right there.
-We'll continue tomorrow, okay?
-Yes.
-Alright, tomorrow then.
-Thank you.
-Thanks.
-We'll keep on practicing.
Yeah, practice hard.
This is pretty hard.♪♪「アイアイ」
難しいな　これ　おい。
-No, no, you have to concentrate more.
-Huh?
Your hand movement's dead too.
-This is fun.
-It's good.
The person who invented this is a genius, huh?
-This is the last of it.
-Oh, there's a red one in there.
Whoever eats this is the lucky one.
-I wanna eat it.
-I want to eat it.
-Me me me me.
-Me me.
Okay, okay, okay. Let's decide who gets the last bite by rock paper scissors.
Here we go. Ready.
First is rock.
Rock paper scissors.
-Huh?
-You.
-It's rock.
No, that's paper. Yeah, paper.
But it's rock.
I win. I get to eat.
Mommy, thanks for the clothes.
Can I wear it to school tomorrow?
-Of course you can.
-Yay!
What shall we do about dinner?
-Say, Marumo.
-Hm?
You met Mommy before, didn't you?
Yeah, I did.
-Where's Mommy sleeping?
-Huh?
Same place as Daddy?
Uh...No.
It's someplace else...probably.
Why not?
Don't families go into the same grave?
Where's Mommy's grave?
-Um..That's...um.
-I want to visit Mommy's grave too.
I've never been there, you know.
Yeah.
Daddy didn't take us.
Uh...Uh... Some other time, okay?
It might be a little far.
Yeah, that's probably it.
It's far.
Yeah, some other time.
Hello, this is Takagi.
This is Aoki.
I'm sorry for calling so late at night.
Ayumi-san, did something happen?
Can you set aside some time for me tomorrow?
I'd like to talk to you about the children.
-What's going on?
-Stuff for the cheering section.
We all brought something in.
The kids are putting in a lot of effort, so the parents have to too.
Is that right?
But what's this?
I brought that.
I wore that and danced at an athletic festival.
We all lined up behind each other
-like this.
-Wait.
I think I've done that too.
This might work.
Hey, hey, hey.
Line up behind me. Line up.
Hurry, hurry.
-Kana-san, you too. Hurry.
-Me too?
All aboard. Go.
-What do you think?
-Pretty good, huh?
This is fun.
Okay, then gather at 8 on Sunday morning.
-Takagi-kun.
-Yes.
Do you have time after lunch?
Yes.
I told you a little bit about it last time too, but
it seems the Product Development people want
to have you transferred back there after all.
-Huh?
-Of course, I would
like for you to stay in this department forever.
It would be better for the twins as well.
However, product development is what you've always wanted to do.
This might be the beginning of a great opportunity for you.
So think about it.
It's your life after all.
Thank you for your concern.
It's the Boss.
The Goma Shio Boss.
Boss?
Boss, g'day.
Yeah, take it easy.
Awesome.
I wonder if he came out of goma shio.
I should've asked for an autograph.
Ah~ I blew my chance.
-Hello.
-Ah, yes.
Excuse me. We saw the poster outside.
The poster?
-About the lost dog.
-Ah.
He may be our dog.
Oh, is that right?
Excuse me for calling you out so suddenly.
First of all, I wanted to return this.
Kaoru's clothes.
I had taken the dirty clothes home with me last time.
Thanks for taking the trouble to return them.
I'm really sorry about the last time.
Me too.
I was a bit harsh.
I happened to see Kaoru fall down on my way home from work.
I couldn't leave her there and found myself talking to her.
I forgot about the time and took her all over.
I hear they're dancing to "Ai Ai" on sports day.
She looked so happy talking about it.
I bet Kaoru and Tomoki will be really cute.
Yes. I'm looking forward to it.
I'm sorry.
Um...You said you had something to talk about?
Ah, yes.
What kind of work are you doing now, Ayumi-san?
I'm working in a medical office right now.
I got my certificate immediately after I divorced Junichirou.
-I see.
-What about you, Takagi-san?
Do you have plans to get married?
I don't think marriage is in my future anymore.
Perhaps, is it because of the children?
-No, that's not it.
-But
you have a job too, and I'm afraid they're a burden to you.
No, I don't feel that way at all.
Everything's fine.
Anyway, please don't worry about the children.
I will take good care of them.
-Mook's owner?
-Yeah.
That's the point of contact.
Can you give them a call?
I wonder if it's really Mook.
I understand the dog disappeared about 3 months ago,
and they reported it to the police but was never found,
so they've been looking ever since.
We have to say good-bye to Mook?
I don't want to do that.
We don't know yet.
We don't know, but
if they're really Mook's owner,
-we have to return him.
-Why?
No. Never.
Isn't Mook family?
Isn't he part of our family?
Yeah, he's our family now.
Then let's just stay together like this.
Me too. I'd like to do that too.
But no matter how much we like Mook,
Mook isn't ours.
Mook already had a family before us.
Those people have been waiting to live with Mook for a long time.
We can't take him away from them.
We have to give Mook back to them.
I don't want to say bye bye to Mook.
Mook is going to stay with us.
No.
I don't want to part with him!
How about a drink?
Yes.
Here.
I had a hard time calming them down.
They were crying and screaming.
I'm sure they're
heartbroken about Mook.
I'm heartbroken too.
About Mook.
And about Ayumi-san too.
I tried to convince the kids
because they were saying they didn't part with Mook.
Mook isn't ours.
He already had a family so we should return him.
As I was talking, I started thinking,
"Hey, wait. Am I talking about myself?"
And so you thought
you should return the kids to Ayumi-san.
Yes.
I don't know what to do.
Of course, when I think about Sasakura,
there's no way I can hand over the kids to Ayumi-san.
He died, trying to raise the kids all by himself.
I can never do anything that would betray him.
Besides, I want to stay with those kids forever too.
Do you think Mook won't come back anymore?
Marumo's terrible, isn't he?
Excuse me, are you Takagi-san?
Yes.
I'm Izumi, the one who took your call.
-Thank you for coming.
-No, thank you.
Mook.
What do you think?
They look alike but...
No, it's not our Ranko.
I'm sorry I couldn't be of help.
No, no, that's alright. Thank you.
Thank you for making time to come here.
If it's alright with you,
please give this to Mook-chan.
It's our Ranko's favorite.
Thank you.
Seems I caused you more trouble than anything.
I hope you find Ranko-chan.
Yes. Thank you very much.
I felt bad for them.
But I was relieved.
When I found out you weren't their dog.
It's funny, huh?
You're not even mine to begin with.
But really,
when I found out that I didn't have to part with you,
I felt bad for them, but I was happy.
Don't cry.
I ain't crying.
I'll stay with you again.
Listen, I'm the one who's letting you stay.
I love you, Marumo.
Aw, be quiet.
I'm so happy.
So we can live with Mook again, right?
-Yeah, we're together again.
-Shaggy hair.
Oh, Marumo. Can we take Mook with us on sports day?
The printout said no pets allowed.
-Really~.
-We have no choice.
Mook has to stay home.
Okay, then. In preparation for the real deal tomorrow, let's do our final practice.
Get set.
Let's go. 3, 4.
Mook, you're staying home, you know.
Besides, that Ai Ai comes much later, huh?
Okay. Nice.
-Nice.
Get set. Ready.
Hey. Over there, over there.
Dad, hurry up.
You made too much bento.
What are you talking about.
This is just right.
-Hey, we're here. What's up?
-Kaoru's about to run.
Alright. Okay. We made it on time, didn't we?
Oyaji-san, hold these.
And Aya-chan, hold these.
-"Kaoru" "Tomoki"
-What are these?
To cheer them on, of course.
Here we go.
Okay. Go, go, let's go.
Let's go Kaoru.
Let's go, let's go.
-Let's go Kaoru!
What are you waiting for?
Come on, Aya-chan, you do it too.
You have to do it too.
Look, do it like this.
Let it fly, Kaoru.
-Marumo's awesome.
-He's cool.
Get set. Ready.
Go, go!
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
Okay.
Kaoru got 2nd place. Alright, good job.
Next is Tomoki. Tomoki, Tomoki.
Go, go, let's go.
Let's go Tomoki.
Hooray, hooray, Tomoki.
Go for it, Tomoki. Go for it.
-Okay, Tomoki.
Okay, Tomoki. Tomoki...
Takagi-san.
Then get set. Ready.
It's hot. Man, it's hot.
Hey, Mamoru, is it okay?
It's okay, it's okay.
The first graders' dance is coming up soon.
I can't wait to see them.
I hope Kaoru and Tomoki do well.
I think Kaoru would be fine, but I'm worried about Tomoki.
Since that Ai Ai part is difficult.
Ah. I hope they're alright.
[I couldn't get their faces
out of my mind even after I left them.]
[There wasn't a day in the past 4 years that I didn't regret it.]
[I hear they're dancing to "Ai Ai" on sports day.]
[I bet Kaoru and Tomoki will be really cute.]
Takagi-san.
Ayumi-san.
I'm sorry.
I just happened to be passing by.
That sounds pretty lame, doesn't it?
We made too much bento.
Oyaji-san and Aya-chan kinda went overboard
and made too much.
So why don't you stay and eat with us?
We don't want leftovers either.
Besides, the more people they have cheering for them,
the happier they'll be.
Next we present a dance by the first graders.
-Taiga.
-Go, Yuzuki.
-Minami.
-Daichi.
What's he doing?
It's gonna start.
Here you are.
Oh, hello.
What's going on with Kaoru-chan?
Maybe she's nervous.
Way to go, Kaoru.
Nice.
Thank you so much for inviting me today.
I had a really good time.
These guys looked like they were having fun too.
Remember when Kaoru messed up on her dance
you immediately ran up and showed the dance for her?
I thought then that "Ah, he really cares a lot
about the children."
It sounds funny to say this now, but...
Mamoru-san, please take care of the children.
Yes, of course.
Hey, you guys. We're almost home.
Wake up, wake up, wake up.
Come on, come on.
Marumo, I have to pee.
What? Wait.
We're gonna run. We're running.
-I can't wait.
-No, hold it in. Hold it in.
Are you awake?
Yes. I guess I fell asleep.
It was fun today, wasn't it?
Okay, we're here.
Then I'm going now, okay?
Oba-chan.
Yes?
What's the matter?
Are you our mommy?
Are you Kaoru and Tomoki's mommy?
No, I'm not.
Oh, so you aren't.
I guess I was wrong.
Sorry.
Kaoru-chan, eat a lot, laugh a lot and grow, okay?
I'll always be rooting for Kaoru-chan and Tomoki-kun.
I'm always on your side.
Thanks for today.
Thanks for seeing them home.
Kaoru, you say good bye to Oba-chan too.
Oba-chan, thanks for coming today.
Good bye.
Take care. Good bye.
Man~ That was tiring, huh?
Yeah, but it was fun.
Yeah.
Marumo, your cheers were awesome.
Thanks.
-Thanks.
-Oh, really?
You get energy when someone cheers for you.
You do, don't you?
Oh, that's right.
The okite for today.
There.
"Let's all..."?
Cheer for each other.
Today you got the strength to push yourself harder because people were cheering for you, right?
Cheering makes people happy, whether you're being cheered, or doing the cheering.
That's so cool. Every day is a sports day.
Yeah, well, something like that.
What is it?
-What?
-Did you want to dance too, Mook?
-Maybe so, huh?
-Did you want to see us dance?
What's this?
Sasakura?
[To Ayumi]
[How have you been since?]
[You must be surprised to get a letter unexpectedly.]
[Sorry. But bear with me for just a little while.]
[After Ayumi left home,
I spent my days resenting you for a long time.]
[Things weren't going my way raising the two children,
and I couldn't forgive you for abandoning your responsibility as a mother.]
[But you were doing this all by yourself, weren't you?]
[Yes, all by yourself for 3 long years.]
[Now that I understand how you felt,
I couldn't stop myself from writing this letter.]
[Thank you for 3 years.]
[1 year has passed. Tomoki has a huge appetite
and Kaoru's grown to be a strong child who doesn't cry.
[This watermelon's good, isn't it?]
[If it's at all possible,
I want you to watch Kaoru and Tomoki grow too.
[I still consider Ayumi my family.]
[Can we all live together again?]
[I want you to stay by Kaoru and Tomoki.]
[That's what I wish for the most.]
[If you're physically well and when you're mentally ready,
please give me your answer.]
[I'll be waiting.]
[From Sasakura Junichirou]
Sasakura.
Takagi-san?
What are you doing here?
This is...
Sasakura had already forgiven Ayumi-san long time ago.
Even without me worrying about him,
Ayumi-san never stopped being family to him.
It was like that all this time.
I knew Sasakura was having a tough time,
and I felt so bad for him.
That's why I swore
I'd never hand over the kids to Ayumi-san, but...
But...but I was wrong.
Takagi-san.
Aya-chan, I'm going to return them.
What?
I'm going to return Kaoru and Tomoki to Ayumi-san.
Wait a minute.
Are you going to be okay with that?
But you're the one who kept them together.
You finally became a family.
I have to do it.
Sasakura wrote this with his kids in mind.
For his kids' sake.
For these kids' sake.
Won't you miss them?
Of course I will.
Because they're family.
Kaoru and Tomoki are my family.
I'll miss them so much, I don't know what I'm going to do.
Then, stay together.
But I have to return them.
I have to.