What's a family?
Does it mean you're related by blood?
Does it mean you live together?
No matter how well you know the person,
you don't really know what he's thinking and
and what he's feeling in his heart.
Even if you're real a family.
What's a family?
What is it that bonds people together?
I never even thought about it before.
Takagi  Takagi  Takagi  Takagi.
Then who's this.
-I'm gonna take a guess.
-Okay, who is it.
Bryant.
Saeki  Saeki  Saeki.
Wrong, wrong, wrong.  A foreigner.
-Ogilvie.
-Right answer.
Here you go, yaki onigiri*.
(*grilled rice ball)
Okay, here it is, the last one.
Who's this, who's this?
Hey, Mamoru, where's Sasakura?
Sasakura?
Don't ask me, I'm busy now.
Hey, Sasakura.
Sorry, I'm late.
Hey guys, our ace is here.
I propose another toast.
To our reunion. Cheers.
Cheers.
Hey. You haven't changed at all.
Hey, you're looking good.
Excuse me, excuse me.
Mamoru, it's been while
Don't come squeezing into this tight spot.
-Work keeping you busy?
-Yeah, obviously.
-Super busy.
-Product development for an office supply company
-keeps you that busy?
-Well, I'm not in product development anymore.
I kinda left there last month.
Why? Did something happen?
Enough about that.
Things happen.
Aren't you handling complaints now?
Will you stop calling it that.
Take a good look. Read it.
"Akebono Office Supplies.
Customer Service"?
We get calls from all kinds of people.
Things must be tough everywhere.
Here, let me make you feel better.
Huh?
Cut it out.
I'm not interested in other people's kids.
-They've sure grown.
-Let me see.
Even though they're twins, they're so different.
Kinda like Zashiki-warashi vs Jizou*?
(*a girl spirit vs Buddhist deity)
They're fraternal twins so their personalities are totally different too.
The older one's sassy, the younger one's a baby.
I'd go through anything for these guys.
I can't even imagine what that's like.
I guess it would be impossible for you.
Hey, if you're having a hard time, look for a new wife.
I have no intention of marrying again.
I'm managing somehow.
But aren't you looking a little haggard?
-It must be tough taking care of twins.
-Well, yeah.
But it's a good thing for the kids.
They've been together since they were born.
Even during sad times, they'll have each other.
Is that how it is?
Yeah.
I'm really glad they're twins.
Thanks to being twins, they've always been happy.
Oh, do you remember?
-Kimura
Hey, Kimura.
Kimura, are you alright?
Catcher Takagi-kun, coming in for Kimura-kun.
Catcher Takagi-kun
Throw me your best pitch.
Let's crank it up.
We had fun back then, didn't we?
Thanks to Mamoru, I was able to pitch as I liked.
I didn't want to pitch around them and lose.
Hey you two partners in crime shouldn't be having a heart to heart. That should've been an intentional walk, right?
That was the first official game for me, you know.
There was no way I was going be uncool and give up a walk from the start.
Right?
This is embarrassing. How can you write something like this.
What does it say?
"Battery for life"
-Why'd you bring it all of sudden?
-Never mind that. I'll give it to you.
-I don't want it.
-Just keep it.
What an embarrassing guy.
-Are you nervous?
-No, I'm not.
The other party will be saying whatever she wants,
but don't give in.
Okay.
We are very sorry for what happened.
The fact that you're apologizing must mean you're taking responsibility.
Well, before we get into that, if you would allow us to
confirm the circumstances once more...
Never mind the circumstances or whatever.
Do you realize I'm hurt?
Because of that, I've had to go to the hospital and
I've been irritated all morning because of the pain.
It's causing me extreme mental distress.
Yes, however...
You're absolutely right.
How is your injury?
-Look.
-Oh my.
It must have hurt quite a bit?
The pain wasn't that bad, but
it bled, you see, so I was alarmed.
I totally understand.
By the way, how did it happen?
This.
Thank you for buying the staple of our company,
the ball point pen with vivid black ink.
Like this.
You took off the cap.
You're saying you used it as an ear cleaner.
And then, I got a cut, like this.
-I see.
-However, ma'am,
the cap of the pen isn't made to be an ear cleaner.
But it doesn't say that, does it?
That's not written anywhere, is it?
If it can't be used that way,
how are we supposed to know if it doesn't say it can't be used that way.
Yes, however...
It's not much, but if you don't mind, please accept them.
Wait, what?
It's not that I wanted something, you know.
Thank you very much for your valuable suggestion.
We're back.
-Takagi-kun.
-Yes.
How was your first customer visit?
I was betrayed by Mashima.
Yes, he totally betrayed me.
-What do you mean "betray?"
-You switched sides without warning.
-You made it look like the bad guy.
-That wasn't betrayal.
It's a technique.
The important thing is to
get on the other party's good side like that.
Will you tell me beforehand if you're gonna do something like that?
-Didn't I tell you?
-Samejima-san, this guy sucks.
Don't bother telling Samejima-san.
He's the one
who taught me that technique.
Can you teach me too?
-Takagi-san.
-Yes.
Please turn in your report.
Please be as specific as possible, like what measures you took
and if any apology gifts were given.
It's almost time for PR to be here, so please hurry.
Excuse me, but who's coming from PR?
Recently Makimura-san's been coming a lot.
Oh, Makimura-san.
Hold on please.
Takagi-san, a customer wants to speak with you.
Me?
You'd better be careful with these calls that specifically ask for you.
What?  Really?
Hello, this is Takagi.
You know, your company's eraser
doesn't erase at all.
Did you intend for it to erase?
We're very sorry.
If you're sorry, stick out your butt.
I'm gonna whoop your ass with a bat, you bastard.
You must be Sasakura.
You got it.
Hey, quit messing around.
-Looks like you're working diligently.
-Of course I am.
I sure had fun at the get-together.
Did you call just to say that?
We couldn't really talk the other night because of all the noise, right?
-What do we have to talk about anyway.
-Don't be like that.
Takagi-san.
Makimura-san's here.
-Mamoru...
-Hello.
Actually, I...
Sasakura, I can't talk now, I'm busy.
Okay, later.
Are you done with all the reports?
This is the last one so
I'll bring it to you by the end of the day.
Directly.
Oh, then just give me the ones that are done.
Oh, alright.
Looks like you're getting acclimated to Customer Service.
Yes, more or less.
Tami-san, the reports.
-Thank you.
Thank you.
Bye.
How come he hasn't changed the light bulb yet.
-Thanks.
-Oh, thank
you. Come again.
-Pops.
-Oh, you're back.
-About the light bulb in the stairway.
-Oh yeah, the light bulb.
-Here.
-Hey, watch it.
-Use that.
-Am I changing it?
You're the only one who uses it.
Come on.
What a pain.
He's nothing more than a maintenance fee thief.
I'm home.
"I'm home"?
Aya, why are you here suddenly?
Oh, you said your back was hurting so I came to check up on you.
My back?
I hurt my back last year.
What's the difference if I'm worried about it now.
Aren't you happy to see me?
Not particularly.
Pops, here's the old one.
Hey.
Where are you going to sleep?
What about the room upstairs?
-Upstairs?
-Yeah.
I rented it out.
Oh.
It's tight, but I'll guess I'll have to make do down here.
Stop being so selfish, will you?
In the first place, I don't have any futon ready
-and it's too cold on the couch.
-That's alright.
It's gotten a lot warmer now.
Still...
I told you it's alright. You never minded being cold, Dad.
So it's me who gets the couch.
That's a given. What are you talking about?
Alright.
I'll be going back up then.
-Make yourself at home.
-Thanks.
Hey, I'm hungry.
-What do you want?
-Who is that?
Oh yeah, I want Kuji Rice.
-Hello?
-Hello, it's Kubo.
Hey, don't be calling me at work.
The other day too, that idiot Sasakura...
-Mamoru.
-Huh?
Sasakura...
What about Sasakura?
He passed away this morning.
Hey, Sasakura did what?
Hey, what about Sasakura?
I said he died.
Mamoru.
That guy.
He wasn't doing well.
Terminal cancer.
Did you know about it?
Well, yeah.
If you knew, why didn't you tell me?
Sorry, but Sasakura asked me not to tell you.
Sorry don't cut it.
If you knew about his illness, what would you have done?
I would've, well, at least in the end
been nicer to him, or been like better friends.
Don't you think that's exactly what Sasakura didn't want?
Isn't it sadder if someone suddenly starts acting nice and friendlier because it's the end?
You'd think "Ah, so this is finally the end."
It would be meaningless to see you if it wasn't the usual you.
What's that supposed to mean.
What happened to you suddenly.
Why aren't you saying anything.
You should've told me if you were going to die.
You should've told me.
Daddy?
It's hard to breath with that handkerchief on your face, isn't it?
No, this is...
Tomoki, come here.
Tomoki, I found a piece of paper.
Here, hold this...
What? Why are you saying that now, Onii-chan?
Didn't you promise Junichiro that you'd take both of them?
Well yeah, I did say that at the hospital, but...
Why did you lie?
Under that circumstance, I had no choice but to say that to put his mind at ease.
Then what are we going to do?
We can manage to take one.
What's that.
You mean split them up?
We have to send money back home too so we're overloaded.
We're all in the same boat, aren't we?
We
have our hands full with just Reina too.
Then shall we send one to an institution?
What are you saying?
That makes me look totally...
Aren't I going to be with Tomoki?
That's right.
Tomoki's going to sleep at Uncle's house from now on.
Kaoru's going to Auntie's house.
But we promised Daddy that we'll stay together.
You know, your daddy told me
that it's better if you slept over separately
so that Kaoru and Tomoki would get stronger.
But, but, Daddy didn't tell us anything like that.
Is that right?
But it's your daddy's wish that you two grow up to be strong.
Let's work at it, huh?
But we promised.
It's a good thing for the kids.
They've been together since they were born.
Even during sad times, they'll always have each other.
Go on, say bye bye to Onee-chan.
No, I won't.
Look Tomoki, Onee-chan's doing bye bye.
No, I'm not doing bye bye.
Tomoki, we have to bye bye.
No, I don't want to.
Tomoki, do what you're told.
I'm not doing it no matter what.
Okay, we're leaving.
Let's go.
-Tomoki.
Come on.
-Onee-chan.
-Tomoki.
I'm going with Onee-chan.
Kaoru, shall we go?
Onee-chan.
Onee-chan, Onee-chan
Onee-chan, Onee-chan.
Kaoru's going to be staying here from now on, right?
Of course.
Do I have to share my room from now on too?
You don't mind it being a little tight, do you?
I do mind. I have entrance exams this year, you know?
Don't force entrance exams into the subject.
Then don't you care if I don't study?
We don't have any other room.
We can't make Kaoru sleep here, can we?
Forget it.
Auntie's going back to the shop.
Can you eat by yourself?
Yes, I'll be alright.
Itadakimasu.
Auntie.
Thank you.
Thank you. That comes to 368 yen.
Yes, what can I get you.
What are you doing?
Did you spill?
I'm sorry.
Hey, Tomoki spilled the miso soup.
Take care of him properly, will you.
I can't get away now, so wait a while.
Stay away from that.
I'm sorry.
Hello. Thank you for calling
Akebono Office Supplies Customer Service.
-This is Mashima.
Yes, yes.
We're very sorry.
Yes.
Oh, is that right?
Specifically, the merchandise is...
I'm gonna whoop your ass with a bat, you bastard.
You must be Sasakura.
Looks like you're working diligently.
Thank you for calling Akebono Office Supplies Customer Service.
This is Takagi.
-Hello, you know,
the ink in this is all hard and won't come out.
What's the deal?
Are you listening?
I'm very sorry for the inconvenience.
Yes. And this product you're talking about is....
I'm leaving your lunch here.
You'll be alright?
-Try not to spill anymore, okay?
-Okay.
Call me right away if something happens.
You can't do anything by yourself.
-Okay.
-Excuse me.
Yes, coming.
-Hello.
-Mamoru, you at work now?
Yeah, what's up?
Remember Sasakura's kids?
The twin boy.
Oh, yeah, that one that looks spaced out.
Yeah.  I got a call telling me that he disappeared.
Seems he was there this morning, but would you happen to know where he went?
-No, I have no idea.
-Yeah, I guess you wouldn't.
That's okay then.
Thanks.
No, I'm not doing bye bye.
Tomoki, we have to bye bye.
-Onee-chan.
-Tomoki.
I'm going with Onee-chan.
-We're going.
-Oh, okay.
Look what happened when I used it.
The document's all smeared.
We're very sorry.
If you don't mind, can you tell us how
you had it stored?
What difference does that make.
Hey, you.
Have you been listening?
Pardon?
Oh yes, we're very sorry.
You'd better be listening, idiot.
It's a waste of time talking to you guys.
Bring someone higher up.
This isn't looking good.  It might drag on.
Let's go back and ask for Samejima-san's advice.
-Takagi-san.
-Huh?
You've been spacing out.
Sorry, Mashima, but can you go back first?
Are you going somewhere?
Really sorry.
Wait.
Hey, what's up?
Are you Daddy's friend?
Yup.
Tomoki disappeared.
Is everyone looking for him now?
-Yes.
-Well, then
-they might find him right away.
-They'll never find him.
I just know he's lost.
-They'll find him.
-I'm gonna go look for him.
Hey, wait.
Wait a minute.
If you go, there'll just be one more lost kid.
-I can find him.
-Calm down.
They'll find him.
He'll be alright.
But Daddy wasn't alright.
He said he was alright, but he died.
Tomoki might not be alright too.
I said calm down.
If Tomoki goes away too, I'll be all alone.
Okay. But you can't go by yourself.
I'll go with you, okay?
Yes.
It's so out of the blue, I have no idea where to start.
Tomoki's probably trying to go back to our old house.
So...that way?
I'm tired.
Are you lost?
I'm lost too.  We're the same.
I'll go take a look so you stay here.
-He won't be at this park.
-Why not?
Because of that.
He doesn't like that kind of scary things.
Is he really a boy?
He's a real wimp.
It's amazing he had the guts to run away from home.
Let's go that way.
Where am I?
Onee-chan.
Daddy.  Daddy.
Don't cry.
Can..Can you talk?
Of course I can.
What's your name?
I'm Sasakura Tomoki. I'm 6 years old.
He's not here.
You don't see him, do you? Let's move on.
Found him.  He's here.
This is Takagi.
Yes, we found him.
Oh, sorry, the sister's with me too.
We were searching together.
Well, she insisted, so...
This place?  Where is this place?
Tomoki, wake up.
-Onee-chan?
-Sh.
-We're gonna have to run away.
-Huh? Where?
Never mind, just run away with me.
Yes, good bye.
Huh? Where did they go?
Hey wait, what's going on?
Where are you going?
This way, this way, Tomoki.
This way.
Hey.
Hey, wait, hey.
-Let go.
-Why are you running away?
I don't want to be separated.
I want to be with Tomoki.
-That's not possible.
-Why?
What can you do?
There's this thing called grown-ups' circumstances.
You can't stay together.
We promised Daddy.
Daddy told us
"You guys have to stay together no matter what."
It's a good thing for the kids.
They've been together since they were born.
Even during sad times, they'll always have each other.
I'm really glad they're twins.
Thanks to being twins, they've always been happy.
Daddy's gone, and I don't want to be separated from Tomoki too.
Don't be mean to Onee-chan.
That hurt, kid.
Tomoki.
Okay, okay.
You guys wanna come to my place?
-What?
If you want to be together that much, come to my place.
Really?
Don't run away anymore, okay?
-Yes.
Hey, you go away.
-Come on.
-Let's go, let's go.
Yes, yes.
Yes, they got me good.
They say they're not going back.
Well, it's late, plus it seems they want to stay together a bit longer. Yes.
Besides, having walked around so much, they look tired.
I'll take them to my place for today.
Yes. Good bye.
Listen, walk quietly and slowly, okay?
Hey you, why are you following us?
No, the dog too.
You don't expect me to take the dog too, do you?
Pets aren't allowed in my room.
Besides, I'm renting the room on the condition I live alone, so
you guys being here is a secret too.
But he's gonna be all alone.
He'll be fine. He'll eventually go back to his owner if you leave him alone.
-No!
-Stop it~ Hush.  You're too noisy.
Alright. Just to the front door then.
Yes!
Go in.
Hello~.
Okay, I'll fix you something to eat so go take a bath together.
Alright~.
Here it goes.
-Were you totally surprised?
-No.
When is this from? Oh well.
-We're done with the bath.
-Hey, wait.
You're wet, you're wet.
Hold on, I said you're wet.
But we couldn't find any towels.
Towel?
Oh, that's right. Wait a sec.
Um...er...here.
Here.
Don't move.
You're gonna catch a cold if you don't dry your hair right away.
Is this too extravagant for them?
-Be quiet, be quiet.
-I'm scared!
Be quiet, be quiet, be quiet, be quiet. Listen.
It's alright, alright, alright.
Listen, listen, listen.
Don't move, okay?
I'll go look for a flashlight,
-so wait here.
-I'm scared.
It's not scary, not scary, not scary...
It's not scary.
Look, look at this.
Sing a song for him.
That song's scary.
That's too depressing.
Sing him a more cheerful song.  Yeah, a more cheerful song.
"Who's scared of ghosts.
There's no such thing as ghosts."
"Someone half asleep must have made a mistake."
"But just a little,
just a little"
"I'm scared too."
No! My canned mackerel!
Hey, stop, stop.
Hey, put it away, put it away.
-This should be it.
-Alright.
Please sign here.
Yes, yes.  Sign here.
Okay, thanks.
Thank you.
-Did the package come?
-Huh? Yeah.
What are they?
Just some daily necessities and stuff?
You're trying to move back, aren't you?
Huh?
Isn't it kinda noisy up there?
Yeah.
Don't mind about upstairs and
answer me honestly.
It's nothing you have to be concerned with.
What's wrong with coming back to my own house?
Don't get defensive.
Besides, what are you going to do about your job?
I don't want any bums around here.
I'm in the process of deciding what to do.
Oh, I'll work here.
I'll give you break on my hourly wage too.
Don't be ridiculous.
Did something happen?
No, nothing's happened.
Would someone who had nothing happen
quit her job and move out of her place?
Is it a guy?
I told you nothing happened.
-What's this?
-Can't you tell by looking?  It's Goma-Shio (sesame seed and salt).
-Goma shio?
When you get desperate for side dishes, goma shio is the boss.
That's how it's always been.
Go on, say hello.
Hello.
Hello, Boss.
-Where's the food to go with the rice?
-Don't have such a thing.
Daddy used to cook for us every day.
Can't do anything about that.
Daddy is daddy, and I'm me.
If you have any complaints, talk to the dog.
I'm mad too.
Okay, let's do "itadakimasu."
-Itadakimasu.
Itadakimasu.
It's good.
-It's good.
See? Isn't it?
Oji-san*.
(*term for older men)
Don't call me oji-san.
Then tell us your name.
Me? I'm Takagi Mamoru.
Takagi Marumo?
It's Mamoru.  Mamoru. What the heck is a Marumo?
Takagi Marumo.
He said Marumo. What a funny name.
That's funny.
Don't laugh. Don't laugh, munchkins.
Yes, hello.
-Is this Takagi-san?
-Yeah, what's up?
It's about the customer we visited today.
Yeah, what happened?
Samejima-san and I are going there first thing in the morning tomorrow,
so we were hoping you'd be there too.
Alright.  Thanks.  Oh!
Takagi-san?
What happened? Are you alright?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Hey you, what are you doing?
Hey, put it away, put it away.
That's right.
Hey, why didn't it go off.
-We turned it off.
Turned it off?  Are you serious? What the...
Listen, you guys be quiet, okay?
Okay~.  See you later.
Good morning.
It's not morning anymore.
-What happened with that customer?
-Nothing.
We'll have to go back there again some other time.
Since you didn't come.
I'm really sorry.
-Did you oversleep?
-I'll go over to
-visit the customer right now.
-No, don't bother.
You'll just be adding fuel to fire.
Let it sit overnight.
I'm sorry.
Oh.
Takagi-kun. That report you did the other day,
is this all?
Oh, that one about ear cleaner.
Yes, the customer accepted the apology gift so
we managed to get it resolved.
Didn't I write that in the report?
But she bled, didn't she?
It must have hurt.
Well, that's what she's saying, but...
The cap can be surprisingly dangerous, huh?
That's what you get for cleaning your ear with it.
I hate to bother you, but can you give this a little more thought?
No hurry.
Ouch.
-Preparations OK?
-OK!
We're gonna make this whole place clean.
What about this?
Trash.
-This and this too.  They're all trash.
-All trash.
Just throw everything away.
-What about this?
-It's broken.
It's broken so it's trash.
They're broken so they're all trash.
All trash.
-What about this?
-Trash.
Oh what about this?
Yuck~.
Trash, trash, trash, trash.
It's dirty.
This is trash too.
Go, mop.
Go, go, go.
Hi.
-What are you doing?
-We cleaned the house.
We threw out the trash too.
Hey.
This ain't trash.
This too, this too.
They're not trash.
After all the cleaning we did.
Who asked you to clean the house.
Even though it may look like trash,
there's something that  should never get thrown away.
Mind your own business.
I'm sorry.
Seriously.
Onee-chan, I want to see Daddy.
Daddy wouldn't get mad at us like this.
It's my treasure, okay?
Wouldn't you get mad if someone threw yours away?
Daddy would have praised us if we cleaned the house.
What's there to praise.
Doing unnecessary things when I didn't even ask you to.
Daddy would have forgiven us if we apologized.
I'm not your daddy.
Stop acting like a baby.
-Daddy would have...
-Daddy isn't here anymore!
He's dead already.
We know that.
We know that!
For life?
For life..that's a lie.
I'm really glad they're twins.
Thanks to being twins, they've always been happy.
What should I do?
I said some terrible things to your precious twins.
Hey, Marumo.
Huh?
You're the worst, you know.
What?
The worst, huh?
Yeah, I'm the worst.
Onee-chan, I'm tired.
Here, I'll give you a piggyback ride.
Marumo?
Hey munchkins.
Sorry.
For saying such terrible things.
I was in the wrong.
Sorry.
Thanks for cleaning the house for me.
But I want you to understand that
Daddy isn't here anymore.
You miss him, don't you?
But you guys aren't the only ones.
I knew your daddy from way back too.
Ever since middle school when we were skinny kids with shaved heads,
we were together.
We always practiced together.
Even when we both got all dirty in the mud,
we grit our teeth and practiced hard.
Even during tough times, I was able to go on because he was there.
I had fun because he was there.
I really loved to catch his pitches.
He wouldn't ease up on
not one, not one pitch.
I'd sure love to catch that ball one more time.
How was I to know that he'd die.
No way.
Don't go and die without telling me.
Don't mess with me.
Don't leave me here by myself.
Are you alright?
I'm not alright.
I miss him, so it's okay, isn't it? Huh?
There are times where grownups cry too. Right?
It's okay to cry if you want to cry. Right?
Okay, let's go home.
-Yes.
-Okay, let's go home.
-I'm hungry.
-Okay, let's grab something to eat before we go home.
-What do you want?
-Goma shio.
Goma shio.
-Don't get into that stuff.
-Goma shio.
Don't forget the canned mackerel too.
What~!