Go, go, let's go.
Let's go, Marumo.
Go, go, let's go...
Yay, thanks, Marumo.
Good job!
You guys, when you're at the pool,
you'd better listen to the lifeguard, you hear?
And don't forget to do warm-up exercise first.
-Alright.
-Okay.
1, 2, 3, 4.
-Not yet, not yet.
-5, 6, 7...
And your homework too.
If you don't get them done, the annual summer break
-homework hell will be waiting for you.
-Okay~.
Okay, then, I'm off to work.
You'd better strengthen your lung power, you Arafou*. (*around 40 years old)
Leave me alone.
Okay, I'm going.
See you later.
Aya-chan. Good morning.
Oh, good morning.
What happened?
I just inflated 2 swimming rings.
The kids say they're going to the pool.
If you don't mind,
Aya-chan, can you watch them?
Sure, I can do that.
I just bought a new swimsuit too.
-Maybe I'll wear that.
-What? Aya-chan in a swimsuit?
Oh, I mean, um, that is...
They're only going
to the community pool so you don't have to wear your new swimsuit
and get all prettied up is what I mean.
What difference does it make.
Look, you're going to be late.
Oh. Thanks then.
Good morning, everyone.
-Good morning.
-Oh, Chief,
-good morning.
-How was your vacation?
We had a great time.
We went on a trip with my daughter and her family, but
it's the first time we went with our grandkid, so
I was so excited, I got carried away.
Here. Presents for everyone.
Thank you very much.
This may be for Rinka-chan?
Oh, it's cute.
This color, this must be for Tami-san.
Won-won-wonderful~.
This must be for Mashima.
C-cool~. I've been looking for something like this.
And this is mine.
I was looking for this...
I wonder where he went?
By the way, what are you doing for summer vacation?
Aren't you taking the kids somewhere?
Well, it's not cheap for a family of three to go anywhere.
What are you talking about. Now's about the only time they'd
-go on a trip with you.
-Pretty soon friends will come first
and they'll get busy with extracurricular activities.
Plus fathers can start getting on your nerves suddenly.
Really? But they're only in first grade.
If you keep on thinking you can go anytime,
you're going to end up not going at all.
Is that right? Trip, huh.
Excuse me~.
-Who's that?
-She's...um...
the insurance lady.
I advise you
not to make eye contact.
Seriously.
Oh, we haven't met before, have we?
I'm Shimada Hitomi with Happiness Life.
-Hello, I'm Takagi.
-How old are you, Takagi-san?
Are you married? Any children?
Um....it's a delicate question, but I'm going to ask anyway. How much savings do you have?
I don't have a wife or savings.
But I have 2 kids in the first grade.
You're raising two children by yourself?
-Yes.
-Oh no. That's very worrisome.
Hitomi's extremely worried.
-Hitomi.
-School expenses can be very high, you know.
Education through college costs 5 million yen for public schools,
10 million for private.
Double that for two of them.
Which brings us to this first.
Educational Endowment Insurance?
How you prepare for the future now
will determine the children's future.
It's going to be too late if you don't watch out.
By the time you regret it, it's too late.
-The children's future?
-Yes, of course.
Ta-Takagi-san.
Excuse me, Takagi-san.
-Yes.
-Um...It's about time
-for the visit.
-Oh, yeah. That's right.
I'll be waiting~.
Hello.
The customer was calmer than I expected.
I'm relieved.
Takagi-san, are you bothered by what that lady said earlier?
Kinda.
It's true, I never thought about
the children's future.
I don't even know how long I can be with them.
Mashima, what about you?
Is there something you're doing for your future?
I guess just a savings account and life insurance.
Life insurance? But aren't you still single?
What does a bachelor have to worry about.
I'm a bachelor now, but
I have someone I want to marry too.
Don't tell me...
Actually, I'm thinking about asking Aya-san to go out with me.
-I knew it.
-I frequented the restaurant
so I think she should know I'm sincere by now.
-I don't know about that.
-No, I'm serious.
Hey, get away, get away.
-You'll root for me, won't you?
-What do you mean root. We're not in middle school.
You don't look too thrilled.
-Huh?
-Don't tell me
you're after Aya-san too.
-Of course not.
-Then
can you find out
how Aya-san feels about me?
Who, me?
"They heard their stepmother
talking to their father."
"'We must get rid of the children.'"
"'Take them deep into the forest so that they never find their way back.'"
"Hansel said to Gretel"
"'Don't cry, Gretel.
God will protect us.'"
Aya-chan, what's a stepmother?
The second mother who comes
after the real mother's gone?
Stepmothers are scary, huh?
Huh?
Yeah, Hansel and Gretel's stepmother's mean, isn't she?
Aya-chan was reading us a book.
We have to write a book report.
Aren't you supposed to read the book yourself for a book report?
But Aya-chan's a good reader.
I hope you guys are doing your other homework too.
We are. Look.
Where?
Kaoru, you're writing practically the same thing every day.
Yeah, because I'm generally doing the same thing every day.
How about you, Tomoki?
"Today we had stir fry."
"The core of the cabbage was tough."
"Thank you for the meal."
-Our dinner menu?
-Yes.
The day before was tarako spaghetti.
Jeez, don't you guys have anything else to write about?
What do you expect?
They haven't gone anywhere.
You ran out of things to draw for your picture diary, huh?
Now's about the only time they'd go on a trip with you.
If you go on thinking you can go anytime,
you'll end up not going at all.
A trip, huh?
Just a sec.
Here it is.
Here, look.
Who are these people?
My junior on the baseball team in college and his family.
He went back to Yamanashi to work in the family's grape orchard.
-Yamanashi?
-Yeah.
Where is it?
Well...Pretend my head is Hokkaido.
Then if I do this, this part of my body is Honshu.
So the belly button is Tokyo.
Then if you go this way, this is...
you know, Mount Fuji. This is Mount Fuji, okay?
On the other side over on my right side.
Yamanashi's here.
-Clear as mud.
-Anyway, you'll see when you get there.
Okay, you wanna hop on over there for a visit? The grape orchard.
Really?
Yay~!
Grapes, grapes, yay, grapes.
Grapes, yay grapes.
A trip, huh? Sounds like fun.
Yeah. We get to swim in a river, not a pool.
Marumo told us
there're lots of real insects and bugs too.
Stag beetles, and beetles.
Crayfish and snakes too.
Come with us, Mommy.
Marumo said to invite you too.
Thanks. But I can't take time off work.
-You can't go?
-I want to, but maybe next time, okay?
Mommy will stay home.
You listen to Marumo-san, okay?
Okay.
We'll bring back a present for you.
Thanks. I'll be looking forward to it.
-Oyaji-san.
-Oh, hey.
I'm going to go pick up the kids while taking Mook for a walk.
-Okay.
-Can I go with you too?
I have some shopping to do.
-Wait a minute.
-Okay.
Looks like the kids and Ayumi-san are getting along.
Yes.
The kids look forward to seeing Ayumi-san too.
They must be, you know, getting more comfortable being a family.
I wonder how long we can be together.
How much longer until Kaoru and Tomoki
say they want to live with Ayumi-san.
When that time comes, I'll of course
abide by their wishes.
But sometimes I get sad.
That one day we'll have to part.
It was hot today too, wasn't it?
Yes, it was.
Can you find out
how Aya-san feels about me?
-Um...you know...Aya-chan.
-Yes? What is it?
Is there someone you like?
What?
Wait, what's this all of a sudden.
Aya-chan, you'd be annoyed if someone confessed to you suddenly, won't you?
Well, I'd probably be more surprised than annoyed.
Look, there's Marumo. Aya-chan too.
Mommy, don't you think
-those two make a good pair?
-They certainly do.
I mean, you may have already noticed, but
-I think it's love.
-What?
What? Is that maybe...?
Yeah.
W-W-What? But...
I think it was love at first sight.
What the...
-And all this time ever since.
-All this time? What? All this time?
But
you had someone else you liked.
Makimura-san.
-Huh?
Huh?
No, no, no, no, no.
It's Mashima, not me.
What? Oh...
I...I knew that.
And I decline.
I'm not going out with anyone.
W-W-Wait a minute, Aya-chan. Aya-chan.
Aya-cha's mad.
Did Marumo get rejected?
Seriously, he doesn't understand women at all.
Marumo.
Aya-chan.
Mook.
Hey.
Yummy.
-Here.
-Thank you.
-So Yamanashi, is it?
-Yes.
The family's growing grapes there.
Risa-chan, the wife, is my junior from college too.
She was the manager of the baseball team.
She was so cute she was everyone's idol.
So, as usual,
I bet
you were in love with that idol too, weren't you?
What? Well, a little.
You sure do like those idol types, don't you?
Thanks for your hard work.
So? Did you have something going with her too?
There was nothing. I'm the one who
-got them together.
-Got them together?
My junior, Daisuke, kept on nagging me to
be the go-between.
Intimidated by women in addition to being Mr. Nice Guy. You've always been that way, huh?
Well, yes.
Hey, Aya, aren't you acting a little hostile toward Mamoru today?
Not particularly.
Oh, then
we'll take care of Mook while you're gone, so go enjoy yourself.
What? Isn't Mook coming with us?
I want to take him.
Of course not.
Three of us are imposing on them as it is.
We can't have a dog tag along too.
Okay~.
We're here.
Takagi Senpai.
Hey, Daisuke.
It's been a long time.
You haven't changed at all.
You too. Here, some presents.
Wow, all this?
Thank you.
And this is Kaoru and Tomoki.
-Hello.
Hello. Nice to meet you.
Shall we go then?
Wow~ That's a big house.
That's Granny and Nana and Shota.
You can play with them later, okay?
-Hello.
Hello.
-I'm glad you came.
-Thanks for having us.
Come on in.
Risa, Takagi-san's here.
Risa. She must be working.
-Working?
-Yes, well...
She's getting some part-time work from the publisher she used to work for.
Huh? Wasn't she working in the orchard with you?
Not right now.
Takagi Senpai, it's been a while.
Risa-chan, long time no see.
It was a long way, wasn't it?
Sorry, we just kinda invited ourselves.
Bear with us for 2, 3 days.
Hey, say your greeting.
-Hello.
Hello. They're so cute.
They're twins, right?
Yeah. Kaoru and Tomoki. First graders. Sassy.
You can look forward to dinner.
-Risa has everything all prepared.
-Oh...
I'm sorry.
I don't have everything quite ready yet.
That's okay. Take it easy. Alright?
The grape orchard's behind the house.
Right here.
-This is awesome.
-Awesome.
Wow~.
Grapes all over.
First time I've seen this.
Grapes, grapes...looks yummy.
They're so excited.
All this belongs to your family, right?
That's impressive.
In reality, it's nothing to be praised about.
Our crop fluctuates from year to year, and
we don't necessarily sell everything we grow.
And here, I thought you guys were leading a leisurely life.
Far from it. We're just barely surviving.
I grew up watching my late father and mother
having a hard time making a living.
All I can think is I can't let it end during my watch.
That must be hard.
Until a little while ago, Risa was helping out too
and the two of us were busy working hard.
But she has a job now and truthfully, that job pays pretty well.
Grapes all over.
Grapes.
Hm? Grapes?
Are they samples? How nice.
Onee-chan, let's try some.
Okay.
What?
Stop.
Wah~.
Ahh~ Onee-chan.
Tomoki.
-Got 'em.
First time we succeeded, Onii-chan.
Yeah. We are, ready...
The Grape Warriors.
Purple Two.
-We shall meet again.
-Meet again.
Grape Warriors?
Onii-chan.
Damn it.
They got me.
What?
Onii-chan, are you alright?
Those guys used psychic powers to make me fall.
They're going to be hard to beat.
Are you alright?
That looks painful.
I have a band aid. I'll put it on for you.
Onii-chan, that's cute.
That should make it better right away.
Leave me alone.
Onii-chan.
The Grape Warriors are gone.
-Please, have a seat.
-Oh, thanks.
Is Risa-chan still working?
Yes, I'm sorry.
She says that it costs money to raise children. She asked me
if I can guarantee the kids' future with just the
income from the orchard.
I couldn't say anything.
Actually, Senpai, I need your advice.
-Hm? What is it?
-Risa wants to go to Tokyo...
Sorry.
-Hello?
-Takagi-san? What should I do?
What happened?
-I just got a call from the hospital.
-Hospital?
Dad collapsed when he was out and about.
What? Oyaji-san did?
An ambulance took him to the hospital.
Takagi-san, what do I do?
If something happens to Dad, I...
-Okay. Calm down now.
-Senpai?
Aya-chan, I'll head back right away.
-But...
-Calm down, okay? I'll see you in a bit.
-What happened?
-I'll have to go.
-What?
-Someone who's done a lot for me fell ill.
-Is he alright?
-I don't know.
-Are you going to tell the kids?
-No, I don't
want them to worry.
If it's okay with you,
the kids can stay with us.
Thanks. That'll help.
What?
You're going home?
Once I take care of business, I'll be right back.
You'll stay here, won't you?
No, we don't want to. We can't sleep over without Marumo.
-Why do you have to go?
-It's an important urgent business.
I have to hurry.
I'll explain everything later.
-It's gonna be lonely with just the 2 of us.
-What are you talking about?
-Remember the okite?
-We're family even if we're apart, right?
Even if we're apart, we're linked together
-so you shouldn't be lonely, right?
-But...
Okay. If Marumo has an important business, we'll try our best.
-Okay, Tomoki?
-Okay.
Alright. Okite is never wrong. Let's do it.
-I'll be back before you know it, okay?
-Aya-chan.
-Takagi-san. I...I...
Oyaji-san.
-Don't touch me, fool.
-What? Oyaji-san?
Takagi-san, I'm sorry.
Apparently, I misunderstood.
-What?
-I told you Dad collapsed, but
looks like he just threw his back out.
Yeah, well...
I was out stocking up and when I lifted a box, I felt my back go out
and I fell to the ground just like that, but
I don't think collapsed is quite the right word.
I'm really sorry.
I tried to call you right away, but I couldn't get through.
You were looking forward to this trip too.
You're mad, aren't you?
I'm glad.
Then your life's not in danger or anything, right?
I was just expecting the worst.
Takagi-san.
Did you leave the kids there?
Yes, but I didn't give them the details.
Anyway, I'm sorry.
No, no.
I'm glad it was nothing serious.
Thanks.
You just wait here until dinner, okay?
Yes.
Shota? Nana.
Onee-chan, what's that?
Well, well, hello.
H-hello.
Onee-chan, Marumo will be back soon, won't he?
Yeah.
Oh, it's the Grape Warriors.
You guys can stay overnight by yourselves even though you're only first graders.
You have potential.  Alright.
-We'll let you join us.
-I agree.
-Accept this if you want to be our comrade.
-Comrade?
That's right.
But there's one condition.
You have to take the Oath of Grapes with us.
Oath of grapes?
Grapes for everyone.
Everyone for grapes.
We fight for our comrades.
Will you swear?
-Yes.
-Thanks.
-Shota Purple.
-Nana Purple.
-Kaoru Purple.
-Tomoki Purple.
All Purple.
Grape Warriors, Purple Four.
（大輔）おっ。
Purple Two became Four, huh?
You look powerful.
Shota Purple, isn't there a Red?
-I want to be Red.
What are you talking about?
There aren't any red grapes.
I guess not.
Also, thanks for the band aid earlier, Kaoru Purple.
What's that about?
Hurry up and sit down. It's dinnertime.
-Delicious.
-Yum.
Kaoru-chan and Tomoki-kun, you're not lonely anymore, are you?
-No.
-That's a relief, huh?
Okay, I still have work to do.
Eat lots, okay?
Okay.
Isn't Oba-san eating with us?
Mom's busy.
Alright., let's go pick grapes tomorrow.
To be a great Grape Warrior, you need training.
Yay~.
Can't wait.
Senpai, is everything all right?
Well, I guess he just threw his back out. What a relief.
Is that right?
That's good.
Are the kids doing okay?
I just left them there suddenly so I imagine they're feeling lonely.
Actually, looks like they're having fun running around.
I knew it. Yeah, they'd be lone...
What? They're running around?
You're kidding.
At first they looked lonesome, but
now they're running around.
They're the Purple Four.
Purple Four.
Kids get acclimated real fast, don't they?
Yeah, but
they'll start getting lonely soon.
Watch, they'll cry in the middle of night.
Well, if that happens, I'll give you a call or whatever, so
-you can deal with them.
-Yeah, you do that.
Call me.
I'll keep in touch.
-Talk to you later.
-Okay.
Oh, Mook.
You finally noticed me, Marumo.
It's not that I'd forgotten about you.
But it's been kinda crazy.
I was alone all this time, you know.
It's lonesome being alone, huh?
I understand how you feel.
What's the matter?
I'm wondering how long I can be with Kaoru and Tomoki.
Takagi-san, excuse me.
Aya-chan. What's up?
I'm really sorry about what happened today.
I thought you might be hungry, so...
-It's good.
-I'm glad.
Are the kids doing alright?
I called a little while ago, and
apparently, they're having a great time playing with the kids over there.
Oh, I'm glad to hear that.
Are you going back there tomorrow?
Oyaji-san should be coming home soon, right?
-I'll stick around to help until he does.
-Really? Are you sure?
-Yeah.
-Thank you.
Are you keeping the restaurant closed for a while?
No, I think he's going to want to re-open right away.
Yeah, he would.
He sprained his back once when I was a kid too.
He got carried away during Setsubun*.
(*Bean-throwing festival)
-During Setsubun?
-Yes.
Right after my mother passed away,
when I said I wanted to throw the beans,
Dad got all fired up and dressed up as the demon.
The hair, horns, everything looked real.
He looked really scary.
Then Dad messed up
his back as he was avoiding the beans, and hence, the ambulance.
The red demon in an ambulance?
Yes.
He went on the ambulance still dressed like that.
But what I really wanted to do was throw the beans together.
After my mother passed away, the house was strangely quiet and lonely.
That's why I wanted to drive away the evil spirits with him.
But Dad got it wrong and became the demon.
What good does it do to drive away Dad.
But as soon as I yelled "Demons out," I felt much better.
Dad's thoughts came through to me loud and clear.
The best dad ever, huh?
Yes.
After you left, Dad kept on talking about you.
He must've been quite happy that you came back for him.
I was happy too.
Really happy that you came back.
Yeah, I was on my way home before I knew it.
I'm losing my patience now.
Alright.
-It's delicious.
-Really?
I'm glad.
Aya-chan, that's Tomoki's toy.
What?
Oh, um..I'm sorry.
Sorry.
Uh...um...I should get going.
Excuse me for intruding.
That's alright.
Ah~. And I tried to help you out too.
So that was you. What were you doing?
You should've seized the opportunity to score.
None of your damn business.
Onee-chan, it's so quiet.
Yeah.
Shota-kun, what was that?
Onee-chan, I wonder what Marumo's doing.
Yeah.
It's lonely not having Marumo around, huh?
Do you think Marumo will always let us sleep with him?
I'm sure he will.
'Cuz, you know, Marumo doesn't like to be alone either.
But what'll we do if Marumo gets married?
We might get a scary stepmother.
What? What should we do?
Oh, but
if he married Aya-chan, she'd be nice.
But Marumo got rejected, remember?
Oh, that's right.
If Marumo marries someone else and they have a baby,
maybe he won't want us anymore.
Will he get rid of us like Hansel and Gretel?
Will Marumo forget all about us?
Wow, they're huge.
Looks delicious.
-Mine are huge too.
-Mine too.
All of you, put your heart into it when you're harvesting.
The souls of our ancestors are in our grapes.
-Ancestors?
-Yeah, my
father and mother,
their father and mother, and
their father and mother.
They're all our ancestors.
There sure are a lot of ancestors, huh?
This grape orchard was preserved carefully by all of them.
People may die, but their spirits remain.
Our ancestors' spirit is what makes good grapes.
-It's a little hard to understand, huh?
-Yeah.
It means that's why our grapes are delicious.
-Right?
-Yeah.
You're right. It's delicious.
The ancestors are amazing.
Here you go.
-That's a lot of food.
-Eat lots, everyone.
She's gone again.
Why doesn't Shota-kun's mommy eat dinner with us?
She lives here. Why?
Mom's busy.
But she used to eat with us, huh? Onii-chan.
She worked in the orchard with us too.
Mom never smiles anymore and she's always tired.
She fights with Dad a lot too.
She looked much happier before, huh?
-Yeah.
-Don't worry.
Even if she's busy, as long as your hearts are linked together.
-Hearts are linked together?
-Yes.
If the family's hearts are linked together,
she'll smile again.
She just doesn't remember that right now.
What does hearts linked together mean?
It means this here, and this here are linked together.
Here?
Kaoru-chan and Tomoki-kun,
are you okay even if Marumo-san's not here?
-Yeah.
Because we're family even if we're apart.
What's that?
Marumo's okite.
Marumo's okite?
Yeah. It's a promise Marumo makes.
If we follow the okite, everyone can live in harmony.
Even if we're apart, we're still family, so we're not lonely at all.
Really?
You're not lonely at all?
Well, maybe just a little bit.
But Marumo's okite is never wrong.
If we try our best, Marumo praises us.
You're family even if you're apart?
Does that mean your hearts are linked together?
Hm.... I don't know.
-Heart is a difficult thing to understand, huh?
You'll understand one day.
-What?
-Hurry, hurry.
-What, what, what?
-Come, come.
Shota-kun, what's this place?
This is Grape Warriors' secret base.
Secret base?
What's this? It's awesome.
Wow, it's amazing.
Don't tell anyone.
It's a secret just for the Grape Warriors.
Roger.
What the Oath of Grape Warriors?
Grapes for everyone.
Everyone for grapes.
Yeah. Let's help out if anyone's in trouble.
We're gonna have a boat race.
Ready. Go.
。
Nana-chan, what's the matter?
You wanna hear something good?
What?
A kappa* lives in that mountain.
(*legendary creatures living in ponds and rivers.)
What?
Kappa? That kappa?
They say kappa can grant your wish.
For real?
For real.
Granny said so.
Granny said she saw a kappa once.
-Granny.
Granny, you saw a kappa once, didn't you?
-I sure did.
-So she did.
There's some at Kappabuchi too, right?
That was a long time ago.
When Granny was a child.
Can we see them too?
I'm not sure.
There used to be many long time ago,
But now he's all alone so I imagine he's lonely and bored.
-I hope you get to see it.
-Granny,
Does kappa really grant your wish?
Sh~ That's a secret.
But it's true.
Just one wish that's important to you.
So it's true.
Don't go to Kappabuchi.
-Dad.
-It's dangerous there. Stay away.
Granny, don't tell them stuff like that.
That place is off limits right now.
Don't know what she's gonna tell them.
-That was fun, wasn't it?
-Can't you even make time
to eat?
Come on, Risa. Are you still busy?
The kids are leaving tomorrow.
-At least have dinner with them...
-Sorry.
I don't think I can.
Deadline's coming up.
Do you still want to take them back to Tokyo?
I've already told you over and over.
Of course that would be much better for their future.
I think they would be better off staying here.
As things are, can you guarantee their future?
Do you think you can enhance their well-being?
That...
I'll find a way.
The orchard business isn't going well,
and you know yourself that it's going to be difficult.
Onii-chan. Mom and Dad
were fighting again.
Shota-kun, Nana-chan.
I think it'll be okay even if they fight.
It's not okay.
But you're family whether you like it or not.
That's Marumo's okite.
Family whether you like it or not?
Yeah. Even if you fight, it's okay because you're still family.
That's what Marumo said.
But still, I don't want them to fight.
We like it better when they're friends, right? Onii-chan.
Yeah.
What can we do?
Oh, how about the kappa?
Let's ask the kappa.
Yeah, let's do that.
Kappa is out.
Dad'll get mad.
But doesn't kappa grant wishes?
Yeah. I want to ask kappa too.
Let's go see the kappa, Onii-chan.
But Dad told us not to go there cuz it's dangerous.
So you don't care if your daddy and mommy fights all the time?
Let's ask the kappa to help them make up.
Let's do it, Onii-chan.
Yeah, okay.
Alright. The Grape Warriors will embark on our secret mission.
Everyone, keep your guard up.
Roger.
-Okay, let's go.
-Roger.
Sh~ Sh~
-Mission accomplished.
Kappa, Kappa, Kappa-san.
Please come out, Kappa-san.
We want to see the Kappa.
Purple Four.
Come out, come out, Kappa-san.
Kappa, Kappa, Kappa-san.
We have a wish, Kappa-san.
We want to see the Kappa.
Purple Four.
Come out, come out, Kappa-san.
We want to see the Kappa.
Purple Four.
This is it.
It looks a place we might find kappa.
If we leave them here,
he'll come out lured by the smell of cucumber.
Where's kappa's house?
Maybe in the swamp?
But he might be in the bushes looking for food.
He could come out from anywhere, so look carefully.
Got it.
Ka-ka-ka...k-k-k-kappa?
D-Dad.
Hey, Shota, Nana. I know you're here.
Come on out.
If you come out now, I'll let it slide.
3, 2, 1.
I'm sorry.
You idiot!
You said you wouldn't get mad.
Of course I'll get mad.
There were stories about kappa since Dad was a kid too.
But someone who came to look for kappa
fell into the pool and died.
That's why this place is off limits.
Don't come anymore. Got that?
Yes.
What did you guys come to ask for?
It's a secret.
I see.
Kaoru-chan, Tomok-kun. Takagi-san will be here this afternoon to pick you up.
-Let's head home now.
-Okay.
Shota-kun, our secret mission ended in failure, huh?
Yeah.
Sorry we couldn't help.
They're not here yet.
I know for sure that they're feeling lonesome.
Marumo.
-We missed you.
-We were so lonely.
Sorry, guys. Sorry.
Sorry. Sorry.
That's how it's gonna be.
-Yup, that's how it'll be.
Marumo.
-Kaoru, Tomoki.
-Marumo.
Marumo.
Marumo, I don't want to go home yet.
-Huh?
-Me too.
-What?
-We're going to stay here
a little longer so can you come back next week?
Didn't you guys miss me?
Look, Marumo's here.
Takagi Senpai.
Thanks for coming all the way.
Sorry I ended up causing you trouble.
Not at all. My kids had fun too.
-I don't wanna go home yet.
-Me too.
You can come anytime.
We'll be waiting.
Thanks a lot.
We'll come again next year.
See you then.
We'll come again.
-We'll come again.
-Bye bye.
Hey, you guys. Were you serious when you said you didn't want to go home?
Yeah.
Because our
-secret mission failed.
-Secret mission?
-Goya Chanpuru*. -Sounds good.
(*Okinawan stir fry with bitter melon)
Oyaji-san, are you alright?
Is your back better?
Oh. I told them on the train coming back
-and they've been worried ever since.
-Oh, is that right?
Thanks. I'm much better now.
See?
-I'm glad.
Oh, that's right.
-Here, Oyaji-san. Present for you.
-Thanks.
Oh? A hand towel? And this. Like this?
Thanks. That's feels good.
-Here, this is for you, Aya-chan.
-Thanks.
-We got one for you too, Marumo.
-For me too? Thanks.
Oh, kappa? Cute.
That area's known for its kappa folklore, right?
-Yeah.
-This thing
on its back here. What is it?
-Oh, yeah.
-Put it together, and ka-ching.
A heart?
Hey, what's this? This is ridiculous.
Dummy. What the.... Dummy
Love plus love equals love love.
Love love marriage.
-Love love marriage...
-Hey, stop it.
Onee-chan, it was fun (zura), huh?
(imitating Granny's Yamanashi dialect w/"zura")
It was (zura).
I wonder how Shota-kun and Nana-chan's doing.
I wanted to be a Grape Warrior too (zura).
Let's go together next time, okay?
-Tadaima.
-Okaerinasai-zura.
What's with this "zura."
-What's this?
-It's a delivery~.
Oh, it's from Daisuke.
What can it be?
Ta-da.
Grapes.
-Looks good.
-Yeah.
Good.
Sweet.
-Hello.
-Thanks, we got the grapes.
Senpai, you never did get to eat the grapes, right?
Just let me know and I can send them any time.
Thanks. How's everyone?
How's Shota-kun and Nana-chan?
Daisuke?
The kids left home.
Risa took them to her parents' home in Tokyo.
-What?
-Actually,
we'd been arguing about the kids for a while now.
She insisted that it's better for the kids' future
to live in Tokyo.
Did you talk it over with Risa-chan?
Yes. I can't abandon the orchard,
plus I have Granny too, so
I tried to stop her, but...
Senpai, I wanted to raise my children here
at least while they were still kids.
There may be some inconvenience, but I wanted them to grow up
appreciating the things that can only be found here.
But I don't know what to do now.
I heard from Daisuke that you were in Tokyo.
Shota-kun and Nana-chan. Are they well?
They haven't quite adjusted to the lifestyle here yet.
Daisuke was worried.
About the kids and about you too, Risa-chan.
I want to take full responsibility
for the children's future too.
We have to do our best here.
What about the children? Have you thought about their feelings?
Takagi-san,
what are you doing about Kaoru-chan and Tomoki-kun's future?
What?
How are you planning to raise them?
If you're going to part with them someday,
that might be fine, but
I'm their mother for the rest of my life.
I agree that what you're saying is the right thing, as a parent.
Honestly, I don't know what to do about Kaoru and Tomoki's future.
I have my hands full just living day to day with them,
let alone the future.
Oh, that's right. If you want,
why don't you have Shota-kun and Nana-chan come over to play?
Kaoru and Tomoki's been wanting to see them too.
During the day when you're at work. How's that sound?
Thank you.
Come in.
-Shota Purple.
-Nana Purple. What happened?
They're my friend's kids from Yamanashi.
Shota-kun and Nana-chan.
-Hello.
-Well, hello.
What?
You're going to be in Tokyo from now on?
We're going to be living in Tokyo, apart from Dad.
Sorry. It's because our secret mission failed.
Because we didn't get to see the kappa.
I wonder how Dad and Granny are doing.
I wish Dad and Mom would make up.
Our family became separated.
That's not true. Families don't get separated.
Because even when you're apart, you're family.
Let's ask Marumo.
Marumo's amazing.
He can make everyone get along again.
Marumo.
Why is Shota-kun and Nana-chan's family separated?
Isn't it strange to live separately when both mommy and daddy are alive?
How can they get back together again?
Huh, Marumo.
It's not that simple.
Grown-ups have grown-up circumstances.
There are things outsiders should stay out of.
Marumo? It's impossible even for you, Marumo?
Not everything goes the way you want.
Just because you're family doesn't mean you have to be together.
There are different circumstances.
But it doesn't say that in the okite notebook.
That's not what the okite says.
There are times it can't be helped.
Shota-kun, Nana-chan.
You mom and dad loves you both very much.
That's why they decided to live separately now for your future.
But even then, I want us to be together.
Me too.
Marumo's okite isn't amazing at all.
Oh, Aya.
I'm going to Kappabashi to take a look at some supplies.
-Okay.
-What~!
Kappa?!
-Yeah, Kappa.
T-here's this place called Kappabashi
where they sell a lot of dishes and knives and stuff like that.
Do they have kappa at Kappabashi too?
Huh? Well...
I don't know about that.
But kappa folklores are everywhere, so
maybe they used to be in Tokyo too, huh?
-Dad.
-Awesome.
They might be in Tokyo too.
But where in Tokyo?
We could find them if we can hear them cry.
Do kappas cry?
I'm not sure if they do.
Ke~en, ke-en.
That's how kappa cries - ke-en, ke-en.
What? Is that true, Onee-san?
-Is that true?
-Yes, it's true.
I heard that from the person I'm dating.
-Thanks.
-Thank you.
Thank you.
Who's that?
-I don't know.
-Kappa does exist.
Yay, yay, yay.
Where could the kappa be?
This is Kappabashi, so
if kappa does exist, maybe around here?
Shota Purple, I think it's this river here.
-Here?
-Yeah.
Mook?
Do you want to join in too?
-Shota Purple, is it okay?
-Please let him join.
I'll make a special exception then.
Hooray~
We are, ready...
The Grape Warriors.
The Purple Four.
Plus
One.
(instead of Woof! Japanese dogs bark Wan!)
-Here.
-Okay.
-Thank you for waiting.
-What's next?
-What shall we take?
Well. Anyway, you were a big help.
Yeah, real big help. Thanks.
Ready~.
Oyaji-san.
-What?
-We'd like to get paid
-for our work.
-Oh, so that's what this was about.
Aya, give them 100 yen each.
-Alright.
-We don't want money zura.
That's right zura.
That's right zura?
-Thank you for the business.
Why cucumbers?
I'm not sure.
What's that?
What's a cucumber doing here?
It's coming. Kappa's coming.
What's this?
It's coming.
Here it comes.
It's getting closer.
-What's this?
-Now.
Wha-wha-what?
-What, what is this?
-Got the kappa.
Got it.
-Huh? Officer?
-What is this?
-He's not a kappa.
-Officer,
where's the kappa?
-Kappa?
-And give us back the cucumbers.
-Huh?
I'm really sorry.
I'll give them a good talking to.
That area is very dangerous for children.
Please be careful.
I'm sorry. Good bye.
Hey you guys. Why did you do such thing?
You too, Mook.
-Because we wanted to see the kappa.
-Kappa?
Kappa can grant us our wish, you know.
So we wanted to see the kappa and ask him to make Shota-kun and
Nana-chan's mommy and daddy to make up.
It's called "Operation Let's Catch the Kappa."
Kappa is lonely all by himself, right?
So he'll be happy if we give him our treasure.
He'll grant us our wish too.
Treasure is something that's important to you, isn't it?
They're important, but our wish is more important.
Look. There's no such thing as kappa.
-There is.
Looking for kappa is too dangerous. Don't do it anymore.
You two are the top priority for your mom and dad.
They made the decision for your sake.
Grownups have different circumstances.
It can't be helped.
Marumo said there's no such thing as kappa, didn't he?
Yeah.
About Shota-kun and Nana-chan too,
he said it can't be helped because grownups have circumstances.
Marumo and us, if we ever have to live separately,
will Marumo say it can't be helped?
I don't want that to happen.
Why did he say that?
That wasn't like Marumo.
Yeah.
Those guys were seriously looking for kappa.
Kappa. Ah, that's what the cucumbers were for.
It's your fault, Dad, for opening your mouth.
They said they're gonna find the kappa and ask him to grant their wish.
To make Shota-kun and Nana-chan's parents make up.
Not only cucumbers, but they were even ready to give up their treasures.
They were going to give them to the kappa.
That means Kaoru and Tomoki are growing up.
They're willing to go that far for their friends.
Yes.
I understand how they feel, but
it can't be helped.
Both Daisuke and Risa-chan
put a lot of thought into the children's future.
I don't know how much thought I'm putting into Kaoru and Tomoki's future.
About the kappa too. I wish I could grant their wish, but
I'm not sure it's something I should stick my nose into.
What do you think I should do?
I even told them there's no such thing as kappa.
Children doesn't give a hoot about grown ups' logic.
Whether it's kappa, or aliens, or
even that demon you throw the beans at.
Isn't it important to just let them believe that those things exist?
Believing that they exist,
chasing after them and confronting them,
that's what gives the children strength, don't you think?
What I mean is,
shouldn't you cherish their desire to believe too?
Takagi-san, did you find out how Aya-san feels?
Huh? Yeah, well, yeah.
Are you listening to me? Ta...
What are you drawing?
-Have you ever seen a kappa?
-Kappa? What are you talking about?
Of course I've never seen one.
You wouldn't, right?
Kappa, huh?
What? Could it be that you've seen one, Samejima-san?
Of course not, they don't exist.
-Of course.
-As I thought.
I thought maybe Samejima-san would say "They do exist," but
-they don't exist, do they?
-Why are you looking for kappa?
Kaoru and Tomoki,
they're looking for a kappa for their friends.
They got it in their head that if they can find a kappa
and make a wish, their friends' family can be happy.
-Ah...
-As if it existed.
But I kinda want to let them see it.
Even if their wish doesn't come true,
I want them to think that their wish got through.
I want them to think that it's not pointless to wish for something.
Anyway, it's nothing. Please forget it.
I see.
Kappa, huh? Maybe it does exist.
What are you looking at?
Yeah, come to think of it...
Huh?
Wait, what are you looking at? What?
What do you do to be a kappa?
Let's see...This?
-Takagi-san.
-Oh, Kana-san.
You're really into this, aren't you?
I heard about it from the people in your office.
Well, yes.
I thought maybe you could use this.
What is this?
It was used at the PR Department's year-end party last year,
but it's just been sitting in our storage room since.
You can use it if you want.
-This...
-Tell me all about it later, okay?
-Yes.
-It's perfect.
Really?
Thank you very much.
Hey, guys.
About the kappa.
Actually, kappa does exist.
What?
Really?
Yeah. I found a great kappa.
Awesome.
This, this. This is the map.
This Sunday, at this time.
Go see him with Shota-kun and Nana-chan.
Alright!
There is a kappa.
Leave it to Marumo.
Nothing's impossible for Marumo.
But,
it might be better if you don't get too close to him.
-How come?
-I mean
kappa is a supernatural monster, you know.
Who knows if you'll be safe around him, right?
-Yeah.
-Yeah, so
you really shouldn't stare at him.
Just take a quick peek from afar, okay?
-Got it.
Yay, yay. Kappa did exist. Yay, yay.
That's a cute treasure box.
Yeah.
A slice of watermelon.
-Shota-kun, what are you drawing?
-I'm drawing stars right now.
-This is mine.
-This is Kaoru's.
-This is Nana's.
-Do you think Kappa-san will like them?
He'll grant us our wish, won't he?
Yeah.
Shota, Nana. Lunch is ready.
Shota?
Kappa, Kappa, Kappa-san.
Please come out, Kappa-san.
We want to see the Kappa.
Purple Four.
Come out, come out, Kappa-san.
Okay, let's say the Oath of Grape Warriors. Ready.
Grapes for everyone.
Everyone for grapes.
We'll reach our destination soon but don't get scared.
Roger.
Shota Purple, I think it's over there.
Alright, let's go.
-Ready.
-Kappa, Kappa, Kappa-san.
Kana-san said "It's perfect," but
I'm not so sure.
Kappa, Kappa, Kappa-san.
Please come out, Kappa-san.
Aren't they here too early?
Come out, come out, Kappa-san.
-Where is he?
There.
Is that Kappa-san?
Excuse me.
Are you Ka-Ka-Kappa-san?
Are you really, really Ka-Kappa-san?
He's real!
Hooray~ Yay, yay.
Kappa-san, we want you to grant us a wish.
We brought you our treasures.
Will you hear our wish?
Yay~ Alright.
Onii-chan, it's the kappa.
Yeah.
Kappa-san, we have a wish.
Please grant us our wish.
Right now, my family's separated.
Even though we all got along well before.
But I still want the family to live together.
-Please.
-Kappa-san, please.
Please.
Dad's out in the countryside with just Granny.
He must be lonesome.
Mom doesn't smile anymore lately.
She's busy so it can't be helped.
I love Dad, and
I love when Mom smiles, so
I want us to be together like before.
Would that be impossible? Would it too hard?
If that's impossible, if it's impossible no matter what,
we'll try to endure being apart, but then
please make it so that
Dad keeps on loving Mom.
Even if the family can't live together,
even if we're apart, we'll endure it,
so please make it so that
Mom doesn't stop loving Dad.
Please.
I'll endure it too, so please.
Shota. Nana.
Kappa-san, do you know that even if we're apart, we're family?
It's Marumo's okite.
So please let Shota-kun's family get along again
so that they can be family even if they're apart.
-Please.
He said okay.
Kappa-san. Can we throw in one more bonus wish?
Please grant us a bonus wish.
Kappa-san, do you know Marumo?
Marumo gets mad easily, gets lonely easily, cries easily,
but he's kind.
No matter how busy he is,
he always does his best for Kaoru and Tomoki.
That's why I love Marumo the most in the whole world.
Me too. I love him the most in the whole world.
So I want to stay with him in the future too.
But we aren't real father and children.
So maybe one day we might be separated.
If Marumo gets married, we might get abandoned.
So even if Marumo gets married, even if we get separated,
please make it so that he'll
keep on loving Kaoru and Tomoki forever and ever.
Even if we're separated because of grown ups' circumstances,
please make it so that
Marumo would keep on loving us forever and ever.
-Please.
Of course, I'll love you forever. Seriously.
He said okay.
Onee-chan, he said he'll grant us our wish.
We did it, Tomoki.
-Onii-chan, we did it.
-We did it.
Alright, line up.
Thank you, Kappa-san.
We're... ready...
the Grape Warriors.
Purple Four.
Alright, let's go.
Kappa, Kappa, Kappa-san.
Thank you, thank you, Kappa-san.
So that's the Purple Four.
Huh? Where are the treasures?
I'm sure they left them around here.
What~! Ka-Ka-Kappa!
-Takagi-san?
-Oh, Risa-chan.
I found a kappa~.
I came back to Tokyo believing that it was for the children's sake,
but now that I know how they feel, I'm not sure of anything anymore.
What Risa-chan's saying
about it being for the children's sake.
I can understand it too.
When I think about the children's future, I get anxious too.
-Yeah.
-But in our case,
I don't know how much longer I'll be able to live with those kids,
and when you say Kaoru and Tomoki's future,
I don't really know what I can do about it after all.
So it may sound irresponsible to you, but
I'm cherishing the moment.
I'm a fool, aren't I?
Always acting on impulse and doing things like this.
But I'm determined to do anything so they're happy now,
that no one's going to beat me in that determination.
You know,
those guys eat rice sprinkled with just goma shio like it's the most delicious thing.
With a happy look on their face.
I want them to remember that
feeling of being happy for the moment.
I think what's necessary for the future may be a happy now.
I want them to have lots of happy moments like that.
If I can do that for them,
I won't be anxious whenever the time comes for us to part.
I regained my composure a bit after seeing the kappa.
Kappa? What's this?
We're coming home once.
Thank you so much for everything.
I don't know what will happen, but I'll talk it over with Daisuke one more time.
Shota-kun, Nana-chan. I'm happy for you.
Come visit us again, okay?
Daisuke.
-Dad.
-Did you come to get us?
What happened?
Nothing.
Senpai, looks like we put you through a lot of trouble.
Thank you for everything.
You have to come to Yamanashi again, okay?
Yeah. Promise.
Okay, let's get going.
Kaoru Purple. Tomoki Purple.
We shall meet again.
-Roger.
Cool. Grape Warriors.
Let's go then.
See you.
Nana Purple. Bye bye.
Shota Purple. Bye bye.
Marumo, we got to see the kappa.
We got to tell him our wishes too.
-Thanks, Marumo.
-Thanks.
Is that right? I'm happy for you.
So Shota-kun and his family's alright now, they made up, right?
Yeah, I think so.
Kaoru, what's wrong? Huh?
What, Tomoki. What, you too, Tomoki?
What, what, what, what? What's wrong?
Now that Shota-kun and Nana-chan's gone,
it hurts around here.
Yeah, me too.
Maybe our hearts got linked together.
Yeah, maybe when you care for someone, your hearts get linked together, huh?
Shota-kun and Nana-chan's mommy was smiling and looked happy, huh?
Yeah.
Shota-kun and Nana-chan looked happy too.
They were smiling because their hearts are linked together, right?
Yeah, you're right.
That's right. Let's write an okite.
If we believe?
our hearts will link together?
Yes. The important thing is to not give up and keep on believing.
If you believe,
-you may even see a kappa?
-Yeah.
That's why you got to see the kappa, right?
Do you think Kappa-san will grant us our wish too?
We threw in a bonus wish, huh?
Huh~.
What, what, what? What did you wish for?
It's a secret.
-What?
-Secret.
-What is it? Tell me.
-No.
Why?
Tell me, tell me, tell...
Anyway, let's eat.
Is that right?
I'm happy for Shota-kun and Nana-chan.
I'm relieved too.
♪♪～
Look, Marumo and Aya-chan's love and love equals love love~.
-What?
-Love love marriage.
Love love marriage.
Love love marriage...
You shouldn't be teasing grownups.
You guys. Sh~ Sh~ Sh~.
But you like Aya-chan, don't you, Marumo?
What?
Aya-chan, you like Marumo a lot too, don't you?
Yes.
Yeah.
What?
What~!
Why?