Summer...?
I really hate it.
I was kinda like it back then, but..
Since I was in junior high,
I started to dislike it.
Being sweaty is so troublesome, right?
I'd rather wanna go to school naked.
Cool!
- We arrived!
Eh, being naked is a bad idea..
Because it would be hard
to cover all those body hair.
The hair on the arm, armpit, back, etc.
Anyway, why do those hair exist?
Only to make you worry
if it seen by others?
Flying in the sky or reading people's mind..
I don't believe such psychic ability exists.
But, if it does exist..
I want to have an ability to remove
all unwanted hair in an instant!
That's dangerous!
Unbelievable..
Sounds fool, huh?
But compared with spoon-bending,
it will definitely be more useful!
What is this?
Probably, a giant Oarfish?
Giant Oarfish is the largest, greatly elongated, pelagic lampriform bony fish
that is usually found in all temperate to tropical oceans yet rarely seen.
Without realizing it,
I am now a twelfth-grader.
Twelfth grade is typically the last year (third grade) of high school.
I feel so old.
Friends, parents, teachers..
Everyone talk about exams. I got it!
I will study, but now I have to
do something else which is..
..nothing!
Eh~ this is so boring, although this is
my last summer in high school.
You lost that drug?
So, we won't be able to go back?
It's not a zero possibility though, wait a sec..
Unbelievable!
Yosh, I decided to enjoy this year's
summer season to the fullest!
Eh...? It's so quiet,
I thought you left me.
Where did you go?
Don't just leave and
disappear on me like that!
So cruel..
What are you doing so late
in other people's house?
Hey, where are you actually?
Please, don't go too far..
I feel lonely and it hurts, stop.. wait!
We will meet again, right?
No, this is scary. Please..
Come back!
Who's there?
Anybody there?
What is..
..this scent?
"Toki wo Kakeru Shoujo"
(The Girl who Leapt Through Time)
I'm more suited to go to
barbershop than hair saloon.
I can't help but liking a shaver.
Even girls can have beards, you know..
Like a lanugo.
Lanugo is very fine, soft, usually unpigmented, downy hair produced by the fetal hair follicles that is sometimes found on the body of a fetus or newborn baby.
You don't need to check it.
Eh, what was that?!
Don't tell me, Goro-chan..
You like me?
Even like this?!
Unbelievable..
This is impossible!
Ouch..
What's with this haircut?
You cut it in a hair saloon
yesterday, didn't you?
Altough I already told you
not to cut it that way.
This doesn't suit me!
"Today is July 7th, the day of Tanabata Festival."
"Everyone, please do write your wish on Tanzaku."
Tanzaku (短冊) are small pieces of colored paper used for hanging wish.
I can't go to school with such hair..
Why? It looks cute, like a helmet.
Helmet-like hairstyle is so lame!
"A Giant Oarfish was found in
Fujiura Coast, Shizuoka Prefecture."
Fujiura is close from here, right?
Isn't she from the same school as you, Mihane?
Wow, she is in a nationwide-broadcast news!
Thanks for the meal.
I'm leaving now.
- Take care!
The ice cream in the fridge is mine.
If you eat that ice, you will get
pricked by thousands of needles!
Mihane, get ready quickly
or else, you'll be late for school.
I'm going to take a day off.
Eh, really?!
Even though you always have a perfect
attendance since you're in kindegarten?
This would feel like getting choked all
day despite having a healthy body.
Bon appetit!
Mom, where is my camera?
Eh, I don't know..
Where is it?
Here it is!
Let's go!
Good morning!
- Good morning!
Hey..
Your hairstyle looks nice!
It suits you!
- Thank you for the lie.
No, it's true! But my dad will be sad, the moment he knows that you won't cut your hair in our barbershop anymore.
Nah, I'm disappointed with that hair saloon.
I will come again to Asakura Barbershop!
Really? Let's go!
Head off without me.
- Eh...?
I need to be filled with
my gasoline first!
Gasoline?
Is it for me?
*He asked if Mihane chose that mushroom-like haircut
because he'd once said to her that he likes mushroom.*
Because I said that I like mushroom?
Of course not..
Mihane, your gasoline is..
Today, I'm filled with a high-octane one!
High-octane? What is that?
What is high-octane?
5 minutes left.
- 5 minutes left?
Hey, do you like a man like him?
Yes, I like such good-looking man!
Like him?
- Yup!
Goro-chan..
Goro-chan, what are you doing?
Ah, sorry..
Sorry.. See you after class!
- I made you drop these flowers.
Please do forgive her,
I will scold her properly later.
Sorry..
- Sorry.
Let's go!
What's happened?
I bumped into him.
I bumped into him because
I was busy calling you, Goro-chan!
Isn't it weird?
How does it look like?
It looks round, like a mushroom.
Hello, good morning!
- Good morning..
Your haistyle looks nice!
It really suits you.
You cut it, right?
It does suit you!
Yup, good morning!
Good morning..
- Don't laugh at me!
- Oh, you cut your hair?
Like a Kokeshi, somehow..
Kokeshi are Japanese dolls made from wood, have a simple trunk and
an enlarged head with a few thin, painted lines to define the face.
Kokeshi, huh?!
As expected from Shohei,
you're as funny as ever!
I knew, Shohei would definitely make fun of me!
Is it too much?
To solve this problem..
We just have to multiply the reciprocal
difference between these denominators.
The difference between 3 and 1 is 2,
so we should multiply this with 1/2.
Which means, the main point is
to break apart the partial-fraction!
Easy, right?
Well then, for the next similar problem..
Who is going to solve this?
Yoshiyama Mihane!
Swimsuit looks nice, but now
it's time for math, okay?
Where is your textbook?
At least you bring a notebook, right?
I don't bring anything but this..
Wow, so romantic!
What a fool!
What do you come to school for?
Sorry..
Yoshiyama Mihane.
- Uh, oh.. yes?
What's with that dying message?
It means that.. this problem
can not be solved, I think.
But, I read it as "I want a special extra lesson".
No, thank you..
I already told him seriously
that I want to break up.
But somehow, we ended up kissing.
Eh, why did you end up kissing?
Since then, it was still two and a half
before the the cram school began.
Our lips became so swollen..
You're such an adult, Eri-chin!
I also want to have a boyfriend.
I don't want a princess
like you to have a boyfriend!
How about you, Mihane?
This year too, you will go to Tanabata
Festival with Asakura and Shohei?
Seems so.
Since we do it every year.
Asakura-kun will wear Yukata?
I want to be hugged by him!
Like this, tightly.
So cool..
I wonder why every high school
girls love to talk about love.
I hate that topic.
Didn't you say that there's a cool college student
who works at a convenience store nearby?
No, it was..
..not love or such thing.
More like a gasoline?
- Really?
It's not love!
Congrats, give applause to Yoshiyama!
It's broken in pieces..
I'm so sorry!
Somehow, I have a bad luck today.
I'm shocked!
I'm gonna throw this garbage.
- Okay.
Put the chairs down.
- Roger!
Please show us a little dance!
How cute!
Take a photo!
Ok, one.. two..
Who's there?
Anybody there?
What is this scent?
There is no such assertive man in life, huh?
How about Yano-sensei?
Yano-sensei?
His voice is too loud.
He wears fashionable clothes
and looks easily get bored.
This is a secret, ok?
- Okay..
How are you feeling? Both of them
are so worried, waiting for you.
So worried? Even though you're
both busy talking about love.
Why were you taking a nap in the lab?
I  wasn't taking a nap!
I smelt a sweet scent from fluid
that came out of a ruptured tube.
I was so curious so I smelt it again
and then I started feeling dizzy.
Was there a ruptured tube?
There wasn't.
- Eh?!
We just found you unconscious.
Eh, there was no flask or beak?
Those tubes were shattered everywhere, right?
Looks like someone had some
kind of experiments there..
I made him drop those tubes..
- I said, no such thing!
Right, Shohei?
- Eh...?
Right, nothing at all.
You heard him?
- Eh...?!
But Mihane, are you okay?
Do you feel anything strange in your body?
What's wrong?
What is it?
I'm hungry..
Are you kidding?!
You're the worst!
- Let's go home!
The conclusion is you had an anemia and felt
so hungry that it made you start hallucinating.
These two are so cruel!
Since there will be final exams soon, they asked me if there is
something wrong with my brain and told me to see a doctor.
You will face the final exams soon? Feels like
you just started being high schoolers yesterday.
Time flies so fast, right?
Our Keita is already a third-grader.
Right?
I should fill in my career plan.
What should I write?
Goro-chan, you're going to work in
your dad's barbershop, right?
But, my parents want me to go to university.
You should pursue your own
dream, because this is your life.
Although he is in social science,
he passed the science exams!
Then be a doctor, working with scalpel
gives you more profit than with scissors!
Hey..
- That's a different issue, though.
Eh, did we ever heard
about Shohei's career plan?
We haven't heard it.
Researcher, in pharmaceutical fields.
So you have such dream, huh?
Not a dream, it's the only thing
that can fit my genetic traits.
The only thing that can fit
your genetic traits? So absurd..
What was that?
- So cool..
Then, what kind of job
fits Mihane's genetic traits?
Eh.. what?
A boy and a girl that suddenly appeared on this boat?
You must be kidding, Yoshiko-chan..
It's true, that was just yesterday!
How can't you remember it?
Do you still take photos with your camera?
Yes, but I don't know what
kind of photos I should take.
Those photos taken by my friends using their
smartphones, looks more fashionable than mine.
I don't have the talent.
Then, I start disliking it.
Do you know her?
She is from our school.
Onishi Atsumi, right?
She is an internet idol.
Because of this, netizens are getting hyped up.
What do they say?
"Sent by a Dragon God, The Miracle Idol"
According to Japanese mythology, the Oarfish is
a messenger from the Dragon God of The Sea.
She just found an Oarfish
that came near the coast, right?
Nowadays, being an idol needs a foreword story.
Like flipping a hand, everyone in Class-2 seems
trying so desperately to be close with her.
Because now, she becomes a celebrity.
I also want to be a celebrity.
If it was back then when you were cute,
I think it's possible for you to be an idol.
But in this era, only having a cute face
won't ever be enough to be an idol.
Thank you for you hardwork!
- Thank you for your hardwork!
Then.. Mihane was born in the wrong era, right?
Wrong era?
I'm home!
Welcome back!
Don't eat my brain!
Eh, what's wrong with Keita?
Who knows..
Jan-ken-pon!
*rock-paper-scissors*
Yosh, PINEAPPLE~
Each time you win a rock-paper-scissors, you should spell a six-syllable word in exchange
for six steps down. This time, the word is パイナップル or "Pa-i-na-tsu-pu-ru" (Painapuru).
I wonder if this year will be the last time
we could go to the festival together.
Why?
Because next year, not all of us
will stay in this town, right?
Ah, right..
The 'princess' said that she want to be hugged by Asakura-kun in Yukata.
Maybe you should go with her..
Jan-ken-pon!
Yosh!
CHOCOLATE~
This time, the word is チョコレート or "Chi-yo-ko-re-i-to" (Chokoreeto).
Maybe I should..
If I go with Mihane, I will be forced
to eat the octopus from Takoyaki.
Takoyaki (蛸焼) is a ball-shaped Japanese snack made of a wheat flour-based
batter and cooked in a special moulded pan, typically filled with octopus.
It troubles me every year.
This year, I won't eat Takoyaki.
Jan-ken-pon!
Yes!
PINEAPPLE~
This time, the word is パイナップル or "Pa-i-na-tsu-pu-ru" (Painapuru).
This is so vexing!
You never win even once,
by the theory, it's too strange.
I did it seriously, though..
Mihane, thanks for the juice!
- Let's have a drink!
Heck~
Yuu-kun, thanks for waiting!
Here.
That gasoline has a girlfriend, huh?
Moreover, she has a long hair?!
Argh, so vexing..
It pisses me off!
Ah, my back feels itchy.
Scratch it for me!
Mihane..
..lacks of delicacy, right?
Because it's Goro-chan..
Be more feminine!
If you say it that way,
I'm gonna beat you up!
Well, then..
Bye~ Bye~ Bee~
Everything looks the same as usual.
What should I take photos of?
That doesn't seem right..
Yes, good.
Put it here..
Eh, a turtle?
Why is this turtle here?
It's dangerous!
Watch out!
Seems I really have a bad luck today..
I'm going to die!
Eh?
Watch out!
Eh, why?!
I already died, right?!
By any chance, I'm a ghost?!
Grandma, can you see me?
Is it finally my turn
to go to the afterlife?
So, I'm a Grim Reaper?!
What does this mean?
Mihane..
- What?!
Shohei!
- Wait a sec..
Wait, it's okay. Just calm
down and tell me everything!
Please, calm down..
- Tell me, am I dead?!
I am a grim reaper, or a ghost? No way!
- You're not even dead, you're still alive!
The same moment was repeated?
You might be mistaken.
But, how about the turtle? Without realizing it,
I already hold that turtle. Is it even possible?!
With such pattern, huh?
- Yes, with that pattern.
That is a pattern of mixed memory, where you might
have mistaken your camera as that turtle (kame).
I see, they look similar..
Not similar at all!
I read it once in a manga.
Maybe that was a Time Leap!
Impossible, you're not "Urashima Taro"!
There is a legend of a fisherman who visited The Dragon God's Palace under the sea
for 3 days but found himself 300 years in the future when returned to his village.
Oh, that's it!
This turtle has that kind of power!
Urashima Taro (浦島 太郎), the fisherman in Japanese legend, was rewarded
with an invitation to visit The Dragon God's Palace because he rescued a turtle.
Eh?!
Mihane?
Mihane...?
- Once more!
Mihane?
Mihane-san..
You don't want people to think of you
like some dangerous person, right?
So, it's better for you not to say anything
about that 'time leap' thing to anyone.
Got it?
Do you understand?
I don't understand.
What are you doing?
Secret!
If I tell you that I can leap through time,
you will definitely make fun of me!
This should be a top secret!
Mom, Onee-chan becomes an idiot!
*older sister*
Why did I get this haircut?
07 JULY
06 JULY
I'm going to make you look cute, okay?
No..
No~
06 JULY
07 JULY
Eh, what was that?
Onee-chan, what's happened?
Aaaaa~ Cockroach! There is a cockroach!
- This is not the right time to worry about that.
Dad, there is a cockroach!
Come here faster, it's a cockroach!
It's not the turtle!
I can..
..leap through time?!
06 JULY
I'm going to make you look cute, okay?
Don't cut it!
Whoa, yeay!
I don't have that weird haircut anymore!
Leap!
I can leap through time!
That's dangerous!
"Today is July 7th, the day of Tanabata Festival."
"Everyone, please do write your wish on Tanzaku."
Look!
This looks nice, right?
So, I allowed you to go to that
hair saloon for nothing, huh?
That's why I did it!
Bon apetite!
"Here is the girl who found it, Onishi-san."
"Could you tell us about the situation
there, when you found that fish?"
Even though you already have a girlfriend, and don't even care with her hairstyle?!
My stomach hurts..
The difference between 3 and 1 is 2,
so we should multiply this with 1/2.
Which means, the main point is
to break apart the partial-fraction!
Easy, right?
Well then, for the next similar problem..
Who is going to solve this?
Me!
Even snow could fall soon, right?
*he is comparing how rare for Mihane to solve such problem with the possibility of snowfall in the middle of summer*
I've prepared myself for this.
You can do it, afterall.
Cool, you can catch it in time!
I'm shocked!
Ouch, what the heck..
No way!
You become so wet.
Water~
Wait, not this one!
Why?
- Because, it's broken.
Here, this one.
Jan-ken-pon!
Really?!
CHOCOLATE~
This time, the word is チョコレート or "Chi-yo-ko-re-i-to" (Chokoreeto).
Goal, yeay!
Wait a sec..
You never lose even once,
by the theory, it's too strange.
Because I did it seriously!
The one who ends up lost
should treat us juices, okay?
Keep your promise!
- I will definitely win!
Jan-ken-pon!
Once more.
This sound..
..and this rhythm..
..make me so comfortable
that it may make me fall asleep.
Back then, you often fell asleep here.
Goro helped me keeping your head up
when I was cutting your hair, so nostalgic..
Since Mihane came here, you kinda
became the flower of this barbershop.
Mostly because no other female
customer would come here after that.
Also, there has been no young
male customers since then.
Ah, I see.
How about you?
Want to cut your hair?
No, for now..
I can cut your hair to look more share-otsu!
Share-otsu is a popular slang in 90s, a reverse pronunciation of "oshare" (fashionable).
He said "share-ostu ni NAU" and ((nau)) seems considered a lame pun for ((now)).
Saying it proves that you're old, Dad!
Back then, your dad was handsome.
You were also a pretty woman, back then.
Beppin-san is a term/nickname used to define a beautiful lady.
Time is so cruel, right?
You're also part of this family!
Power outage?
Mihane, bring me the flashlight.
Ah, thank you!
What are doing?
Eh, what's that?
I heard something..
- What is it?
Please, be careful..
Mom, there is a fire!
- Fire? Where?
Look, there!
- That's far from here.
Smokes are coming out.
- Ah, you're right!
It's near Goro-chan's house.
- Goro-chan? Asakura's house?
I have to go there.
- Wait, Mihane!
Mihane!
Goro-chan, glad you're okay!
Seems there was a fire outbreak
from the sub-station nearby.
Shohei.. Shohei!
How is it?
It's been extinguished now.
- Really? Thank goodness!
Only by having a small chance, she is is now at
the center of attention. She is amazing, isn't she?
But since the beginning, seems
she has the talent to shine, right?
Right..
The talent to shine, huh?
I also have such thing.
Eh?
What do you mean?
- I also have that!
5 seconds left!
4.. 3.. 2..
"A very rare and the so-called sea monster, The Giant
Oarfish was found in Fujiura Coast, Shizuoka Prefecture."
07 JULY
"Here is the girl who found it, Yoshiyama-san. Could you
tell us about the situation there, when you found that fish?"
"Something terrible would probably happen soon. Since long, Oarfish is known for..."
Wow, you're in a nationwide broadcast!
"Known for its trait that makes people called it
as a sea monster, Oarfish has a silver body and..."
What are you planning to do?
I want to be a celebrity.
Like, being an idol?
In this era, your face..
No matter how cute my face is,
it won't ever be enough to be an idol.
I got it.
She just called herself "cute", huh?
- Indeed, she did.
That's why, I'm gonna be a clairvoyant idol.
Okay..
I will shock the entire world.
Record it properly, like this!
- Yes, I'm taking this properly.
Tonight at 08.10 pm, there would be fire outbreak
at the electricity sub-station near Asakura Barbershop.
It will cause a power outage in Fujiura.
Don't say things that would jinx us!
I'm telling the truth!
The fire will get extinguished
quickly, nothing to worry about.
If it's true, then it's okay..
- Let's introduce the staff!
The one who dreams to be a charismatic
barbershop owner, Goro-chan and..
..the one who loves to wear
a polka dot pajama, Shohei-kun.
Really?
- I don't even have a polka dot pajama!
No, I saw you wore it!
You saw me?
What do you mean?
If you upload this on the net,
people will laugh at you!
I wonder..
Well then, everyone..
Please look forward for it!
Here they come..
There's another unit coming!
See? My prediction comes true!
Eh? Polka dot?
- Here he comes!
It's a polka dot pajama!
- No, it's not like that.
My mom just bought it today and
I couldn't refuse it, so I wear it.
You're right!
Amazing~
"Video of a Japanese high school girl whose miraculous
prediction came true, has been going viral on the internet."
"In her first video uploaded on the net, she predicted that there
would be a fire outbreak around 8pm at a sub-station in Fujiura."
"Both the time and place of the incident that
she predicted, have been proven accurately true."
"Meanwhile, on the same day at 9am, there
was a similar accident occured in Wisconsin."
"The suspect who hid in a junior high school building,
is a man from South Ireland who has been arrested now."
"But the video from the clairvoyant idol, Mihane..."
08 JULY
I am now a famous celebrity!
I'm starting to enjoy my life!
How about stop being one?
- You think, I would do more?
I think, it's better for someone who gives
lots of effort like her, to get such attention.
You said it as if I was not
making any effort, huh?
Were you?
- I'm not the type who tends to show it.
You used to make lots of effort
before you left the boat club.
My back was hurt,
there's nothing I can do.
Despite joining a photography club,
you're still not making efforts?
Do you really wanna be a celebrity?
Since you don't know
what you really want to do..
You just seem like desperately trying
to enjoy being the center of attention.
Goro-chan, you know nothing about it.
It's Yoshiyama!
She is so cute!
Do your best!
How about tomorrow's Tanabata Festival?
You will go there with us, right?
Seems pprobably not, or else
my fans would gather around us.
Mihane-senpai!
Goro-senpai!
Good afternoon!
- Good afternoon!
Mihane-senpai, I will be in charge of bowing
in the upcoming beginner competition.
I'm going to carry on
the same courage as yours!
We will do our best!
- Yes, do your best.
Thank you, please do your best!
If you wouldn't mind,
please come and cheer for us!
That girl obviously did a time leap!
So, what should we do?
We can only watch over her, right?
You're mad at me?
Whose fault do you think is it?!
The world begins to fall into chaos!
The drug's effect will start vanishing soon.
Onee-chan is also popular in my class!
So, you finally start to respect me?
I always knew that you have such
talent. Give me an autograph later!
Onishi!
Do a backstroke!
Start swimming now!
Backstroke is a swimming style in which the swimmer performing backstroke lies flat
on the back; arms stretched with extended fingertips, and legs extended backwards.
Swim faster, we're going to record it.
Come on, do a backstroke!
Look, she's been recording you.
Let's not getting involved, okay?
Let's head back!
HEY!
Why are you bullying her?
I'm gonna call the police!
Police?
No way, let's go!
Sounds boring!
Onishi-san..
Are you alright?
09 JULY
Onee-chan, the police has come.
Police?
Yoshiyama Mihane-san?
Ah, yes.
Would you come with us to talk about
the fire outbreak happened on July 7th?
Why were you there?
I thought, it's almost the time of occurance.
How did you know about it?
That's because.. something
that I can not explain.
Because you're the one who caused it, right?
I didn't cause it!
Just tell us the truth..
If I tell you the truth, will you believe me?
Of course.
I can leap through time.
Don't understimate us!
Enough, why don't you tell us the truth?
I can leap through time.
Hey, tell us the truth..
I can leap through time!
Fireworks, huh?
It's time for Tanabata Festival.
After all..
I'm not cut out to be an idol.
Eh?
Well then, yoroshiku onegaishimasu!
06 JULY
5 seconds left!
4.. 3.. 2..
"I didn't expect to see an Oarfish here."
07 JULY
"Something terrible would probably happen soon.."
Wow, she is in a nationwide-broadcast news!
I'm fine being an ordinary high schooler.
It's not good to cause too many uproar.
Thanks for the food.
- You're welcome.
Onee-chan, the ice cream
in the fridge is mine...
You're already eating it?!
- Don't worry, I'll buy you one later.
She piss me off! Mom, you should prick
this b*tch with thousands of needles!
Naho, don't call her "b*tch"!
I'm leaving now.
Mihane, go change your clothes!
I wanna sleep a bit more.
Even though you always have a perfect
attendance since you're in kindegarten?
No worries at all, my perfect
attendance will keep continuing!
What?
09 JULY
Sorry..
Shohei has something else to do,
so he couldn't come with us.
Eh? Too bad..
Even though this would probably be
the last time we could go together.
That's why, let's enjoy this festival!
Okay~
Anyway, I'm wearing a yukata.
Is there no reaction at all?
Yes, you're really..
..cute.
Sounds too forced.
Afterall, fireworks are much
better seen from up close, right?
Here is the octopus.
Here.
When will you be able to eat the octopus?
This grilled flour-ball is more delicious.
Being able to go to a festival as an ordinary
high school girl, makes me so happy.
You said it as if you're an idol.
I was an idol!
The most popular idol in the world.
Oh.. in your dream?
You should just be grateful to be
able to come to this festival with me.
For that, I am so grateful.
- You're welcome!
That's why..
- Eh?
Would you be my bride?
Stupid..
- No, I'm serious.
Would you be alright if
I ask you to be my girlfriend?
Eh?
Would you?
Goro-chan, your serious face is weird!
I'm asking you seriously.
I want you to be my girlfriend.
It's hot!
Sorry..
Shohei has something else to do,
so he couldn't come with us.
Oh, I see..
Your yukata looks cute.
I mean, Mihane looks cute in that yukata.
Thank you.
What's wrong?
You act so weird.
Not at all.
Back then, we used to hold hands
like this so we wouldn't get separated.
Whoa, Takoyaki!
You can eat the octopus now, huh?
I would still eat it for you, though.
Because, I'm already 18 years old.
Goro-chan, the octopus..
- Would you go out with me?
Both of us.
Why suddenly talk about it when
we're still talking about the octopus?
This whole day, I had always been
looking for the right timing.
I like Mihane.
I like you.
I said, I like you!
Sorry..
Shohei has something else to do..
- For now, I don't need a boyfriend.
Why said it?
All of a sudden.
Yosh, let's watch the fireworks!
I want to be Mihane's boyfriend.
I like you.
Ouch!
Eh?
Why didn't you come to the festival?
08 JULY
I didn't come?
But the festival is tomorrow, right?
Ah, right..
It's tomorrow.
Tomorrow, you would have to do something
and you couldn't come to the festival.
And then, Goro-chan..
Anyway, I'm in a pinch!
Okay..
Let's go together to the festival!
But, Goro told me not
to go together with you.
Eh? So, that's why..
Eh?
So..
Goro-chan..
..is in love with me.
Love?
Since we have always been together..
Our relationship right now is more precious.
Love..
How does it feel?
That thing called "love"?
Well, I used to hear that such thing existed in the past. Despite hearing such thing..
Sorry, what I meant by
"in the past" is actually "now".
How does it feel?
"L.O.V.E."
I consult with the wrong person.
Anyway, you should come to the festival!
Come, okay?!
Love..
Love~
This is yummy!
Yummy~
Mom, have you ever fallen in love?
Why did you suddenly ask?
I wonder if I can fall in love.
They say, falling in love
is not a natural thing.
500 years ago during a war period,
political marriages was a common thing.
Even in 100 years from now,
love is not going to exist.
Because a couple would be decided by
the compatibility of their genetic traits.
No one can't fall in love.
Really?
- Yes.
Slowly looking for love would also be fine.
I see..
Each of them are the same!
Failed another Goukon, huh?
Goukon (合コン) is an organized group dating that is popular in Japan.
I'm quite popular, you know..
But, they are all too shy.
If only they can be more assertive..
I would straightly fall in love, right?
Welcome!
- Thank you.
Maekawa-sensei?
Yano-sensei?
You often come to this shop?
Yes, sometimes.
Isn't it too far?
Is your relationship bad?
No..
Well then, may I sit beside you?
Of course.
What would you like to drink?
- Beer.
Okay..
- One beer!
Have some snacks.
- Oh, thank you!
When you help someone in a pinch
situation, love will starts blooming.
Helping those in a pinch? Love..
09 JULY
Sorry..
Shohei has something else to do,
so he couldn't come with us.
He already did that thing!
This "Kakigori" thing tastes extremely good!
Kakigori (かき氷) is a Japanese shaved ice dessert flavored with
syrup and a sweetener, and often also with condensed milk.
Since this is the last, it would be
nice if we go together, right?
Right.
- Yummy~
From the moment I realized that I can leap through time..
I don't want to force myself trying to have a date.
Because both my first boyfriend and my first love..
..should not be something that can be repeated, ever.
You're covering me, move aside!
- Move closer, are you ready?
Yosh, take it!
- Okay~
Did you take it?
- Yes, I did.
Are you sure?
- Yes, I'm sure!
So slow..
That's why I said
I would buy it for her.
Frozen pineapple tastes so good!
That good?
- Yes, this is scary..
This is too good.
It scares me off!
What a yummy frozen pineapple!
Thank you.
- Your welcome.
Yakisoba!
Yakisoba (焼きそば/fried buckwheat), is a classic Japanese street food made by stir-frying
boiled ramen noodles, vegetables, and meat/seafood with a sweet and savory sauce.
Eh?
- What is it?
Someone, help!
Let's hold this, 1.. 2..
- Are you alright?
Shohei!
- Hey, are you okay?
1.. 2..
- Shohei!
Shohei!
No!
Shohei! Shohei!
This is too good.
It scares me off!
Watch out!
Shohei!
Ouch..
What are you doing?
Ah, pineapple..
Thank goodness!
Thank goodness, you're safe!
Nothing is safe!
My frozen pineapple?!
What's wrong?
This thing would fall soon and
Shohei would be trapped under it.
That would be terribly!
I'm telling the truth!
This is dangerous.
We should change the rope.
Bring me the new ones.
Okay~
I thought you're gonna die!
I thought it was too late..
Thank goodness, you're still alive!
Why are you crying?
I'm worried, you fool!
Don't laugh!
You're crying too much.
- Don't laugh at me!
Because you're crying..
- I'm not crying!
This Frankfurt Sausage is too delicious, right?
Anyway, why Frankfurt?
Go search it on the net!
- What kind of fruit is so frank?
*He mistook (Frank)furt, which is spelled as フルト (furuto), as fruit?!*
Frank? I don't know.
- Too delicious!
Let me walk you home.
I need to scold Shohei about something,
so I'm going home with Shohei instead.
Wait, you're still mad about it?
I still don't get why, though..
- See you tomorrow!
Ah.. No, see you on monday.
Bye~ Bye~ Bee~
Goro-chan, please walk with
me instead. Goro-chan..
Why do have to scold me?
That was a lie.
Eh?
Because today I can't let myself
being alone with Goro-chan.
Oh, because he would confess to you?
I'm so cruel, right?
I'm not so sure, but seems this girl had
leapt through time and saved my life.
Her crying face looked so weird..
..but, it made me happy.
Sorry!
In the past, I was often chased by dogs.
Go away!
They always chased me.
I was so scared.
Are you alright, Mihane?
Mihane, it's okay now.
That time..
Goro-chan was desperately trying to save me.
No, that's me.
Shohei was desperately trying to save you.
That time, Shohei was
desperately trying to save me.
So nostalgic, huh?
Indeed!
Hey!
- Cut it out!
What's with these messages?!
Don't look at this phone
without my permission!
You're the worst!
That hurts..
One love just disappeared from the world.
If you're falling in love,
that kind of ending awaits you.
That's why I'm scared.
You're talking about.. Goro?
It would be better if we just
keep being best friends like this.
When was the last time we
talked like this? I can't remember.
Me too, but I'm glad we can talk a lot.
Right.
See you.
This yukata looks good.
Good night.
Mihane, 5 minutes left.
Five minutes?
- Five minutes!
♬～ 嗚呼　あなただけは消えないで ～♬
♬～ ah anata dake wa kienai de ～♬
"Ah, I wish you wouldn't disappear.."
♬～ 戻れるなら　あの夏へ ~♬
♬～ modoreru nara ano natsu e ～♬
"..if one day, I could go back to that summer."
♬～ 青空を　見上げる僕は ～♬
♬～ aozora wo miageru boku wa ～♬
"While looking up to the blue sky.."
♬～ 手を伸ばす　意味を知らない ～♬
♬～ te wo nobasu imi wo shiranai ～♬
"I would stretch out my arms, although it probably means nothing."
♬～ 行き先なんて　どこでもいいさ ～♬
♬～ yukisaki nante doko demo ii sa ～♬
"I don't even care about the destination."
♬～ 空には届かないだろ ～♬
♬～ sora ni wa todokanai daro ～♬
"Because it wouldn't be a place that can reach the sky, right?"
♬～ 夏が舞う　そんな匂いと ～♬
♬～ natsu ga mau sonna nioi to ～♬
"The scent that flutters through out that summer.."
Good morning!
♬～ 太陽をさがす向日葵 ～♬
♬～ taiyou wo sagasu himawari ～♬
"The sunflowers that keep facing towards the sun.."
Good morning!
♬～ 花火　仰ぐ　その横顔 ～♬
♬～ hanabi aogu sono yokogao ～♬
"The side of your face staring at the fireworks.."
During the time when I couldn't go back,
a summer and a love had just begun..
♬～ 切り取って胸にしまっていた ～♬
♬～ kiritotte mune ni shimatte ita ～♬
"Those things have managed to cut through my heart."
This is all your fault!
Please make the drug quickly!
With my power, I'm going to have an encounter!
OST: "Koi wo Shiranai Kimi e" (NEWS)
Because, I was in love with that girl.
That girl's love might be able to conveyed through a photo.
Wanna try to kiss?