Eh? Wait a sec..
What's wrong with you?
Hey, you're so heavy!
Let's go on a picnic..
Picnic.
Eh?
I prefer go to an amusement park.
The three of us will go, right?
- No..
Just the two of us.
Eh, how about Shohei?
We always have fun together, right?
Let's have fun without him!
If it's just the two of us,
it will be more fun.
Somehow, your voice sounds weird.
Because, we are now a couple.
Eh?
Yoshiyama Mihane!
You who always work hard, have made me fall in love.
Amazing~
I love you!
Would you be my Juliet?
Romeo!
I hope you do not runaway from this.
I want a love that can't disappear.
If she finds out the truth about me,
will this love come to its end?
Her memory..
..can be easily changed by me.
Like a Kokeshi, somehow..
- Kokeshi, huh?!
Kokeshi are Japanese dolls made from wood, have a simple trunk and
an enlarged head with a few thin, painted lines to define the face.
No, that's me. Shohei was
desperately trying to save you.
Shohei was desperately trying to save me.
Love that is made from a lie..
Could it be a real love?
You slept too long.
Go on a picnic feels nice, but..
..going to an amusement park seems quite fun.
Then, let's re-start the day!
Eh? Really?
Of course.
"Toki wo Kakeru Shoujo"
(The Girl who Leapt Through Time)
Episode 4
Amusement Park!
Amazing!
- Let's ride a roller coaster!
What is that?
- Eh?!
You don't know what a roller coaster is?
Because this the first time
I go to an amusement park.
You've been wasting your life!
- You're kidding me, right?
Let's go!
Let's learn about the grammatical structure of "so that"!
First, start from its literal meaning.
"The water was so cold."
This means, the water..
Looks great!
Eh?
I won't let you escape!
Ride on, please..
- Okay~
Well then, get ready and fly to the paradise!
Let's go!
- Don't jinx us!
Oh, no!
Stupid!
Unbelievable!
- We're going down!
Unbelievable..
Once more! Once more!
- No, please don't! Really, I can't..
Mommy~
Genetically, I am not suitable for this!
Once more! Once more!
- It's impossible for me, please don't..
Encore~ Encore~
Encore..
Or maybe, we should stop doing this..
Right?
Delicious!
Yummy~
They don't see us, right?
Yup.
But, seems they're enjoying their youthful days.
You stare too much.
Thanks for the food!
Ouch..
Eeeh!? They both just
fell down at the same time!
Your voice is too loud!
Bon appetit!
Looks yummy..
They suddenly fell..
- They're gonna see us!
Hamburger, Aha~
Hamburger..  O, yeay!
Relative pronouns..
You should also identify which
phrase that follows the word "who".
See this encircled verb?
That cloud looks like a lion.
Like a zoo in the sky!
Ah, there.. It looks like
a fat kangaroo, right?
At the left, either it looks like an elephant's
trunk or.. oh, it's a standing polar bear!
Welcome back!
- I heard the rumor..
You passed the mock exam for medical school?
Seems that was just because of luck.
If you become a doctor,
please take care of Mihane!
If it's Mihane-chan, we would be
so glad to welcome her in this house.
If it does happen, we will give
you a hair coloring for free.
Really? Okay then, although my daughter is
not a smart girl, please take care of her!
You're willing to swap your
daughter with a hair coloring?
So cruel!
Instead for studying for her final exams, today
Mihane goes to an amusement park with her friend.
Maybe, she is ready for the exam.
- No, I don't think she is ready.
She shouldn't play too much, right?
Welcome!
Same cut as usual?
Yosh!
Looks pretty.
Although I am the one who
made you look pretty..
What are you doing?
- Nothing.
Go study, then. I will let you
know when dinner is ready.
Ah, I forget to buy Natto!
Nattō (納豆) is a traditional Japanese food made from soybeans fermented with
Bacillus subtilis var. natto. It has powerful smell, strong flavor, and slimy texture.
I don't want to take the entrance exam.
Eh?!
So, I won't enter a medical school.
I also won't go to college.
Dad!
Okay..
Welcome!
Eh, where is the customer?
Goro said, he won't take the entrance exam.
Eh?
If you don't want to go to college,
what are you planning to do?
I am going to do what I want.
- Doing what you want?
You don't say that you're planning
to take over this barbershop?
Forget it, you don't suit for this!
Don't decide it for me.
This barbershop has no future..
Think about your future thoroughly!
- I have made my decision.
Why?
Are you worried about the tuition fee?
That's not it.
I'm not interest to do it.
Why are you not interested?
Why do you want to take over this shop?
Since I was a kid, it has been my dream.
What kind of dream is that?
Don't just decide your future based
on things like dream or interest!
Face your capability!
It's so unfortunate to have parents who
don't want to support their son's dream.
So unfortunate!
So, what? You're saying that parents
should support all their child's dreams?
But, I don't think so.
Don't mistake your temporary feeling for a dream!
Then, let me ask you..
So, you're going to disregard
your parent's expectation?
You piss me off!
- Dad..
Is it wrong to live my life as I like?!
Don't decide it as you like!
Because "expectation" is too troublesome!
How dare you...!
You really want to be a barber, huh?
I have said that since long, right?
I got it.
But, I won't give this shop!
If you really want to do it,
do it somewhere else!
I got it.
Paella is the best!
It tastes good!
Yummy~
Because I was so fired up,
I tried to cook it since yesterday.
Since yesterday?
Thank you so much!
It's okay, I'm happy to see
someone eating my food.
Yummy, wait a sec..
what is this?
I wrapped apples with porks.
Is it a film camera?
Yes, this one is best!
May I take a photo of you?
- Yes, of course!
Okay..
That kind of camera is hard to find, right?
Ah, indeed.
Anyway..
I don't have any photo
from Shohei's childhood.
Although we have always been together
since we were small, I think it's strange.
Shohei's childhood photos?
I wonder if we have it here..
Eh, don't you have it?
In family album, for example..
I think we have it,
eh wait a sec..
Shohei, why don't you have any childhood photo?
This so delicious, what is this?
I wrapped apples with porks.
Eh, you wrapped apples with porks?
How could you make it?
Mihane, your phone is ringing.
Here.
Yes?
- Ah, Mihane?
You're not with Goro-kun, right?
Goro-chan?
No.
I'll let you talk to Goro-kun's mom, okay?
It's me, sorry for calling you suddenly..
Goro hasn't come back yet,
since he left our house.
Eh, runaway?
His phone?
He left it. If he is fine,
then we won't be worried.
What if he gets an accident..
Where does a high schooler usually go?
How about a manga cafe?
A manga café (漫画喫茶/マンガ喫茶, read as mangakissa, which "kissa" being short for "kissaten", means cafe or
cafeteria) is a kind of cafe in Japan where people can read manga. People pay for the time they stay in the cafe.
It's summer..
Maybe, he just wanted to sleep outside.
- Sleep outside?
Mihane, would you ask your friends about him?
Sorry for bothering you..
Goro-chan!
Where did you go?
Are you kidding me?
Thank you so much!
Goro!
Hello, I haven't found him yet.
If something happened to
Asakura-kun, I will die.
If you die, it will be more troublesome!
Goro!
Heck, where are you?!
Where did he go?
I think, he would feel like a loser
if he come back too soon.
There is no choice but
to leap through time, huh?
To the moment he left his house.
Let's go!
Eh?
Your face is telling me that
you don't want me to go with you.
I don't make that kind of face, though..
Though?
Probably, I should better go off alone.
Why?
Because.. Goro-chan would feel troubled?
Although I also worry for him?
Wait, is it possible that..
Goro started to hate me?
No, that is not why..
- Then, no problem!
Let's go!
He left his house around 7pm, right?
Right.
Tanabata festival?
Why here?
I made a mistake.
Once more!
Why don't you hang up?
You break the rule..
This time, you hang up first!
Geez, this is my bedroom..
- Jun-kun, you hang up first!
Eh?
Nothing..
Eh, why?!
This is a haramaki, huh?
Haramaki (腹巻, literally means "bellyband") are items of Japanese clothing
that cover the stomach. They are worn for health and fashion reasons.
Once more!
- Okay..
1.. 2..
Why are we here again?!
This is weird..
- Wait a sec!
I can't go back to a certain time!
- Stupid, this is so stupid!
We were at this bus stop after
came back from that amusement park!
15 minutes until he left his house!
Come on, Shohei!
- Wait, I can't..
This is too difficult!
- Use your feet!
Goro-chan..
Goro-chan!
Oh, there he is!
Wait!
Mihane?
Why?
Too hot!
Don't tell me, you guys leapt through
time only to stop me from leaving?
Why did you leave your house?
I said that I don't want
to take the entrance exam.
They said, it means I disregard
my parent's expectation.
Even though you already said that you
want to be a barber since you were a kid?
My dad asked me to forget it,
because I am not suitable for that job.
Let's find out then!
I will support you..
..and your dream.
I'm so tired..
..being Asakura Goro who always try
keeping up with people's expectation.
Let me do what I like!
That is how I feel.
Yosh!
Let's do it!
Do what we want!
Stop holding back..
Now, let's do what we really want!
Tonight, let's express our feelings!
Good, it sounds good!
We still have a lot of chances, right?
Well, even if this will get us into trouble..
That time, Mihane-san will do something!
Yes, I will do anything for you.
How is it?
Well, I'm glad to hear that..
But you guys just came back
from an amusement park, right?
I also want to ride on a roller coaster.
But I would disturb you, right?
You should leave me alone.
We can't leave you alone,
that's why we are here.
Yosh, then let's start with
things that Mihane wants to do!
The opposite, huh?
Why? Isn't it time for Asakura
Goro to express his feelings?
I will think about it later, but first
let's start from things you want to do!
Eh?
Then..
♪～ When there are just the two of us.. ～♪
♪～ ..would you mind if I forget anything else? ～♪
♪～ I love you.. ah, I really do! ～♪
♪～ Then, all of my friends plan to go out tonight.. ～♪
♪～ For now, I don't want to go to school or house! ～♪
♪～ Although those adults tell us to overlook our feelings.. ～♪
♪～ I won't overlook mine! ～♪
Let's sing it, guys!
♪～ I runaway with a stolen motorbike.. ～♪
♪～ ..without knowing where I head off to. ～♪
♪～ I keep driving through the dark curtain of night! ～♪
Sorry for waiting..
Miura-san, are you okay?
No problem!
After I did a medical check up,
they said I was just too tired.
Don't force yourself, okay?
So, did you enjoy your date?
It's for the school's field trip.
Ah, I remember something!
I saw something strange.
- Eh?
Our students, Yoshiyama Mihane and
Fukumachi Shohei were going on a date.
They were...?
No, it's not strange at all.
The strange part is that they suddenly said
"Nyo~" while fell down onto the floor..
Then, without any reaction..
They kept eating their hamburgers.
Strange, isn't it?
They said "Nyo~", huh?
- Yes, they said so.
Somehow it looks like
they used to do it.
Let's cheers, thank you for today!
- Thank you for your hardwork!
Why don't you use a glass?
- I don't want to add up the dish pile.
Onee-chan said she is staying
overnight in Ojou's house.
*Ojou = Princess*
Eh, shouldn't she study for her exam?!
Here.
Here we are!
- Yosh..
Let's dive in!
Cool.. I always wanted to enter
a pool at night, at least for once!
Have fun like this, is the best!
It's nice to be boys, you can swim
although you only wear your pants!
You can join us too!
- It's okay, Mihane.. Join us!
No, I am a girl!
Eh? So, you're a girl?
- Yes, I am a girl!
I am a girl!
Get ready!
If I win..
Ready?
About Mihane..
- I am not going to lose!
Start!
Do your best!
EH?!
- Where is my pants?
Eh?
Shohei, you're disqualified!
Sorry..
- For real?!
I lost it, sorry..
- Where is it?
Hey, stop it!
You always do that!
Really, don't look down..
Please stop it, hey!
Altair, Vega, Deneb.
The Summer Triangle.
*The Summer Triangle is a fixture of summer skies. Its three stars are Vega, Deneb and Altair.*
The milkyway is so beautiful.
The starlight actually came from billion years
from the past, til it finally reach the earth now.
Eh? Eh? Eh?
What's happened?
Wait!
- 1.. 2..
No, wait!
We just set a new record!
This is fun!
Mihane, this is Shohei's idea!
Are you kidding me? Goro,
you're the one who suggested this!
Well, we just have to
turn back the time, right?
Next turn is Goro-chan, okay?
Have you decide
what do you want to do?
I want to do something bad!
We already entered a pool at night!
This is something that
a good kid shouldn't do.
I want to do.. something bad.
I got it.
Go, break all the windows!
We just have to turn back the time,
then everything will be fine!
It means nothing, right?
If I do this.
I know what I want to do.
What is it?
I want to live like this forever!
How about repeating this day, over and over?
It's brilliant, right?
It's okay if tomorrow never comes.
It's okay, right?
If no one put their expectations on me..
I think, I can do anything I want.
That's why, I wanted to do something bad.
But at the end, I don't have
any courage to do something bad.
Isn't it boring to be a good kid that
can fulfill other people's expectation?
You're talking about being a doctor?
- It is what my parents want.
If you don't want to do it,
I think you don't have to do it.
It is not because
I don't want to do it.
Sounds complicated, right?
Eh?
- It does.
Since I was a kid, I have always
said that I want to be a barber, right?
At first, you want to be a scissor though..
To be an object?
It was in kindergarten!
- Even so, it's weird!
Why did you want to be a scissor?
Didn't you sound like a pervert?
What a dangerous kid!
- Indeed, right?
But, lately..
I am not sure if being
a barber is my real dream.
Because I keep saying to my parents and
my friends that being a barber is my dream.
Now, I feel like I can't throw away
that dream without any responsibility.
You know Shigemi from the baseball club?
Although he has playing baseball since he was a 1st grader,
he said that he doesn't really know if he likes baseball.
*1st grader of elementary school*
Eh?
I really understand how he feels.
How he feels about...?
"I don't know whether I like it or not,
but I keep doing the best I can."
Both Shigemi and I..
Because we don't really have interest,
we can't be passionate about it.
In this era, being allowed to do everything
freely, only causes you lots of troubles.
Between a lot of probabilities, you have
to find out and choose your own path.
You sound like a stranger.
In the future, people are
given suitable roles efficiently.
In a movie?
I'm saying that..
Goro is a hard-working and serious person.
Most of all, he is so kind with other people.
So I think, you're suitable to be a doctor.
I think, your parents want you to become a doctor
not only because of the result of your mock exam.
But, also because they have been watching
you grow up and then, they suggest it to you.
They say, people around you could
understand you, better than you think.
Sometimes, it happens.
Argh, my miserable face has been photographed!
For me, I see it as a face of someone
who strives hard to face his own future.
Nice words.
You know..
Even when I'm in college,
I want to keep taking photos.
That's why, I'm planning to go to Tokyo!
Eh?!
What?
When did you decide it?
Lately.
But, I just told you now.
Somehow, I feel embarassed.
What's with that pose?
So, "tomorrow" will be "today" soon..
"Yesterday" can't last forever.
One by one, "tomorrow" becomes "today"
and then, "today" becomes "yesterday".
Then, one day we will die.
In 100 years, we won't be alive.
May I do something bad?
Eh?
Nah, I'm going to do it.
I really love Mihane!
I have always liked you
but I always failed to say it.
Then, Shohei stole you right in front of
my eyes, makes me so frustrated!
But, I also envy him!
Shohei, make sure you
can make her happy!
Do you understand?
I have decided.
I won't go back to 22nd century.
I am going to make her happy!
I will stake my life for her!
Stupid..
Thank you, Goro-chan!
Why did you thank me?!
♪～ If you see the sun through the gap between your hands.. ～♪
♪～ I can feel blood flowing inside my body. ～♪
♪～ The worms, the cricket, and even the gerridae.. ～♪
♪～ Every living things become friends! ～♪
Are you kidding me?!
Have you set the timer?
- Yes!
Really?
How many seconds?
- Six seconds.
5.. 4.. 3.. 2.. 1..
Where have you been?!
If you really want to take over
this barbershop, then do as you wish.
I quit being a barber.
- Eh?
I will study for the entrance exam.
Then..
I will try to face my capability.
Okay..
You're hungry, right?
I have Natto for you!
OK.
Ah, I just remember..
We leapt through time..
..and I forgot about the lunch, this is bad!
I'm sorry..
I know you cooked all of these food with
full of efforts, but.. how should I explain this?
I totally forget..
This is apple-wrapped porks, right?
This is so delicious!
Sorry, although it may seem
like I have not ate it yet..
I already ate this.
Mom?
Do you know how worried I am?!
Do you hate me?
Do you want to leave me?
Don't leave me suddenly like that!
I won't leave.
I hate a hospital smell,
it gives me sickness.
How is it possible?!
To be honest, it's critical..
You have a serious condition!
Critical? Impossible..
Even an unhealthy lifestyle could not
cause your internal organ to be like this.
Significantly, even your bones
have been aging too fast.
Do you remember something that caused this?
Remember something?
"I came from the future.."
There is no way I can say that.
Two buta-tama and a drink, right?
Buta-tama (ぶたたま, Pork Omelet) is a an Okonomiyaki (お好み焼き) a Japanese
savoury pancake containing a variety of ingredients) with some pork-toppings.
1900 yen.
Why did I stay in 21st century?
Keita, you're not allowed to taste the beer!
Hey, wait a sec!
Give me the money!
There is only one reason.
Because my family,
Yuri and Keita is here.
I and Yuri are not married.
And, Keita is not my son.
Even so, they are my family,
precious and irreplaceable.
What a bother!
You should pay 1900yen to me,
or else, I would never forgive you!
Because of you, he runs away!
Stupid!
Because of that fate,
I met her that day.
It has been 7 years, huh?
An encounter can change someone.
If people from the future live in this era..
They are going to die?
I found out about it after I had
lived for 3 years in this era.
So, break up with Mihane-chan
and go back to the future!
For the sake of you both.
Miura-san, do you still want to live here?
I don't mind to die, because I have a family
that is more precious than my life here.
As long as I can be with Yuri and Keita until
my very last day, I would be very happy.
But, I wonder if it's okay for me
to be the only one who feels happy.
Eh?
Listen..
Mihane-chan can leap through time, right?
Jackpot!
I have to tell you something
about Miura-san from "Ribbon".
Eh, what about him?
He would probably tell
you something weird.
But don't believe him at all,
everything he says is a lie!
Huh?
He wants us to break up.
Eh?
Anyway, believe me!
Whatever happens,
I "want" to stay with you.
No..
I "will".
I wonder why you skipped a class.
Turns out, you're so fired up.
Zoe..
- Yup?
You should go back to the 22nd century soon.
I wish I can.
When the time starts cleaning up itself,
it will try to erase all the unknown things.
Eh?
"Ah, I wish you wouldn't disappear.."
"..if one day, I could go back to that summer."
"While looking up to the blue sky.."
"I would stretch out my arms, although it probably means nothing."
"I don't even care about the destination."
"Because it wouldn't be a place that can reach the sky, right?"
"The scent that flutters through out that summer.."
"The sunflowers that keep facing towards the sun.."
"The side of your face staring at the fireworks.."
"Those things have managed to cut through my heart."
"I had always thought that our future.."
"..would be going to continue forever."
♬～ 嗚呼　あなただけは消えないで ～♬
♬～ 戻れるなら　あの夏へ ~♬
♬～ 青空を　見上げる僕は ～♬
♬～ 手を伸ばす　意味を知らない ～♬
♬～ 行き先なんて　どこでもいいさ ～♬
♬～ 空には届かないだろ ～♬
♬～ 夏が舞う　そんな匂いと ～♬
♬～ 太陽をさがす向日葵 ～♬
♬～ 花火　仰ぐ　その横顔 ～♬
♬～ 切り取って胸にしまっていた ～♬
♬～ いつまでも僕らの未来はずっと ～♬
♬～ 続いてくと思ってた ～♬
♬～ ah anata dake wa kienai de ～♬
♬～ modoreru nara ano natsu e ～♬
♬～ aozora wo miageru boku wa ～♬
♬～ te wo nobasu imi wo shiranai ～♬
♬～ yukisaki nante doko demo ii sa ～♬
♬～ sora ni wa todokanai daro ～♬
♬～ natsu ga mau sonna nioi to ～♬
♬～ taiyou wo sagasu himawari ～♬
♬～ hanabi aogu sono yokogao ～♬
♬～ kiritotte mune ni shimatte ita ～♬
♬～ itsumademo bokura no mirai wa zutto ～♬
♬～ tsudzuiteku to omotteta ～♬
..are going to be swept away by the time.
Those who came from the future like us..
Eh..
What do you mean?
If people from the future continue to live in this era..
They are going to die soon.
Eh?
Going to die.. soon?
Eh?!
We are going to die soon?
Senpai, are you planning to stay?
To that day, after school..
Please take me back to the lab!
..with hypnotism.
So, the one who was desperately trying
to save me that day is.. Goro-chan?
I want to stay with you, Mihane.
You should go back to the future!
I want to you to leap through time..
..and make sure our family didn't exist.
Each encounter has its own responsibility.
In these 7 years, I have felt so happy.
I do not have a son.
Although this is my own decision,
am I too troublesome for you?
I don't want your life to be shortened.
I want to be with you forever!
Good bye.