I am not good at saying goodbye.
I hate it.
Just like how I hate crying all by myself after the last day as
10th grader because I should move to another class as 11th grader.
Saying goodbye to friends..
...means saying goodbye with all
the precious moments, and it's painful.
For me, time is life.
Hey, will you cry?
If our time together, comes to its end.
Keita, from now on, could you
please take care of your mother?
Of course!
Listen to what she says, and talks
to her about a lot of interesting things!
Of course, I will!
Thank you.
Mi-kun, you should also take
care of Mom forever, okay?
Okay, cheers!
Also, I should be careful not to do
anything that will make you hate me.
Eh?
You know, my dad left me
because he hates me.
No, that's wrong.
It's true, because I remember.
7  Years Ago
Hey, wait a sec!
Give me the money!
Ouch!
Because of you, he runs away!
Stupid!
Hmm, why did you cry?
It's not your business!
It's not your business.
Who the hell are you?!
She already paid her debt, right?
Eh, why are we here?
Yes, her debt has been paid.
Bon appetit!
Miura.. Miura..
Would you mind to be called "Mi-kun"?
Mi-kun!
Sounds good!
It's been 7 years since then,
and Keita has grown up.
It's been 7 years, huh?
My internal organs have been aging
much faster than Keita's growth.
It's been so critical.
When I heard about the result,
I think it was all my fault.
No, it's not true.
I'm afraid that all food I have ever
cooked for you are not healthy.
They said you're aging too fast and
there is no medical explanation for it?
It doesn't make sense.
Whatever it is, it makes me worried.
When I wake up in the morning..
I'm afraid that Mi-kun has gone away.
So, if I see you whenever I open my eyes..
It feels like a miraculous encounter!
The happiness from having such encounter usually
only last for a while, but I can feel it every day.
I'm so grateful!
That night, I was trying to find out
the proper way to say goodbye.
Soumen.. Soumen..
Soumen (素麺) are very thin white Japanese noodles made of wheat flour, less than 1.3 mm in
diameter. The noodles are usually served cold, so it's especially popular during summer time.
Isn't it hot?
Want to have a ride?
No, thank you.
I walk as a physical excercise.
I need your help, Mihane-chan.
Eh?
Actually, I came from the 22nd century.
What?
I came to collect some environmental samples.
But, after I met Yuri..
I decided to live in this era
and take care of my family here.
But few years after, I started to
feel something strange in my body.
When I did a medical check up, the result shows
that my internal organs have been aging too fast.
Seems it's caused by the energy produced
whenever the time does a self-cleaning.
Soon, all people from the future
would be swept away by time.
I can not live any longer.
Eh?
You're going out with Shohei, right?
You should break up with him.
Because, Shohei also came from the future.
Ah, really?
Anyway, that was a long introduction..
Why don't you say it like in a drama? Like,
"You are siblings that were separated at birth!"
Simple, but interesting.
Eh?
You just want me to break up with Shohei, right?
No, that is not what I want.
I want you to make sure
that our family didn't exist.
Eh?
I want you to leap through time and
make sure our family didn't exist.
What do you mean?
7 years ago, I want you to
make sure I didn't met Yuri.
Wait, I can't accept this!
I am not giving it to you.
- Eh?
Pay her debt with that money,
and even if she didn't meet me..
Yuri is so pretty.
I bet she would meet another
man who could make her happy.
She would be happier than now.
Please, lend me your help!
Impossible!
Moreover, I never said that
I can leap through time!
Stop pretending!
You can do it, right?
When you leap through time,
you always say "Nyo~", right?
Huh? Nyo~?
Oh, I see..
It might give you pain,
please be careful..
I said, I can not leap through time!
Hey, Mihane-chan..
Please help me!
Everything that Miura-san said..
do you think it was all a lie?
Sounds like a poor lie.
- You're right.
But, he knows about the "Nyo~".
He lied to you.
- Yes, he did!
Shohei came from the future?
It's definitely impossible.
Like I said..
- So, what are you?
Then, I'm a newcomer here.
Yoshiyama-san..
You may not know me..
I know you.
Onishi-san.
I am going to move to
another school in Tokyo.
Eh?
Since long, I have always wanted to be your friend.
One day, let me take a photo of you!
8.. 9.. 10..
Here is your photo.
- Thank you.
Wow, I look good in this photo!
I don't know why
you made up that lie.
Why I lied? There is no reason,
because I was not lying at all.
My body will reach its limit soon.
Tonight, I am going to have my last dinner.
But they do not know about this,
they think it's our usual dinner.
The moment they sleep,
I will leave them.
You're running away.
I think, each encounter has its own responsibility.
Responsibility?
You should say goodbye.
No, I can't.
We can't say goodbye to each other.
Because we are all so close.
Then, you should stay together!
The best thing to do is to make sure
our encounter never happened.
You can leap through time, right?
I know you can.
Please, lend me your help!
Because I really love my family!
I don't want them to be sad
because of my own problem.
I want them to keep smiling.
Please..
For me, my family are more precious
and irreplaceable than my own life.
Make sure that encounter didn't exist!
Lately, I can't leap to the right time.
I don't know if I can
go back to 7 years ago.
But, you want to do it?
But please don't run away
from your own family!
Thank you.
Sorry for waiting!
Bon appetit!
- Looks delicious!
This is for Keita.
- Thank you.
This is for you.
This is the best!
What's wrong?
- Eh?
Well..
There is something I have to say.
Our family will end today!
Eh?
End?
This family that we have for
these 7 years is going to disappear.
But, don't worry..
All of us will restart our life,
starting from 7 years ago.
Although we would not be together..
No one would feel sad or lonely,
although we won't meet each other.
Because since the beginning,
we would never meet each other.
Is this because you have
to be hospitalized next week?
Doctor said it will be just another
medical check up, you're exaggerating!
I want you to know..
..that I love both of you, so much.
I love you.
If it's possible, I want us to
stay together forever.
But, being together will only make you sad.
It will give you painful memories,
that's why.. you should understand.
Keita, help your mother..
Live your life to the fullest!
Then, find someone you love.
To live, is to love someone.
Both of you have taught me that.
You're just going to have an endoscopic examination,
but you say it as if you're going to say goodbye forever.
For being my family during these 7 years..
Thank you so much!
We are family.
I am so happy for that!
What are you saying?
We will be family forever, right?
Forever, as family!
Mi-kun, you're crying..
You're not cool!
Don't cry, Dad!
Okay~
Because you're a Dad, in our family.
Keita..
Ah!
Here.
- What is it?
Our photos from that day.
- Oh..
We look good!
We're the best family in Japan.
No, in the world.
Even in the universe!
It's sad to see your last dinner.
If you our encounter didn't exist,
all the sadness would be gone.
I wonder if having farewell
is the best thing to do.
Next is your turn, Mihane-chan.
Eh?
How should you break up with Shohei?
I have no intention
to break up with Shohei.
People from the future
won't have a long life.
Like I said, he is my childhood friend!
It's hypnotism.
Hypnotism?
Could you remember
his face when he was a kid?
Go away!
Stop it, go away!
Are you alright, Mihane?
Mihane, it's okay now.
That was Goro-chan..
So, the one who was desperately trying
to save me that day is.. Goro-chan?
Not Shohei..
♪～ Poetry of life.. ～♪
♪～ ..by a woman who falls in love. ～♪
Eh, where is Goro-chan?
What is he doing?
- He goes to a cram school.
7 years from now, you asked
me to give you this photo.
Stop!
Hey, wait!
I don't need this.
Welcome!
Good afternoon!
Today, we have to announce something.
We are going to be married.
- Eh?!
We want you to be
witness in our wedding.
Oh, I see.
- Congratulations!
Thank you so much.
- It's all thanks to Take-chan's family.
It's surprising!
Yano-sensei, you did it!
- Don't tell anyone for now, okay?
But, we have to think how to tell the others.
Hey, wait a sec!
Who are you actually?
Huh?
What do you mean?
You want to hypnotize me again
and change my memories?
You knew it?
My real name is..
Ken Sogoru.
My era has different environmental condition.
There is only snow all year round.
The last four seasons only
existed in 21st century.
I came to experience a summer season.
We only planned to stay for few hours, but..
Accidentally, I lost the drug for the time-leap.
Eh? You lost it?
It's a small bottle with a greed lid..
..filled with purple fluid.
Do you know it?
- How could I know?
Of course, you don't.
Then?
- Ah, then..
I tried to collect some chemical ingredients..
..which could only be done by
mixing some materials in this era.
I should have succeeded, but..
Did you make another mistake?
Mihane, you ruined all the potions.
..at the school lab.
On July 7th, after the class ended..
Eh?
So, you're saying that you
can't go back because of me?
It's your fault..
Well, it's true.
But, thanks to you..
We fall in love with each other, right?
Mihane?
So, you won't go back?
I'm still trying to make the drugs.
It will be done soon.
But, don't worry..
I will stay in this era.
Eh?
I thought you would be happy.
You should go back to the future!
Because if you don't, you will..
I want to stay with you, Mihane.
Even Miura-san..
If he really treasures his family..
Until the end, he should have stayed in this era.
Go back!
Although this is my own decision,
am I too troublesome for you?
Go back!
Go back to the future!
Mihane, help me..
- Huh?
Okay!
Take that.
- This?
Yes.
- Okay..
Ah, wait a sec..
You're too careless..
- What are you doing?
Why there is a newspaper here?!
First, you should apologize!
I just need to turn back time.
Eh?
Why?
What are you doing?
- Why?
Why?
Turn back!
Turn back! Turn back! Turn back!
Come on..
"For you, who do not know about love.."
(Koi wo Shiranai Kimi e)
You're going to leave?
Eh?
Stir like cutting it thoroughly.
Here.
Yes, like that.
About me..
You already realized it?
When you didn't come home
that night, I call the police.
I was so worried.
They said, I do not have a son.
Mom..
Don't you want to ask who I am?
I'm happy to have you.
I know, you're not a bad kid.
Thank you for all delicious food!
When will you leave?
Tomorrow..
Then you should wash the dishes
tonight, to pay your rental fee!
Mom!
What's wrong?
There is no reaction.
Eh?
Really?
This is bad!
I will grow old and die in this era?!
This is great!
I can stay in this era!
This stupid guy!
Amazing!
Yeay~
Mihane..
I have a good news!
After the last stage of the drug
making process, it has no reaction!
What's wrong?
Be happy for me..
Let's be happy together!
I can't be happy.
Shohei won't have a long life..
..and it's all my fault.
If only I didn't ruin your experiment..
You must have been back to the future.
I shouldn't have felt it.
Eh, what?
I shouldn't have fallen in love with you!
In the exam, there will be a lot of
problems that use 1/12 formula.
Learn more about it!
Is there something you don't understand?
I said something that I didn't mean.
And, then?
The way I said goodbye..
..was wrong.
If you realize your mistake, then you
won't make the same mistake twice.
Mayuka, let's go!
- Okay..
Is it possible..
Small bottle with green lid,
which filled with purple fluid.
Shohei!
He is not here.
Should I drink this?
Although it's quite hazy,
but I'm sure this scent..
I should go back to the school lab,
on July 7th, after the class ended.
Before I make that wish.
I remember something important,
so I decided not to go back.
If I go back to that day..
I will make my first love disappear.
Isn't it just a first love?
Isn't it a love that will be forgotten?!
One day, first love will only become
something that you use as jokes.
I have nothing to lose.
For the sake of my precious someone..
I should be glad to throw away my first love!
It's just a first love!
Although, he is just my first love..
Please..
Please! Please! Please!
08 August
On July 7th, at the lab,
after the class ended.
Please, take me back!
Would you be my Juliet?
Julio!
Nyo~ Ouch..
07 July
Shohei..
You're here, right?
Hey..
Hey, where are you?
There you are.
Why are you here?
I come to make sure you
can go back to 22nd century.
Before this..
I ruined your experiment.
Because of that, you can't
go back to the future.
I smell that scent and I fainted.
Thanks to that drug,
I can leap through time.
I had a lot of fun.
That scent is from a lavender, huh?
You may not know it, but..
We were a couple.
Eh?
Sounds weird, right?
Because it would happen
someday in the future.
You started to like me..
..and arbitrarily, you changed my memories.
So cruel..
Sorry.
You don't have to say sorry!
You haven't done it yet.
This is you, at the first time
you ate a frozen pineapple.
You smiled brighter than
when you saw the fireworks.
But, after this..
There was a decoration tower fell upon you.
Eh, really?
But, I leapt through time and saved you.
You're safe.
When you saw me crying because
I was relieved, you laughed so hard.
Why you're the only one
who wears a sport uniform?
15 minutes before..
For the first time..
You kissed me.
I was trying to avoid you,
but then I fell into the pool.
Sorry for avoiding you that day.
This is taken from our class'
performance at the school festival.
Shohei was Julio.
Julio?
"Romeo and Julio"
At the closing party, in front
of everyone, you confessed to me.
I actually hate such thing..
But..
I was so happy.
This..
We had a picnic.
We went to an amusement park.
We also had dinner in your house.
Entered the pool at night.
Your weird face..
What is it?
Looks terrible, right?
No matter how many times you did it..
I don't want to have a boyfriend like that.
People who came from the future..
..shouldn't stay too long in this era.
To make sure you can go back to the future..
There is no other way but to come here.
But, Shohei..
You said, you don't want to go back.
Even if your life will be shortened,
you want to stay with me.
I don't want it.
I don't want your life to be shortened.
That's why..
Go back!
I see.
Is it okay for you..
..if I go back to the future?
I've been trying to hold back.
But, if you ask me like that..
I don't want you to go back!
Of course, I want you to stay with me!
Because, you are my first love.
I don't want to lose you.
But, if you don't go back to the future..
You're going to die!
So, I give up..
I see.
Take this.
If the drug is done, you should go back!
Go back quickly!
Hey, this one..
You wrote it, right?
"For you,
who do not
know about love.."
This photo album has no
photographer's name on it.
This is..
..yours, right?
"For you, who do not know about love.."
(Koi wo Shiranai Kimi e)
Not yet. But from now on, you are going
to make this photo album, Mihane.
"For you, who do not know about love.."
(Koi wo Shiranai Kimi e)
These are good photos, right?
This is a very beautiful album.
Right, it's all thanks to Mihane.
"Ah, I wish you wouldn't disappear.."
"..if one day, I could go back to that summer."
"While looking up to the blue sky.."
"I would stretch out my arms, although it probably means nothing."
"I don't even care about the destination."
"Because it wouldn't be a place that can reach the sky, right?"
"The scent that flutters through out that summer.."
"The sunflowers that keep facing towards the sun.."
"The side of your face staring at the fireworks.."
"Those things have managed to cut through my heart."
"I had always thought that our future.."
"..would be going to continue forever."
"I wonder if this sadness would also disappear someday."
"Just like the summer we had spent together.."
"..when it finally came to its end."
"Ah, I wish you wouldn't disappear.."
"..and take me back to the middle of that summer."
"Just like how we fell in love that day.."
"I want to embrace you tightly."
"Ah, I wish you would never leave.."
"Once more, let me make a wish.."
"If only I know that it would hurt this much.."
"I wish we could have stayed as friends."
♬～ 嗚呼　あなただけは消えないで ～♬
♬～ 戻れるなら　あの夏へ ~♬
♬～ 青空を　見上げる僕は ～♬
♬～ 手を伸ばす　意味を知らない ～♬
♬～ 行き先なんて　どこでもいいさ ～♬
♬～ 空には届かないだろ ～♬
♬～ 夏が舞う　そんな匂いと ～♬
♬～ 太陽をさがす向日葵 ～♬
♬～ 花火　仰ぐ　その横顔 ～♬
♬～ 切り取って胸にしまっていた ～♬
♬～ いつまでも僕らの未来はずっと ～♬
♬～ 続いてくと思ってた ～♬
♬～ この悲しみも過ぎてくのかな ～♬
♬～ 共に過ごした夏がそっと ～♬
♬～ 終わり告げるように ～♬
♬～ 嗚呼　あなただけは消えないで ～♬
♬～ 夏の中へつれてって ~♬
♬～ 恋をした　あの日のまま ~♬
♬～ 抱き合えたら ~♬
♬～ 嗚呼　行かないでと願うだけで ~♬
♬～ もう一度と願うだけで ～♬
♬～ こんなにも　痛いのなら ～♬
♬～ 友達のままで　よかったのに ～♬
♬～ ah anata dake wa kienai de ～♬
♬～ modoreru nara ano natsu e ～♬
♬～ aozora wo miageru boku wa ～♬
♬～ te wo nobasu imi wo shiranai ～♬
♬～ yukisaki nante doko demo ii sa ～♬
♬～ sora ni wa todokanai daro ～♬
♬～ natsu ga mau sonna nioi to ～♬
♬～ taiyou wo sagasu himawari ～♬
♬～ hanabi aogu sono yokogao ～♬
♬～ kiritotte mune ni shimatte ita ～♬
♬～ itsumademo bokura no mirai wa zutto ～♬
♬～ tsudzuiteku to omotteta ～♬
♬～ kono kanashimi mo sugiteku no kana ～♬
♬～ tomoni sugoshita natsu ga sotto ～♬
♬～ owari tsugeru you ni ～♬
♬～ ah anata dake wa kienai de ～♬
♬～ natsu no naka e tsurete tte ～♬
♬～ koi wo shita ano hi no mama ～♬
♬～ dakiaetara ～♬
♬～ ah  ikanaide to negau dake de ～♬
♬～ mou ichido to negau dake de ～♬
♬～ konna ni mo itai no nara ～♬
♬～ tomodachi no mama de yokatta noni ～♬
Thank you.
Both this summer and this love..
I will take them with me.
I love you.
Good bye!
Please take them..
Ah, there she is!
Mihane?
I have to fill my university application.
Then, your first choice is Tokyo University?
Kyoto University? Harvard University?
Which one?
- Harvard!
Just kidding!
I want to enter an university
that has photography club.
Huh?
Seriously?
I have something I should do.
Got it!