First of all, let me state this..
This is all your fault.
Amazing~
We're arrived!
Here we are,
but it's too hot!
What an unexpected humidity!
Help me, please..
For now, don't tell anyone about us!
If you break that promise,
we will eat your brain!
It would be easier if
you hypnotize that kid.
It's hard to hypnotize a child.
Besides, no problem will arise because
we only stay here for three hours.
What a beautiful season!
"Summer"
Because of that day, 22nd century
doesn't have four seasons anymore.
There is only snow all year round.
People in this era won't believe it, right?
In our era too, summer should be there.
Let's bring it back, then..
Hey, you!
Your hairstyle is not cool at all!
Honey, do something with his hair!
What an uncool hairstyle!
- It's fine, it looks cool for me.
Wait, for godness sake!
I really hate this!
Argh, stop it!
You're going back with that hairstyle?!
It's terrible, the worst haircut I've ever had!
I think..
Girls who have a mushroom-like
hair are most likely submissive.
*Do-M: submissive, docile, etc.*
All the research samples we have collected
will definitely be appreciated by our Professor!
What's wrong?
I lost the drugs.
Huh?!
You lost that drug?!
So, we won't be able to go back?
It's not a zero possibility, though.
If we can find some chemical extracts from Crocus sylvius,
like from Lavender Essential Oil, and combine its scents..
What are you doing so late
in other people's house?
Is there any lab equipment in our house?
Mom?
There is no such thing in our house!
Shohei, if you talk to your teacher..
You can borrow it at school, right?
You're right, at school!
Yummy~
Eat it slowly..
Who's there?
Anybody there?
Hey..
This is all your fault.
So, you're saying that
we can't go back to 2122?
Didn't you say that we can go back?!
We will, let's go back..
- The hell we will!
Jan-ken-pon!
*rock-paper-scissors*
Once more, let me say it clearly..
This is all your fault.
It's better for you not to say anything
about that 'time leap' thing to anyone.
In this era..
Shohei, watch out!
Actually, I only intended to experience
how it feels to be in a summer season.
No, that's me. Shohei was
desperately trying to save you.
The moment I realized it..
This yukata looks good.
Good night.
In this era..
I'm beginning to fall in love.
"Toki wo Kakeru Shoujo"
(The Girl who Leapt Through Time)
Episode 2
I remember what your dream was
when you were still in kindergarten.
You said, you wanted to be a scissor.
I thought you're a dangerous kid.
Eh, what was that?
Goro-chan, you still like me?!
Like I said, it's better if we keep being friends!
Mihane.
- Eh?
Have you ever kissed?
Why do you suddenly ask?
They say, it tastes like lemon.
Lemon-kakigori tastes good, right?
Kakigori (かき氷) is a Japanese shaved ice dessert flavored with
syrup and a sweetener, and often also with condensed milk.
Huh?!
Eh, where is Goro-chan?
Wanna try to kiss?
What are you talking about?
Friends don't do such thing!
You did it with Goro-chan, right?
- Of course, I did not!
Don't tell me, you're also..
..like me?!
It would trouble me!
You're troubled, huh?
You're the one who caused
a trouble, Yoshiyama Mihane!
Those kinds of quadratic equation
will come out in the next exam.
Sir, how about cubic functions?
Is it going to come out too?
No, not that far.
This time, only until these quadratic equations.
What would make you in trouble?
- I won't tell any of you guys.
Whoa, you won't tell us?
Sounds like a fishy dream..
Definitely!
- Fool, of course not!
You're vexed?
- No, I'm not!
Why bring a watermelon?
- This is my lunch!
The last one should do ippatsu-gag!
- Ah, no way.. Wait for me!
*one liner jokes*
You beat me..
- Wait, look..
Isn't it..
..Nishioka-kun?
Looks dangerous!
- Isn't it really dangerous?!
So dangerous!
Don't lean forward!
Do I look like someone
who wants to dead?!
Eh?
Somehow, I really like high places.
My heart will beat faster
and it makes me feel alive.
But, it's dangerous..
It's dangerous!
Actually, today is my death anniversary.
Huh?
You have a nice chest..
*she is talking about his nipples, which actually sounds.. weird?*
Indeed.
No, this is not about it.
On this day, two years ago,
I got a heart transplant.
Like I said, for my previous self,
today is his death anniversary.
Meanwhile, my new self is
going to start his second year.
This new self is obviously me,
but this is not really me.
Eh?
What do you mean?
My character has changed.
Although I used to be scared of high places, for
some unknown reason, I have started to like it now.
Moreover, every night after 8pm,
I feel like my heart starts beating faster.
But, I don't know why.
You mean, it has something to do with
someone who gave you that heart?
Who knows? I do not know
anything about my donor.
However, I was told once that
my donor was about 15-18 years old.
Whoever that person was,
I feel so grateful for this.
That's why..
Even for a bit, I want to live in the way
that will make this heart feels happy.
It's hard to believe such thing.
So, how could I make you believe me?
However, I believe that aliens are exist.
Aliens, huh?
He fell down!
Hey, I think..
I'm going to tell you guys, about my secret.
Ah, I don't wanna hear it..
- I can leap through time!
Huh?
She said it..
I don't how I get this power, but seems
it started after I fainted in the lab.
I can turn back time!
May I laugh?
Wanna try do a jan-ken?
I definitely won't lose!
*jan-ken-pon: rock-paper-scissor*
Definitely?
- Definitely!
"Definitely" sounds too much..
- I definitely won't lose!
Okay~
Jan-ken-pon!
Wait a sec!
Eh?!
No..
This is unbelievable!
Right?!
Shohei, do you believe her?
Well, I don't want to believe
in such psychic ability, though..
He is going to fall down in three seconds.
3.. 2.. 1..
See? See?!
Like I said..
With my power, I'm going to have an encounter!
You're gonna meet Nishioka-kun's donor?
Yup!
Don't you want to know what kind of
person who unbearably likes high places?
Not really.
I also want to know about that
mysterious thing happened at 8pm.
You should not do it! If somehow,
you managed to save that person's life..
Nishioka-kun wouldn't get his heart transplant.
It's absolutely bad!
You're gonna cause lots of trouble.
I don't want to change the past!
I just want to know.
Don't check on things unrelated to you!
Don't do it!
You guys are too serious!
If you really have such power, you can
use it for lots of other things, right?
He is right!
Would you be alright if
I ask you to be my girlfriend?
I want to be Mihane's boyfriend.
I like Mihane.
I already used that power,
for things that make troubled.
Things that make you troubled?
Don't check on things unrelated to you!
You suck!
I'm gonna meet her, afterall!
I'm so curious to know
what kind of person she is.
Here, take it.
You're gonna leap through time, huh?
Do it, let me see it.
Looking at me like that,
would make me nervous!
Don't look at me!
- Stupid!
Eh?
She is not here.
Eh..
Eh?!
Eh, really?!
Mihane!
Unbelievable..
This is unbelievable!
Shohei!
It's a real thing, right?
Eh?
Mihane!
I hope there won't be any problem.
What is this?!
This is unbelievable!
She is back.
"She is back"?
What do you mean?
Amazing~
Eh.. Mihane!
Are you okay?
Are you hurt somewhere?
Do you feel anything strange?
Whoa, it's amazing!
- Then, how was it?
Amazing~
She was not someone who liked high places.
Eh?
Amazing..
Unbelievably amazing!
Two years ago, on the same day as yesterday,
there was a bicycle accident in the downtown.
She was riding down a steep road
when she suddenly had a brake failure.
She couldn't stop it.
The one who died..
..was a twelfth-grader.
Twelfth grade is typically the last year (third grade) of high school.
She is so cute!
She always studied in the library until almost
closing time, preparing for the final exams.
She was a diligent girl.
Oh, no!
Then, why Nishioka-kun likes high places now?
Anyway, did you really meet that person?
Of course, I did.
How about the mysterious thing
that happened around 8pm?
Who knows..
But after she went back from the library,
she always headed off to the train station.
Train station?
She was not going to meet anyone.
She always waited for the train that left at
8.20pm, and then she would head back home.
I see.
- Eh?
Do you know something?
You know it, right?
- Of course, I do!
What is it?
- She is a rail fanatic!
Tetsudou Otaku (鉄道オタク) is a rail fanatic, term used to define someone who is obsessed with trains.
Huh?!
Huh?
Because someone who
always rode on that train!
Like.. me?
No, someone she liked.
Oh..
Huh?
Oh~
Wait, I'm gonna check on it!
Hey!
- Mihane!
She went there as if she was going
to a nearby convenience store.
Is it okay to leap through time?
- No, of course it's not okay!
..I think.
It's dangerous!
Amazing, are you okay?
And, how was it?
She was in love, right?
Instead of being in love..
She was trying so hard
to hold back her feeling.
Hold back her feeling?
Yes.
"Avoid getting in touch with local citizens!"
Professor said that.
Although we hypnotized them,
it's still not good enough, I think.
You even come to school,
what are you planning to do?
People in this era..
..can fall in love.
Love?
Oh, people in the 21st century
still had a freedom to love, huh?
They can have a date..
..walk someone they love, to the rail station..
..and have a kiss.
Kiss?
Pressing someone's lips to another?
Some people even do
more than just pressing it.
I see, you know the details..
Because I have learnt about it.
Eh?!
Senpai, do you want to fall in love?
Senpai (先輩) is an upperclassman, someone of a higher age, or senior.
No way..
Love has no benefit
and the risk is too high.
98% of people in 22nd century..
..are married based on their genetic traits.
Of course, including me.
Before the drug can be re-created,
we can't go back to the 22nd century.
Since we are now living in 2016..
How about trying to enjoy it, Zoe?
You spread such thing on the net?
- Yes, everyone does it too.
Good morning!
Shohei, look at this!
Spiderman's kiss?
*term used for an upside-down kiss in which one person kisses the other in an upside-down position*
Yes!
Pretty sure you're gonna regret it!
This will stay on the net forever!
- That is why I uploaded it.
My boyfriend is so romantic, he said things like
Nagashima-san, "With this, our love will stay forever!"
How romantic!
- Right?
But, who is Nagashima-san?
Each of them looks good.
It looks good, right?
These photos are good?
Such photos...?!
She was not someone who liked high places.
Sorry, I found out about her.
About my donor?
Yes.
Tell me, what kind of person she was?
She was a diligent girl.
"I want to be with Sensei, but
I have to wait until graduation."
Ryou-omoi (両思い) is the opposite of Kata-omoi (片思い, means unrequited
love), which indicates that she was wishing to be his teacher's girlfriend.
She was in love with someone
she shouldn't fall in love with.
You may not believe me, but..
..that's the truth.
I see.
So, that's what happened around 8pm.
Thank you.
- Ah, it's nothing..
On the contrary, I checked
on things unrelated to me.
No, it's okay.
Each night, my heart beats faster around 8pm.
It must be because, she was used
to hold back her own feelings, right?
Afterall, we have to do
what we want while we can.
But suddenly taking her to high places,
would only make her feel troubled, right?
She might want to say, "No, this is not
the kind of heart-beat that I want!"
I can't tell everything about
that girl, to Nishioka-kun.
Eh?
She waited for Yano-sensei?!
No one knows..
..about Yano-sensei before
he came to teach in this school.
I think, I tend to intervene
with somebody else's problem.
Make sure you remember things
you have to do before 3pm!
Hey, are you awake?
If you really want to go to public university,
you have to be more focused on your study.
Sensei, did you ever fall
in love with your student?
Why do you ask suddenly? I never did.
If I did, there would be a trouble, right?
But there was a student who liked you, right?
So, what?
What are you thinking about that girl?
No student ever like me, though.
Even in your previous school..
None of the students loved you?
If it's just a misunderstanding..
There was.
..I think.
It's not a misunderstanding!
At the end, I don't know what it was
and I can never find out what it was.
Don't spead any weird gossip, okay?
She was died before she could
convey her true feeling. It's tragic..
So tragic!
Because no one knows
when they will die, right?
Moreover, her feeling has been
considered as a misunderstanding.
I'm so vexed!
- Why are you so vexed?
Although it felt so painful,
she kept holding back her feeling.
Then suddenly, everything had come to its end.
You don't know how frustrating it feels!
I know that feeling!
You're talking about how it felt when your
waist hurt and you have to leave the boat club.
Both your efforts and dreams became nothing.
Nothing at all.
That girl's love is also considered as nothing.
Although it really did exist.
Mihane..
Although you can leap through time..
You are not allowed to
change that girl's fate, okay?
Or else, you would snatch out Nishioka-kun's life.
I understand.
Anyway, Goro..
- Hm?
You like Mihane, right?
Eh?!
Actually, I think I'm also
falling in love with Mihane.
I wonder if it's alright for two
people, to love the same person.
What's with that question?
This is my first love,
so I don't really get it.
If it's alright, then we're good.
For the rest..
We should just leave it to Mihane.
Let her decide, right?
See ya!
Goro..
Have you ever kissed?
Huh?!
I wonder if Mihane has ever kissed.
I don't know!
So, it means..
Gora and Mihane..
..have never kissed yet.
Yosh!
Yosh~
- Yosh?
Yosh! Yosh! Yosh!
What the heck does he mean?!
Bye~ Bye~ Bee~
I don't say anything!
Please don't eat my brain!
I won't eat your brain.
In exchange for that..
Please give me some food!
I'm back!
- Welcome back!
Mii-kun..
- Hm?
I have a friend who looks hungry.
May I give her a Buta-tama?
Buta-tama (ぶたたま, Pork Omelet) is a an Okonomiyaki (お好み焼き) a Japanese
savoury pancake containing a variety of ingredients) with some pork-toppings.
For your friend?
Of course, you may.
Why don't you invite her to come here?
Don't you have a house or a family?
They are so far,
and I can't go home.
But you have a friend, right?
- Oh, you're talking about Senpai?
He pisses me off!
You have a fight?
- Something like that.
What do you call this?
Buta-tama? This is the best!
Because Mii-kun made it!
- Mii-kun? Who is that?
He is not my real dad,
but he is my dad.
I see.
Here comes the weakness!
This is impossible, right?!
"Chapter 7"
"With a kiss, make her fall (in love)!"
This sounds bad, really!
Welcome home!
- Ah, I'm home..
Here it is.
Taco-rice!
Taco rice (タコライス takoraisu?) is a popular of Okinawan cuisine, consists of taco-flavored ground
beef served on a bed of rice, frequently served with shredded cheese, lettuce, tomato and salsa.
Somehow, feels strange.
I forgot how much I love cooking.
Although he can't eat it right now..
Having you eat this dish
is also a happiness for me.
Mom, are you in love with me?
Yes, I love you so much.
Well then, may I kiss you?
What a joke, people will laugh
at you if you're such a mother-con!
Mother-con or "maza-con" is a Japanized English for "mother complex" (mama's boy).
Sorry, I just want to try it.
So cruel, try it with your hand!
"I wonder if it's alright for two
people, to love the same person."
It's not alright!
Heck~
I bring some university
brochures for you. Here!
No, thank you. I have much time left.
- Soon you have to decide!
Yes, but now I have to do my homework.
If you're hungry, we still have
natto for you. Do you best!
Nattō (納豆) is a traditional Japanese food made from soybeans fermented with
Bacillus subtilis var. natto. It has powerful smell, strong flavor, and slimy texture.
Okay~
Jun-kun, you hang up first!
Eh? Then, I'll hang up first.
Let me countdown, ready?
1.. 2..
Why don't you hang up?
You break the rule..
This time, I'll hang up.
Here I go.
1.. 2..
What the hell are you doing?!
- Who is that Jun-kun?
My boyfriend.
- Eh, you have a boyfriend?
Of course, I have.
I'm already an eight-grader!
Eighth grade is typically the second year (second grade) of junior high.
What have you done?
- Stop asking like children!
You know, Naho..
In this world, although they are deeply falling in love,
there are people who should hold back their feelings.
So, what?
Then you shouldn't fall in love, Onee-chan!
Nowadays, men are so submissive!
Why?
Let's stop drinking alcohol for now, okay?
I wonder if Yano-sensei is not interested
in having relationship with any woman.
Mii-kun, are you alright?
- Yes, I'm alright.
- Yes, just having a nosebleed.
It's fine, this is not a problem.
Don't make me shocked!
Yano-sensei has a high-level defense!
*she literally says "guard" instead of "defense", though*
What are those?
Utility poles and telephone wires.
Why?
- Eh?
It somehow looks beautiful.
Sometimes, we have that feeling
(when we look at things), right?
Well, indeed. But..
Somehow, it seems like you didn't really want
to take those photos when you took them.
Ah, sorry..
I don't know which one will look good.
There is nothing I want to take photo of.
It shouldn't just a "thing", right?
How about taking the moment?
The moment?
*he literally says "time" instead of "moment", though*
What kind of moments do you
want to keep forever, Mihane?
I want to to see those moments.
Sorry for being so inconsiderate.
It's okay.
However.. photos are good, right?
It can capture a moment forever.
That's it!
- Eh?
That girl's love might be able..
..to be conveyed through a photo.
I'm from The East High
School's Photography Club.
I'm looking for a model..
Sorry, I'm busy.
Asking her out of nowhere
would obviously look suspicious.
Excuse me..
- Do you hate being photographed?
Hey..
Being a model is impossible for me.
There is an insect there, look!
I really need to find a model.
Eh, really?
Sorry to bother you,
although I know you're busy.
I'm looking for a model, and
then I see you who look so cute..
Please, be a model for me!
What's wrong with you?
Somebody, help me!
I'm not a suspicious person.
I really am not!
What makes you look so troubled?
Ah, I have been looking for a model.
No matter how many times
I asked, I always got rejected.
Looks tiring..
- Yes~
Is there anything I can do to help you?
Eh?
Oh..
Yes, please!
I will take the photo, so..
Could you be the model?
Are you going to use it for a competition?
Probably..
If you lose, don't blame it on me.
Okay!
Finally~
I want to take prove of your love.
Do I look good?
This is my first time
being a model.
Hmm, can you please open it?
*she literally asks that girl to take off, or to (let her heart) be naked*
Eh?!
Open your heart!
What do you mean?
Like.. if you want to fall in love,
don't resist to show your feelings.
Imagine as if I am the one you love.
Let out those feelings of love!
I like you..
I like you.
I like you!
The prove of her love..
..is not something that I can ask.
How is it?
Looks good?
It does look good.
I hate being suck at this.
Sorry, I can't take it properly.
How could you know that I have
been holding back my feelings?
Because your heart shows it.
So, a cameraman can understand such thing?
Interesting!
Don't you want to convey your feeling?
He is a teacher.
The one I like.
If I can get accepted in the faculty
of medicine, I'm going to confess!
Today is her last day.
I should learn maths!
Next time, tell me about your love story.
I am not allowed to change her fate.
Eh?
Why are you crying?
You're so weird!
You shouldn't cry that much while saying goodbye.
You know that this is not a forever farewell, right?
Hey, stop crying!
Because you're so cute,
you should laugh instead.
I can't wait to see those photos!
Although you can leap through time..
You are not allowed to
change that girl's fate, okay?
Even for a bit, I want to live in the way
that will make this heart feels happy.
Come on!
See you later.
Without telling her that she has
a brake failure, I watch her leaving.
"Ah, I wish you wouldn't disappear.."
"..if one day, I could go back to that summer."
"While looking up to the blue sky.."
"I would stretch out my arms, although it probably means nothing."
"I don't even care about the destination."
"Because it wouldn't be a place that can reach the sky, right?"
"The scent that flutters through out that summer.."
"The sunflowers that keep facing towards the sun.."
"The side of your face staring at the fireworks.."
"Those things have managed to cut through my heart."
"I had always thought that our future.."
"..would be going to continue forever."
"I wonder if this sadness would also disappear someday."
"Just like the summer we had spent together.."
"..when it finally came to its end."
"Ah, I wish you wouldn't disappear.."
"..if one day, I could go back to that summer."
♬～ 嗚呼　あなただけは消えないで ～♬
♬～ 戻れるなら　あの夏へ ~♬
♬～ 青空を　見上げる僕は ～♬
♬～ 手を伸ばす　意味を知らない ～♬
♬～ 行き先なんて　どこでもいいさ ～♬
♬～ 空には届かないだろ ～♬
♬～ 夏が舞う　そんな匂いと ～♬
♬～ 太陽をさがす向日葵 ～♬
♬～ 花火　仰ぐ　その横顔 ～♬
♬～ 切り取って胸にしまっていた ～♬
♬～ いつまでも僕らの未来はずっと ～♬
♬～ 続いてくと思ってた ～♬
♬～ この悲しみも過ぎてくのかな ～♬
♬～ 共に過ごした夏がそっと ～♬
♬～ 終わり告げるように ～♬
♬～ 嗚呼　あなただけは消えないで ～♬
♬～ 戻れるなら　あの夏へ ~♬
♬～ ah anata dake wa kienai de ～♬
♬～ modoreru nara ano natsu e ～♬
♬～ aozora wo miageru boku wa ～♬
♬～ te wo nobasu imi wo shiranai ～♬
♬～ yukisaki nante doko demo ii sa ～♬
♬～ sora ni wa todokanai daro ～♬
♬～ natsu ga mau sonna nioi to ～♬
♬～ taiyou wo sagasu himawari ～♬
♬～ hanabi aogu sono yokogao ～♬
♬～ kiritotte mune ni shimatte ita ～♬
♬～ itsumademo bokura no mirai wa zutto ～♬
♬～ tsudzuiteku to omotteta ～♬
♬～ kono kanashimi mo sugiteku no kana ～♬
♬～ tomoni sugoshita natsu ga sotto ～♬
♬～ owari tsugeru you ni ～♬
♬～ ah anata dake wa kienai de ～♬
♬～ modoreru nara ano natsu e ～♬
"What happened in Izukyu Shimoda Station
at 20:20 (8:20pm) is not a misunderstanding."
Yano-sensei?
Oh, Maekawa-sensei..
I got these free tickets..
Would you want to go together?
"Barber"?
It looks interesting.
Yes, if you wouldn't mind..
Let's watch it together!
Looks good..
Really?
I like that one.
It looks nice.
Those are good photos, right?
You're right.
But, I really like this one.
I wish I could take a better photo.
Turns out, people can start falling in
love in such a very short time.
Although she only had a short life,
that girl was able to fall in love.
Love is probably good, right?
Oh, no!
I'll catch that one!
It starts drowning..
You can reach it!
A little further!
What are you doing?
"With a kiss, make her fall (in love)!"
Although I think,
this is not what it means.
We will give the original novel "The Girl Who Leapt Through Time" for 30 lucky people!
Check our homepage for the details!
Everyone, don't forget to participate!
Both of you wanna leap through time?
Yes!
Let's make a recital!
Transfer student?
No one told me about this.
You are not allowed fall in love
with someone from a different era!
You just have to do it.
The power of love will help you!
Please be my Juliet!
No matter how,
I want to be Romeo.
There are only three ingredients left!
Sorry for being such a bother.
Let's go!
See?
Let's do our best!