Go! Go! Go!
Until junior high,
I was in soccer club.
But during high school,
I decided to join the boat club.
Go!
Go! Go!
The last row!
The last defining moment.
The reason why I couldn't cry..
What was it?
Although this might sound like
a lie because I say it myself..
I do have lots of friends.
But no one knows..
..about how uncool I am.
Before I entered high school, my homeroom teacher at junior high suggested me to get into a private school.
My parents also said that
I could get into a private school.
But I decided to enter a public school instead.
This month's income.
- Thank you.
My parents thought that I did that
because I was worried about the tuition fee.
They're wrong.
Good morning!
You surprised me..
- Good morning!
I want to get in the same school as Mihane.
She is also the reason
why I joined the boat club.
But because she hurted her waist,
she quitted that boat club last year.
The reason why I couldn't cry
is probably because of her too.
I wonder since when
I started to like Mihane.
Goro, hold up her head.
Roger!
I even felt envy towards a scissor.
I want to be a scissor.
Scissor, he said?!
I was so envy with a scissor
that could cut Mihane's hair.
If I think about it now,
I sounded like a pervert!
Bye~ Bye~ Bee~
Although I already decided to confess
my feeling to her in the summer festival..
At the end, I failed.
You like Mihane, right?
Eh?!
Shohei even realized that I like Mihane.
I wonder if it's alright for two
people, to love the same person.
What's with that question?
As if he just declared a war.
Hey, are you kidding me?!
I would end up hating him
if he steals Mihane from me.
Oh, no!
It starts drowning..
What are you doing?
She looks cuter than usual.
Shohei is so stupid!
How dare he kissed me suddenly like that?!
Anyway, that is not the problem!
I really want to scold him..
But, I couldn't say it in front of
Goro-chan who didn't see it.
I was thinking to leap through time,
but I was too hesitated to do it.
However, it's my first kiss.
I could not pretend as if it never happened.
Because it can't be wiped out from my memory.
How could you easily sleep, huh?
He pisses me off!
Mihane didn't leap through time.
Then, she doesn't hate it?
Somehow, I like her more than before.
Okay..
Excuse me, I'm going in.
Hey, we're in the middle of a lesson!
Transfer student?
No one told me about this.
Let's continue!
What are you doing?
Senpai, you're the one who told me
to enjoy living in this era, didn't you?
Fukamachi.. Aihara..
If you have a question, raise your hand!
Okay~
Eh, I don't have any question though..
"Toki wo Kakeru Shoujo"
(The Girl who Leapt Through Time)
Episode 3
Eh? I thought Goro-chan
is the one who cuts my hair.
Who is Goro?
Don't say that..
He is our childhood friend, Asakura Goro.
The son of "Asakura" Barbershop's owner.
Don't play dumb!
You really don't know him?
Where did Shohei go?
Onee-chan..
- Eh? What? What is it?
Onee-chan!
- Nooo~
Don't sleep there, it's dinner time!
Tonight, we have grilled meat!
Mihane, it's steak!
Wow, thank you!
Looks delicious..
- Bon appetit!
There are only three ingredients left!
We will soon be able to go
back to the 22nd century, right?
Yes, we will.
Anyway, about the school..
What's so fun about it?
The lesson was a waste of time!
It's already written on the textbook, but
the teacher re-wrote it on the blackboard.
And then, he told us to write it on our notebook?!
I don't get it!
Because twelfth graders will have to face a final
exam soon, you guys do not have to do this.
But, what should we do?
For the school festival.
In your last school festival here,
is there something you want to do?
Well, all tenth and eleventh graders have
already done their best to prepare it.
But I think, participating in
such event is not bad for you.
It will be your memories.
How about a choir?
How about doing it to refresh your mind
after studying for final exams, Hase Tamotsu?
I have a cram school after this.
Tabuchi Mana, since you're from the dance club,
how about performing a "Para Para" dance?
We are busy excercising for
the national competition.
Anyway, what is a "Para Para" dance?
You don't know a "Para Para" dance?
Like this.
You don't know this dance?
- So lame..
So, our class won't do anything for the festival?
Our class' performance has started!
♪ I came to a morning audition ♪
♪ My hairstyle looks so OK ♪
What kind of dance is it?
Cool, isn't it? Amazing, right?!
All twelfth graders take it easy, but
the eleventh graders look so passionate.
They have a good solidarity.
That internet idol, Onishi-san..
I wonder if she is really popular.
She already has 200.000 followers.
200.000?!
This time, she will have a major debut.
That's why all her classmates are supporting her.
200.000?!
Atsumi~
- Atsumi~
Atsumi! Atsumi! Atsumi! Atsumi!
The first semester ends today.
Although your summer holiday will start tomorrow,
do not slack off and keep focused on your study.
Please, take responsibility of yourself!
Twelfth graders should be
ready to face the final exams.
They already announced that our
summer holiday will start tomorrow.
This doesn't feel like a summer holiday.
We should have done a class performance, right?
At the school festival?
- Yes.
Actually, I want to do it.
But it was hard to say it back then, right?
I also want to do it.
Eh, Goro-chan too?
We couldn't do such thing anymore,
since it's only done in youthful days.
Actually, I also want to do it!
Eh?!
Let's do that!
- Huh? It's too late to that.
Oh!
- That's what I mean!
Huh?
"That" thing!
Both of you wanna leap through time?
Yes!
It would be better if we decided to
do a class perfomance, so let's do it!
But, are you sure the other will agree?
You just have to persuade them,
we are going to help you!
Please..
- Please!
Please! Please! Please!
About the school festival..
What's happened?
Everyone, let's make a recital!
For our last school festival,
let's do it together!
Hey, Goro-chan.. Shohei..
Both of you, say something!
Why?
I hate doing a public performance.
You guys actually want to do it, right?
No, not at all.
What a traitor!
You're forcing us!
You said you're gonna help me!
You heard us saying it
few days from now, right?
But, it's the first time we heard it.
We have to persuade everyone to do it!
In such situation, there is no way
we could persuade them, right?
But Goro-chan, you're the one who
said that we can persuade them!
Did I say such thing?
- No, you didn't.
You said it, in the future!
Then he hasn't said it, yet.
Argh, this is not about
whether you said it or not!
It's because we are going to regret it
if we do nothing, do you understand?
Do you understand?!
I think, it will be a good memory for all of us.
So, we have to make it succeed!
To make it succeed,
I will do anything I can.
No one wants to do it?
We don't know what we are going to do,
so it's hard to answer your question.
About that, we haven't decided it yet.
How about performing a "Para Para" dance?
Like this.
We don't want to do unuseful things.
Eh?
Just like Hase said.
You really don't know a "Para Para" dance?
Let's do a "Para Para" dance!
Here..
Watermelon!
You like it?
No, I'm already beyond the level of "like".
Few days ago, I ate this for the first time.
Since then, I have become addicted to this.
Few days ago.. for the first time, huh?
Doing a choir or a dance would be hard because
there are some people who don't want to perform.
So, it would better be something
that needs some backstage jobs.
Ah~
Why you're the only one
who eat that watermelon?
You want it too?
- No, I don't!
I mean, you should also think something!
Cutting watermelons..
- Forget about the watermelon!
It's hard to ask someone to do
something that is not his interest.
If there is only few people who
enjoy it, wouldn't it feel too lonely?
Since we have the chance, I want us
to make a good memory together.
For me, I hate that "together" phrase.
Eh?
It's somewhat surprising.
In my school, only those who were
popular could enjoy such events.
So, I always thought that it's boring.
But looking at you guys now,
I start to regret it a little.
"How could we persuade those who don't
look interested to participate in that event?"
"How could we make them enjoy it?"
I think, they might also think about it.
Why don't you ask Yuri to participate?
"Yes, please!"
Do I look like a high schooler?!
It's impossible!
- Keita!
It must be hard for them..
There is not much time left until the festival, right?
It's not about the festival preparation.
I am talking about their love triangle.
Really?
Even Shohei?
Because Mihane-chan is so cute, right?
Let's make a drama!
Drama performance?
- It's the most tiring performance!
What is the title?
"Romeo and Juliet"
I get that you're worried about this.
But after we discussed a performance
that can be enjoyed by the whole class..
I think this is the best choice.
There will be some people who perform on the stage,
while the rest will prepare things at the backstage..
Such as making properties, costumes, or backgrounds.
I will make use of your specialities.
Is there anyone who don't want to do it?
Sorry!
No matter how, I want to be Romeo!
Sorry for being such a bother..
But please, spare my self-indulgence.
Please!
What are you doing, Goro-chan?
You're ruining my effort to persuade them!
If that's what you want, Asakura-kun..
Then, we have no other choice.
Eh?
- Indeed..
I'm going to have a competition soon,
so I don't know how far I can help.
It's okay, just do what you can.
Me too, I will do what I can!
Me too.
- Yosh, thank you!
Well then, the whole class will participate!
Okay~
- Yosh!
Why are you sulking?
Wouldn't it be faster if you persuade
them since the beginning, Goro-chan?!
Just look at how popular you are!
What a stupid fellow!
Are you angry.. or praising me?
I'm pissed off!
Ah, give up!
I give up.
Well..
Everyone becomes passionate, isn't it good?
Who wants to do these certain jobs?
Let me make the costumes!
- Costumes?
Then, me too!
How about the choreography?
- Well, I'm okay with that.
But, I will do it firmly!
Eh? Me?
In charge of properties?
Romeo will be potrayed by Goro-chan, right?
I think, Shohei would fit to be Laurence.
Eh?
- Nice idea!
I want to watch it!
- Sounds interesting..
It's okay, right?
- Me?
Yes.
Then, the one who will
potray Juliet's guardian is..
Me!
Sensei will be Juliet's guardian!
Is it okay if her guardian is a male?
- It's okay, we should add something new!
Sounds interesting!
- Indeed..
Okay then, Sensei will potray it.
Let's do it together!
Those who have not decided
any role, are Mihane and Aihara.
It's either potraying Juliet or in charge of
backgrounds, which one do you want?
Since it's my responsibility for choosing this
performance, I decided to accept anything left.
So, I leave it to Aihara-san.
Then, I will be Juliet.
- Huh?!
Sorry, forgive me..
Then it's decided, right?
Yeay, it's decided!
Is it okay for you to be
in charge of backgrounds?
Finally, thank you!
Juliet?
Why should you be Juliet?
*Wherefore art thou Juliet?*
Senpai, Romeo should be the one who say it!
It's not a dialogue!
I'm asking about your role!
Oh, my role?
You're really going to do it?
Because if I'm in charge of backgrounds,
I have to draw many things, right?
Right.
I hate being dirty, so it's impossible!
That's why you take the main role?
Better than being dirty.
Even so, you shouldn't be the main role!
Eh?
Where is Shohei?
I don't know.
Eh?
I'm going to look for him.
Give back the key.
Not there.
Oh, there he is!
Eh?
Where is Shohei?
He looks so busy.
- Eh?
Forget it, let's go!
Why are you angry?
Sorry, I'm a bit late..
Ah, they left without me.
I'm back!
- Welcome back!
We have a guest, looks like he wants
to talk to you about something.
Welcome back!
Eh?
Do you like Mihane-chan?
Well, yes.
Then, stop it!
Eh?
When were you born?
Why suddenly ask?
You're not from this era, right?
Me too.
I came from the future.
Go back to the future!
What are you doing in this era?
I lost the drugs, so I couldn't go back.
Huh? Stupid..
So, what are you planning to do?
I'm extracting some ingredients..
..and make the drugs from the scratch.
You're a researcher?
What are you doing here?
I'm now living with my family.
I decided to live in this era.
Forget about me, it's more important for you
to give up your feeling for Mihane-chan.
Why?
You are not allowed fall in love
with someone from a different era!
You have the courage to say that, huh?
Although you already
make your own family here.
I'm warning you, just stop it!
Juliet will be potrayed by Aihara.
Who is Aihara?
Why not Mihane-chan?
Mihane-chan should potray it!
- She should, right?
Can't you do something about it?
- No, of course I can't.
Why don't you ask her to be Juliet?
Right!
Welcome!
Good afternoon..
To this side?
- Oh, okay..
What do you think?
- Looks good.
Ouch, it hurts!
Which one?
- This.
It hurts, don't touch it!
Are you okay, Hase-kun?
Why did you kill my best friend?
You should move too!
Takeda, do it properly!
Juliet use this potion only
to make herself look like dying.
Actually, she wants to keep alive.
How pitiful..
How pitiful!
Five days left!
To which side?
- Ah, this side.
Oh, this side?
- 1.. 2..
Once more.
- Once more?
Then, to this side.
So hot!
Four days left!
Hey, wait a sec!
Excuse me.
Let's measure his shoulder width!
- His shoulder width is 51cm.
51cm.
- Not yet, hold still.
Can't you do it later?
- No, it should be now.
Three days left.
With this wing of love..
I will fly to the sky!
Okay~
Your soft lips couldn't call my name..
- Yeay, it's done!
Try it first!
Ah..
Argh, it's torn!
Sorry~
Romeo is not the only man
in the world, Juliet-sama!
Two days left!
A bit more, do your best!
One day left!
Would you want to dance with me?
Ah, sorry..
Okay, sorry..
Sorry!
Huh?
- Once more!
Just drink this potion, in two days..
This is too fragile.
Romeo.. Romeo..
Why should you be Romeo?
*It refers to "O.. Romeo, Romeo.. Wherefore art thou Romeo?" which basically
means the same, from Shakespeare's "Romeo and Juliet" (Act 2 Scene 2)*
Romeo!
Sounds bad..
- She can't express it properly!
Romeo~
What is it?
"Because you think that I already died."
Because you think that I already died.
Put the dagger on your chest!
- Are you kidding me?!
Put the dagger on your chest..
- No, it's not part of dialogue.
Good job!
Finally, tomorrow is the day.
Although there are few things
that still make us worried.
Eh, few things?
There are few things, huh?
Because there is someone who doesn't interested
for the festival, everything seems useless now.
Hey, I'm talking about you!
Although you're not good at it,
at least you should do it properly!
I'm doing it properly, though..
You don't seem like doing it!
I have to face a national competition soon,
so actually I shouldn't waste my time doing this.
If you want to have that role, do it properly!
Watching you slack off gives me headache!
Well, it's because we only
have a little time for rehearsals.
As a main role, she has to remember lots of lines.
Those properties you broke, fix it yourself!
Enough..
Since the beginning, I don't get why
I should be in charge of properties!
Hase-kun, do you want to be on stage?
I should be Juliet instead..
It will be more funny.
Indeed, it will.
- It will be interesting!
I quit.
Eh? Wait..
- Aihara!
I already did what I can!
I practiced it until I couldn't
sleep, and that was the result.
No matter how hard I try, everyone says
that I don't seem like doing it properly.
Although I don't have the capability to do it,
I asked to be the main role. I'm so sorry.
Aihara, Sensei will teach you!
That's why I confronted you
(after you asked to be Juliet).
What should we do?
- It's tomorrow, right?
Hase-kun!
You really want to be Juliet?
No, we have to perform it
tomorrow. It's too impossible!
If it's not "tomorrow",
you want to do it, right?
Huh?
Eh, what's wrong?
Let's go back to the day
when we decided the roles!
Eh?
- I couldn't explain it there.
Follow me!
- How could we follow you?
During the first time-leap, I brought a turtle with me
and I was be able to leap through time with that turtle.
But human and turtle are different, right?
Shut up, and close your eyes!
Focus your mind to the moment
when we decided the roles!
Eh, what's wrong?
- Is this real?
What was that?
It feels amazing!
Let's do it!
It's already decided,
but.. so sorry..
This is too sudden, but..
I think it will be more interesting
if Juliet is potrayed by male student.
I think so.
As expected from Hase-kun!
So, would you potray Juliet?
Eh, why me?
Hase-kun, you actually
want to be on stage, right?
No, I don't!
- For real?
What do you mean?!
I shouldn't do such thing..
I'm fine being in charge of properties!
It's different from what he said before!
Then, Shohei should be "Juliet"..
…or, it's "Julio".
Me?
Asakura-kun and Fukamachi-kun
will potray Romeo and Juliet...?
Sounds perverted..
What do you imagine?
Indeed, sounds interesting!
- Huh?!
Then, who will be Laurence?
Me.
Okay, the only one left is..
Aihara, would you want
to be in charge of backgrounds?
I have no choice, right?
I'll do it then, I will.
Yosh, let's do our best!
This is the best I can do.
Sorry..
So, you're not bad at drawing?
I just hate being dirty.
Ew, so dirty!
Thank you for making
such amazing background!
We are so grateful for this!
If you don't mind with this..
I'm so touched!
"God's Hand"
- Amazing!
"Lesson Five: Confess Your Love Boldly!"
It's impossible..
Shohei, it's dinner time!
Okay~
I tried to cook some watermelon-based meal.
Amazing!
Bon appetit!
Yummy~
- Glad to hear it!
Watermelon? Watermelon..
"Why should you be watermelon?"
*Wherefore art thou watermelon?*
Forbidden love?
Even if I have to let you go,
I would keep loving you.
It's the effect of "Romeo and Juliet", right?
Eh, is there such effect?
If you have to face an obstacle,
your feeling will grow bigger.
So, you should better face it.
The power of love will help you!
You're right.
If you drink this potion, in two days..
..you will look like dying.
As long as I can be with Romeo
by then, I will do anything.
So, you have prepared yourself?
Yes.
Your soft lips couldn't call my name anymore.
The only love of my life..
Their love will definitely be able
to pass though this obstacle.
You must have been waiting
for me in a place with no obstacle.
I will also go with you!
The moment I realized it..
It's already too late.
Put your faith in love..
..and take this love thoroughly.
Here comes the day!
OK!
- 1.. 2..
A bit to the left..
Now, we just have to enjoy this festival and
make sure we have a successful performance!
Class 3-6, let's do our best!
My name is Julio,
Rome is there!
Lady Julio..
It's time for a morning "Para Para" dance!
Let's be passionate, Lady Julio!
Why should you be Romeo?
*Wherefore art thou Romeo?*
My grandfather gave me this name.
My family are fans of "Giant".
The Yomiuri Giants are the oldest team among the current Japanese professional teams,
while Hanshin Tigers is a professional baseball team especially popular in the Kansai region.
But, your family are fans of "Hanshin".
The Tigers-Giants rivalry is considered the national Japanese rivalry, on par with the New York Yankees
vs. the Boston Red Sox in Major League Baseball or Real Madrid vs. FC Barcelona in Spanish football.
Please, could you stop
being a fan of "Hanshin"?
Asakura-kun, quick!
You girls are helping me to change
costumes? I thought the boys will do this.
Why should you...?
- Ah, this is embarassing!
Tell me why..
Why did you kill my best friend?
Do I need a reason?!
Hey, Tybalt!
- Romeo!
Cool!
This potion will put you in an apparent death.
If I drink that potion,
I will look like dying, right?
Right!
Just make sure you use it
with a proper dosage.
Thank you, Laurence!
I wish you luck.
It goes well until now.
- Let's hope the last act will go well too.
Julio!
Julio~
Why..
Why did you leave me?
Julio~
Oh.. that ball!
Really?
Is it just an act?
- Is he just pretending?
Mihane, what should we do?
Now, we have to help Goro-chan..
It looks bad!
This is bad..
He fainted!
Why is Romeo dead?
I won't forgive you for going there alone!
Sorry!
Sorry for making you guys worried.
Are you okay?
I thought I would die..
But, I'm okay!
I'm so sorry, everyone..
Glad to hear it.
Mihane, how is it?
Should we re-do it again?
Yes, right before the performance.
I will warn Goro-chan about that ball.
This time, we will definitely make it succeed!
Yosh..
Let's go back!
But, the moment Asakura-kun fainted..
His face looked weird, right?
And Shohei's last act, looked so cool.
It made everyone laugh so hard and
at the end, they gave us standing ovation.
When the drawing that Aihara-san made
with full of efforts, started broken..
Everyone saw it, right?
- Yes, we did.
It was all because my feet got stumbled.
I'm so sorry!
Thanks to you, our drama
could reach the climax.
What a cool response, Hase!
It's enough, right?
There is no need to re-do it.
Everyone smiles so brightly, right?
I have so much fun.
Right..
This is quite good.
The last school festival has finally come to
its end and everyone seems enjoying it.
I'm so happy!
Well then, for our miraculous failure..
Let's have a toast!
Yeay!
Here it is.
- Ah, thank you!
Ah, sorry..
Say "cheese"!
Amazing~
I'm glad to be involved in this muddy ship.
*he refers to their failed performance*
Youth without failure means nothing.
Even I can say something like that.
Muddy ship is the best!
Failure is.. good!
Failure is good!
Hase!
- Well done, Hase!
Keep it up!
It's good!
- Failure is good!
Failure is good!
OK!
So fun..
In this particular place,
I have something to say.
What is it?
Yoshiyama Mihane!
You, who always work hard..
..have made me fall in love.
Eh?
- Fall in love?
Fall in love?
- Really?
I love you!
Eh, what is this?
Would you be..
..my Juliet?
"Ah, I wish you wouldn't disappear.."
"..if one day, I could go back to that summer."
"While looking up to the blue sky.."
"I would stretch out my arms, although it probably means nothing."
"I don't even care about the destination."
"Because it wouldn't be a place that can reach the sky, right?"
"The scent that flutters through out that summer.."
"The sunflowers that keep facing towards the sun.."
"The side of your face staring at the fireworks.."
"Those things have managed to cut through my heart."
"I had always thought that our future.."
"..would be going to continue forever."
"I wonder if this sadness would also disappear someday."
"Just like the summer we had spent together.."
"..when it finally came to its end."
"Ah, I wish you wouldn't disappear.."
"..and take me back to the middle of that summer."
"Just like how we fell in love that day.."
"I want to embrace you tightly."
"Ah, I wish you would never leave.."
♬～ 嗚呼　あなただけは消えないで ～♬
♬～ 戻れるなら　あの夏へ ~♬
♬～ 青空を　見上げる僕は ～♬
♬～ 手を伸ばす　意味を知らない ～♬
♬～ 行き先なんて　どこでもいいさ ～♬
♬～ 空には届かないだろ ～♬
♬～ 夏が舞う　そんな匂いと ～♬
♬～ 太陽をさがす向日葵 ～♬
♬～ 花火　仰ぐ　その横顔 ～♬
♬～ 切り取って胸にしまっていた ～♬
♬～ いつまでも僕らの未来はずっと ～♬
♬～ 続いてくと思ってた ～♬
♬～ この悲しみも過ぎてくのかな ～♬
♬～ 共に過ごした夏がそっと ～♬
♬～ 終わり告げるように ～♬
♬～ 嗚呼　あなただけは消えないで ～♬
♬～ 夏の中へつれてって ~♬
♬～ 恋をした　あの日のまま ~♬
♬～ 抱き合えたら ~♬
♬～ 嗚呼　行かないでと願うだけで ~♬
♬～ ah anata dake wa kienai de ～♬
♬～ modoreru nara ano natsu e ～♬
♬～ aozora wo miageru boku wa ～♬
♬～ te wo nobasu imi wo shiranai ～♬
♬～ yukisaki nante doko demo ii sa ～♬
♬～ sora ni wa todokanai daro ～♬
♬～ natsu ga mau sonna nioi to ～♬
♬～ taiyou wo sagasu himawari ～♬
♬～ hanabi aogu sono yokogao ～♬
♬～ kiritotte mune ni shimatte ita ～♬
♬～ itsumademo bokura no mirai wa zutto ～♬
♬～ tsudzuiteku to omotteta ～♬
♬～ kono kanashimi mo sugiteku no kana ～♬
♬～ tomoni sugoshita natsu ga sotto ～♬
♬～ owari tsugeru you ni ～♬
♬～ ah anata dake wa kienai de ～♬
♬～ natsu no naka e tsurete tte ～♬
♬～ koi wo shita ano hi no mama ～♬
♬～ dakiaetara ～♬
♬～ ah  ikanaide to negau dake de ～♬
Juliet!
Juliet! Juliet! Juliet!
Juli..
Julie..
Juliet!
Kiss her!
Kiss her! Kiss her!
- Huh?
- You guys are so noisy!
Kiss her!
I really like Mr.Yano's acting.
I'm talking about the radish!
I really like radish in Oden.
Oden is the quintessential Japanese comfort food. It is a kind of hot pot or stew consisting
mainly of daikon radish, konnyaku, and fish cakes stewed in a light soy flavored dashi broth.
Oh, really?
- Exactly!
If you don't mind, next time..
Would you mind teaching me how to act?
Okay? Please..
- I need more beer!
Please, teach me a little!
- Miura-san?
Just for a while,
are you embarassed?
Miura-san!
Miura-san, are you okay?
- Miura-san!
Call an ambulance!
- Okay!
Miura-san, Miura-san.
Hey, Miura-san!
Hang in there, Miura-san!
Eh?
There is no Shohei in these pictures.
Why?
There is no Shohei..
I'm so happy to hear your confession.
If she finds out the truth about me,
will this love come to its end?
Why don't you have any childhood photo?
Eh? Run away?
Is it wrong to live as I like?!
Goro-chan..
- Goro!
I really love Mihane-chan!