[The guys are changing.]
[Please knock before entering.]
Wow. That's not gonna look good.
Quit touching me. Ow!
What should I do? My gym clothes are inside.
Hey! Wait!
The boys are changing.
I don't know what to do... P.E. is about to start...
Huh? What... W-wait!
Huh? Why? Why did she...
Maybe there isn't anything Kyuuto dislikes...
...nothing that makes her hesitate...
...nothing so embarrassing that it makes her cry out without realizing it...
...nothing she wishes could be undone but can't be...
Tenka toru!
[Be victorious]
- Seriously?
- We're gonna do that?
As you all already know...
...this is a ritual for luck in tests dating back to when this was an all boys school.
We're doing this the night before the festival?
- Why's it only guys?
- That's not fair.
Last year, Horiuchi-kun, who was top of his class...
...said this was stupid and refused to participate.
And what happened to him?
On the day of his entrance exams he had the flu. Everything he'd worked for, up in smoke.
So... that's how it goes. Everyone, let's take this seriously.
- Hey... Who had the nicest body?
- Kageyama.
I saw him as the childish type.
But you know, he's pretty ripped...
Listen to you! He's well muscled, but still slender...
Now, now, everyone. Everything will be revealed the night before the festival. There's no need to get ahead of ourselves.
Only Heita.
What? Fukai?
Only Heita had a mark.
I hate the Culture Festival.
Last year, I used my illness as an excuse and stayed home from the festival.
And the year before that...
No... It's... It's not like that.
Yay! You having fun?
- Seriously, he's horrible.
- Just mean.
[Yaki-soba]
The Culture Festival makes me remember things that I can usually forget.
They say you will never feel the same wind blow twice...
...there are some things you can never undo...
That empty, helpless feeling...
That's right. You always have hated them, haven't you...
...stuff like fireworks, and long novels...
Well, you feel sad when they're over, right?
So, what're you going to do about this year's festival?
Maybe I'll stay home this year too...
The whole... "be victorious" thing too?
You think that thing really helps you pass?
- Well, no, but...
- Oh yeah... on the day before the festival...
...maybe I'll stay here overnight. Can I?
By "here" you mean here?
Let's have our own "festival eve" party.
What?
I'll say cool stuff like, "are you depressed or something?"...
I'll borrow that bed.
Then you might be able to see the "Night Nurse."
What? A "Night Nurse"?
At 8 pm, a nurse comes, a woman.
She always says, "I'm the Night Nurse!"
"Night Nurse"... What's that mean, huh? Now it's gonna bother me...
I don't know what it means. She's the one that says it!
She says, "I'm the Night Nurse"? What's she look like?
The same wind never blows twice...
Even though I'm not in love with Shibata Kyouko anymore, don't even think about her...
...every time I see her, my breath catches in my throat.
Even if I want to take it back...
...I remember that there are some things you can never get back...
...the hopelessness of that hurts.
This feeling is something...
...Kyuuto probably doesn't understand.
[Kyuuto]
Episode 3
translation by sarujin
QC by sayochama
GIRIGIRI FANSUBS
NOT FOR SALE OR RENT
About the representative for the "Miss" Contest, will anyone nominate themselves?
Anyone?
No way. All you'd get is embarrassed, right?
And Class-C's Shibata Kyouko's gonna win anyway, right?
And Shibata Kyouko's super serious about it, right?
Apparently she's already bought clothes for the contest even though she hasn't been chosen as the rep yet.
That's right. If you get picked, you'd have to buy new clothes too, huh?
No need to worry. It'll never happen for you.
Isn't there anyone?
You have to perform too, right?
If you're talking about cute, in our class that'd be...
...Kawai-san?
That's just a pun!
Yeah, why don't we let our class rep do it?
That's enough with the jokes already!
No, really, no joke, have the class rep do it, right?
That's right. We have to study for exams...
Excuse me...
...I have to study too, though...
That's why. This is a chance for you to take a little break, Kawai-san...
All who think Kawai should do it...
Here...
Then, it's decided.
Turn yourself this way a little more...
Perfect!
And, smile.
Good.
I didn't think you'd raise your hand too, Kageyama-kun.
Huh? What are you talking about?
The rep for the Miss Contest.
Well... I mean... because you're cute, Kawai-san...
I didn't think you'd make fun of me like that.
Huh? What do you mean?
You really are pretty!
I really do think that...
Fukai-kun.
I was chosen to be the rep for the Miss Contest.
Oh.
If I...
...if I win...
Sorry...
It's nothing.
"Will you go out with me?" Is what she probably wanted to say, right?
"I've been waiting a long time."
I'm Fujino.
Fujino Tsukiko.
- Oh. The shut-in...
- You've heard of me.
Where's 3rd Year, Class-B?
You know... Classes are already over...
That's okay. I like it better when there's no people.
Otherwise my energy gets sapped.
Huh?
Mark?
On Fukai's chest?
It's a scar from his surgery.
- Surgery?
- Yeah.
Oh! That's it!
So that's why...
That's it! That Fukai was saying he wasn't coming to the Festival...
I mean, there's that "be victorious" thing, right?
I guess you wouldn't know.
I see. He didn't want people to see the scar on his chest...
Honestly. He was worried about something like that?
Is having a scar really that bad?
I think it's pretty cool...
Amazing...
...it's stifling in here...
A place like this is impossible for me...
Hey! Fujioka!
Nishi-senpai?
You're looking good.
I've got this friend. He's thought up an amazing plan...
A plan?
Even without doing a thing...
...money just comes rolling in.
I see.
Wanna join us?
Oh! No!
Think it over.
What's with him?
What's this? It's all for Festival Eve?
- Isn't that too much?
- Well, we're staying up all night, right?
What happened? How'd you get this?
It is happening to Nakao-kun too, right now.
What?
Nakao... Nakao!
Fukai...
You!
Ow! Ow, ow...
So...
In short, all of this...
...is special effects make-up?
The eye?
Since we were doing it anyway, I thought...
...we'd do it to my taste.
I thought you might not do the "Victory in Exams Invocation" because you didn't want people to see your scar...
If you failed your entrance exams because of that...
...I thought that's something you can't take back, so...
Then I thought I should just make scars that stand out more than yours...
Why would you go this far for me? ...going out of your way to make scars and stuff.
You came running to help me because you thought I was in trouble, right?
Even though you shouldn't be running...
I'm really exhausted...
It seems like...
...there's this feeling like I have to be in that "Victory in Exams Invocation," you know?
Yeah... But after I'm done for the day, I'll come back.
I've got to see that "Night Nurse," right?
Nakao's a good guy, huh?
Yeah.
Later.
Bang.
Let's go.
It's a charm to ward off evil.
If anything more happens I'm going to have to take some time off of school.
Is it all right to dispose of money?
That's not throwing it away.
It's an offering.
Fujioka-kun disposed of some too.
Really? He made a wish at a shrine too?
30,000 yen.
30,000 yen?
So... you can do things like this too...
I've got this friend...
He's thought up this amazing plan...
A plan?
- What?
- Even without doing a thing...
...money comes rolling in.
This is bad! That job's gotta be something dangerous!
What do I do...
Think it over.
What are we gonna do, Fujioka?
We will tell him not to do it.
Well... Well, yes, but...
I can't just say, "don't do it."
It's not like we can take care of Fujioka's living expenses.
If he had money, this would end without Fujioka having to do dangerous work?
Well... For now anyway...
30,000, huh?
What?
We will have everyone dispose of their money here, for Fukioka's sake.
"Everyone," who?
The people I meet starting now. Everyone.
Please dispose of some.
Huh? Me too?
I guess I just really can't... I'll make sure to return the money.
What? You used it all already?
You're pretty careless with your money, huh?
You've got a little brother, right?
What're you gonna do?
Guess there's no helping it, huh?
Think it over carefully, one more time.
That comes to 440 yen.
A friend is poking his nose into dangerous business.
Please, dispose of your money.
Money?
Do you think you could lend me some?
I can't really ask mom...
- Another idol?
- No.
Clothes.
Clothes?
Are you stupid?
Clothes aren't important enough to borrow money for.
I was chosen as the representative.
Representative?
From my class, for the Miss Contest.
What?
Someone as ugly as you would never be in a "Miss" Contest.
I really was chosen.
Then they're just harassing you.
They make the ugly girl feel good, then laugh at her.
You get excited, even go so far as to buy clothes...
How stupid are you?
Don't even think about entering that thing.
You should enter.
Yamamoto-san...
No... It's true, so...
What is?
Someone like me... It's only because I work so hard at studying that people treat me like one of them...
Just like my older brother said, I'm ugly, so...
It could be that this "brother" of yours is wrong.
Kawai-san, you're beautiful.
No, I can't be...
There's no way that can be true.
I see...
So, you won't believe what I say...
It's not like that!
Yamamoto-san...
...it isn't that I don't trust you.
I want to believe.
...but I can't.
Because, I'm...
Kawai-san...
You've come all this way...
...without saying wrong things are wrong, haven't you?
If you don't say, "that's wrong"...
...the "wrong" things become the truth.
Unless you say it as loud as you can...
After all, no one else will say it for you.
Say it. Scream it.
Say, "I am beautiful."
Who cares if people make fun of you?
- Get out of my way!
- What's with her?
Say, "it isn't true," as loud as you can.
A friend has poked his nose into dangerous business.
Please, save him.
Thank you very much.
I'll just keep on screaming...
I don't have love. I don't have money.
I'm just a proud ne'er-do-well
Here.
They're beautiful.
You're sure you don't mind?
I'm sure. I'm not gonna wear them again.
Thank you.
I am not ugly.
I am not ugly!
- Kyuuto?
- Yes.
She just got back... tattered and worn-out.
Worn-out?
She was serious...
Shikahamabashi High School is about to begin the Festival Eve events.
All senior boys, please begin preparations for the "Victory in Exams Invocation."
I been tellin' you! The way you talk's weird!
Say it proper. Proper. Got it?
Go on.
Your money...
Are you okay, Miss?
Are you okay, Miss... Ow, hot!
Hot... Hot!
Shall I bring in some ice? Miss...
Are you okay?
But... What if she's actually...
...a crane or something...
Sensei, may I borrow the yellow paint?
Please, go ahead.
Hello. Please excuse me for intruding.
- Hello.
- What're you here for?
What do you mean? You said you'd be late, so I brought some ohagi...
- Thank you so much!
- Why'd you bring ohagi?
- I am his mother...
- Okay. I get it! Thank you. Let's go home, okay?
You're not leaving yet?
Haven't you had enough already?
Back then... it was because of you we didn't make it to Koshien, right?
That again? I've heard it enough already...
To make a mistake like that at such an important moment...
I was so incredibly embarrassed...
...I didn't think I could live, but...
...it was unexpectedly easy to keep living, don't you think?
For both me and you.
I guess so.
What do I do? It's impossible now. Impossible...
The dress I borrowed was put in the wash...
It must mean... that I shouldn't be in it.
Right? I mean...
...it isn't as if anyone will be put out if I don't enter.
I...
I'll go tell them I'm not participating.
I'll do something about the clothes... okay?
It's just like my brother said.
It was wrong of me to enter at all.
No matter what you may say, Yamamoto-san...
...I...am ugly.
Are you going to believe your brother?
Or are you going to believe in yourself?
Who are you going to live your life believing in?
I want to believe in myself...
- I just push here?
- That's right.
How simple!
It'd be nice if people were that simple too...
What?
Well...
...words don't get through... and I can't give a hug...
What should I do at a time like that?
All that's left...
...is passion.
You see... Right here, you can feel this heat simmering, and soon...
...pop! The lid will come flying off.
And it will land, clink, with the person you're trying to reach.
It'll hit its target that easily?
Don't think about aiming, just hope for its flying.
Like this... Pop!
Be victorious!
Has it started?
Nishi?
Hey, you're looking good!
The school is doing the same old ridiculous stuff I see.
I suppose so.
That's right! I have to give them back, don't I?
Come on. Come on.
Here you are.
I don't need this stuff after all this time...
What are you talking about?
Here. This one too.
You know... This was the one thing...
...you always tried your hardest in.
Be victorious.
Be victorious!
There she is! I found her!
- Kawai-san, you have to come!
- This way! Come on!
Okay. Here we are.
Kawai is beautiful!
I'm so jealous!
He's risking his entrance exams to say that. Lift your head and listen to it, for him.
Kawai is beautiful!
Oh. That's right.
Will you give this back to Kageyama-kun for me?
Kawai is beautiful!
- The Miss Contest is about to start!
- Seriously? Better get moving!
Huh?
Don't tell me... it reached her?
I was chosen to be the rep for the Miss Contest.
You're leaving without watching the Miss Contest?
I promised someone else, so...
Watch, for her.
It's not like anything will change if I watch.
You think so?
Even though this moment will only happen this once...
This is...
...uniforms from other schools?
We'll accessorize and coordinate, and create a one-of-a-kind uniform.
[Sorry. Looks like I'm gonna be a little longer.]
Thank you very much.
Next up, from class 3-B, Kawai Emiko-san.
Here she is!
Let's go.
- Amazing...
- We've been waiting!
I am Kawai, from 3rd year, class B.
I'll be singing, "The Wind."
Every single person...
...sets out on their journey alone.
...looks back at the home they've left.
Feeling just a little bit lonely...
...even if you turn and look back...
...all that will be there is the wind blowing.
Every single person...
...stumbles in their lives.
Every single person, has their dream crushed...
...and turns to look back.
Dry sycamore leaves dance...
...on this winter road.
At the sound of the sycamore leaves falling...
...I turn and look back.
Even if I hear "please, come home," and turn back...
All that there will be is the wind...
That day... If I had just smiled and said, "it's fine," after you shook me off your arm...
...do you think we'd still be together, even now?
If I won the Miss Contest...
...I thought I might be able to get that back.
"Of course we can get it back"...
...will you say that for me?
...even if it's a lie...
If we started dating again...
...would that mean that we'd gone back and fixed things?
I know that's not what it would be.
And you know...
...that it wouldn't be. Right?
"Getting something back"...
...probably means...
...being able to move on to the next thing.
Shibata Kyouko-san...
Stand-by, please.
Okay.
Shake my hand off...
...and go.
Go, and we'll take back everything. Okay?
Now...
...we're even.
Yeah.
Please, look out for my son.
- Huh? You're leaving already?
- I have somewhere to go...
Oh! I have one of these too.
Hm?
Chiro!
What's wrong? Chiro?
Chiro licked that amulet, and now...
- That's because it wards against evil spirits!
- What do you mean?
If anything other than a human touches it...
...they say that whatever it is will suddenly vanish from this world, taken out like garbage.
- Anything that isn't human?
- Well, Chiro-chan is an animal, so...
Chiro-chan!
What? You mean you mean nothing not human should touch it?
What should I do? I gave one to Kyuuto!
What? Kyuu-chan?
It's really that effective?
It's extraordinarily effective.
A lightning bolt struck.
It couldn't be...
...not on Kyuuto...
Come on now, get back. Stand back, I said.
Kyuuto...
- Kyuuto!
- Get back!
Calm down! There's no one in there. That's just a machine!
Kyuuto! Kyuuto...
Kyuuto!
Kyuuto.
Don't move.
Are you okay?
Give me a break...
Excuse me.
I'll be looking after you tonight. My name is Kagawa. Pleased to meet you.
What? I mean... Um...
Where's the "I'm the Night Nurse" person?
Oh. Kanai-san. Didn't you hear? She got married.
She's probably in Italy right now. I'm so jealous.
We're home!
Honestly, Tou-san...
This is how he gets when we leave him alone...
If you sleep there, you'll catch a cold.
Welcome home.
The crane...
Where's the crane?
What are you talking about?
There was a crane here!
- A robotic Crane Wife.
- You drank too much.
No! She... She was in that room!
She had her wings spread, like this, but they were mechanical.
What are you saying?
No! Stop!
There's nothing there.
Huh?
You're kidding...
Excuse me a sec...
She... She was right here.
The machine was flashing...
You were dreaming.
I was?
You drank too much.
Are you okay?
Fujioka!
Kyuuto collected this for you.
She said it's so you won't get involved in anything dangerous.
Sorry. We overheard you and Senpai talking.
Loose change like this... isn't going to change anything.
That might be true, but...
Look...
I've told you this has nothing to do with you.
That's right.
It's not my problem.
But I don't like it when people crush other people.
You don't like it either, right?
Standing by silently... watching someone get crushed.
You hate it, right?
Nishi-senpai...
...wouldn't do that to me.
Seriously, what is this?
You really are an idiot, aren't you...
The money you tossed...
...I was the one who picked it up.
That's right.
It's just like he said.
I was going to crush you under my heel.
Being made to carry all this junk...
...lies just can't make it through this stuff.
Are you okay?
Kubo-kun? Sorry to keep you waiting.
Who's there?
Fukai-kun asked me to come play games all night in his place.
Which do you want to settle first?
Heita hates endings.
Really...
And because he's afraid of endings...
...he's not good at starting things.
Well, you can't live that way, can you?
Humans die, 100%...
Everyone... Oh!
Everyone knows that. That's why you live.
Tell Heita that.
Did I die? Here... Did I die?
Yes. You died perfectly.
Oh no, no, no. Bring me back to life.
I ended up spending the whole time at school...
I'm sorry! Are you okay? You aren't hurt?
I'm okay.
Where on earth did she learn that?
Guys! Quit goofing off!
[You can still take it back. Hang in there!]
[Come back...]
[There's no such thing as too late. Please, don't give up.]
[Just a little more! Keep trying!]
The same wind...
...will never blow twice.
And in the midst of that...
...we live.
That's right. Screaming and crying.
That's the first time I'd seen something like that.
It kinda creeped me out, but...
...somehow, it was moving.
[Heita]
I had a dream.
Kyuuto was human...
...and I was a robot.
When I asked, sobbing, why I wasn't a human...
...Kyuuto came to my side and said this...
"Being human or not..."
"...that stuff doesn't matter."
"Right now, you and I, Heita, we're becoming human."
"Being worried for by others..."
"...worrying about others... We can do that."
"We are becoming people that others can love."
"Isn't that enough?"
Kyuuto's words were so kind...
...even in my dream, I sobbed uncontrollably.
[Kaidan no katasumi ni...]
In a corner, on the stairs...
[...suwari uzukumaru no ano hito ni...]
...that person cowering, crouched...
[...nani ga atta n darou]
...I wonder what happened.
[Ittai nani wo mitekita n darou]
What did that person see?
[Hitogomi no naka de...]
In a crowd of people...
[...niramiau danjou no aida ni...]
...that man and woman glare at each other...
[...nani ga okottarou]
...I wonder what happened between them.
[Ittai donna jijou ga atta n darou]
What circumstances led them there?
[Itsuka boku wo yobidashita...]
Once, you called me outside...
[...sensei ga donatteta sono scene ha...]
...and the teacher yelled. That scene...
[...donna dattarou]
...I wonder what it looked like.
[Ittai boku ha nani wo shitta n darou]
What on earth did I learn from it?
[Itsu kara ka tsuzuiteru...]
On the other side...
[...sensou no hate ni donna koto ga...]
...of this war that's lasted since who knows when...
[...matteru n darou]
...I wonder what waits for us.
[Soushite boku ni nani ga dekiru n darou]
And what can I do?
[Koto no shinsou ha nani mo...]
The truth of things...
[...shitteiru you de shirienai...]
...we feel like we know, but we can't learn...
[Sore demo dou ni ka kou ni ka...]
Even so, somehow or another...
[...ikiteita naka ga nai]
...It's like we were never here.
[Muda ga atteba tarirarenai]
It's not enough to meet with futility...
[Demo shinjirareru mono mo sukunai]
But there are too few things to believe in...
[Tada hitotsu tashika na no ha boku no kimochi]
The only certain thing is my feelings...
[Kimi no sono koe wo kikashite yo]
Let me hear that voice of yours
[Shinjireru mono ga soko ni aru yo]
That's where I find something to believe in
[Tada hitotsu tashika na no ha omae to no toki]
The only certain thing is my time with you...
[Kimi ga suki]
I love you.
This world is made up of stuff that doesn't matter and stuff you can't do anything about.
He is a man who has no mercy for others.
It has to be you, Sensei!
There's no such thing as "forever" in this world.
Everything ends, one day.
I knew it. She isn't human.
If you let go, it's all over.
I want to say the things that I think, but...
...it'll put the people I'm talking to in a bind too, so...
O-Tentou-sama is always with you, but...
...without effort, not a single grain of rice shall grow