Take, for example...
...a person on this earth...
...who is more important to you than yourself...
Does a person like that truly exist?
Take, for example...
...something that seems like it should change my life...
- Please read this.
- I will!
...giving a confession of love like the ones I've seen on TV...
...wearing clothes I found in a magazine...
...going on a date at a place everyone lines up to get into...
...kissing someone in a scene just like a movie...
In the dead of night, I ask myself over and over...
..."it would have been good even if it wasn't me, right?"
"It would have been good..."
"...even if it wasn't you, right?"
"The guy next to me would've done just as well, right?"
"Was there any reason..."
"...it had to be the two of us in the first place?"
It can begin at any time...
...and end at any time.
She's dead, isn't she?
Something that disposable...
...is that really love?
It isn't sold anywhere...
...and it doesn't have a name.
Falling in love with someone like that...
...is that some...
...incredible miracle?
Who threw a person away?
People aren't garbage, you moron!
I hate this. I really hate it.
I hate the way the world is.
Take, for example...
...a person on this planet...
...who is more important to you than yourself...
Does a person like that truly exist?
Here you are. This, right?
Hm?
Well, I'm off.
- Okay. Stay safe.
- Your bag.
Thanks. Bye.
Have a good day.
Hello? Principal?
Sensei? How did it go yesterday with the girl I introduced you to?
Was a Doctor of Engineering a little too much for you?
She really has no luck with men, you know.
She says she's shy.
Well... I was thinking that she isn't the kind of woman I would be able to get along with...
No, no. Now...
...if you just try going out with her once...
Huh? What?
Hello? Principal?
Oh. Thank you for yesterday.
Science lab...
I... class... just attendance...
Science prep room!
[Science Preparation Room]
Sensei?
I...
...I'm finished.
Yes. Beautiful.
Beautiful.
Looks good, I think.
Fukai-kun...
...you said you'd have the surgery if I let you touch my teeth, right?
Well...
Why did you say that?
Who cares? That was so long ago...
But it was "teeth." Who says that, normally? "Can I touch your teeth?"
Well...
...I must've felt like they might make music.
Music?
Teeth look sort of like the keys of a piano, so...
...I wonder, "which note would come from this person?"
Don't pull back so far! This was when I was a kid.
I see...
The truth is...
...even now, sometimes...
...just every once in a while...
...there are times...
...that I think, "maybe music would come from this person."
Of course...
...I know no music will come out, so...
...I don't touch people's teeth.
Doing something like that is...
...the lowest sort of thing you can do as a human.
And anyway...
...there's no way any musical notes will come out.
Wanting to...
...make sure of that...
...is completely foolish...
No way!
No. I was just...
Please give me a name.
What?
Please give me a name... within 20 seconds of activation.
Give you...a name? Me?
5...seconds left.
- 4... 3...
- No. Wait! Hang on!
- 2... 1...
- Q...
Kyuuto
(Q10)
My name...
...is... Kyuuto.
Yes.
What is your name?
Fukai Heita.
It was the note "la."
Fukai Heita...
...has been authenticated.
I'd met a girl...
...who sounded the note "la."
Q10
[Kyuuto]
Episode 1
translation by sarujin
QC by sayochama
GIRIGIRI FANSUBS
NOT FOR SALE OR RENT
A robot?
What? She looks like a human though...
I told you, she's a humanoid robot.
- What?
- A robot in the shape of a human.
- So that means, it'll move?
- If you flip the switch.
But... A robot?
We'll put it back...before this gets any bigger...
Principal.
It's moving.
Someone's flipped the switch!
- Close it! Hurry, close it!
- What? What's going on?
- Huh? You're being chased by a girl?
- Close that! Close it! Close it!
What? What do you want?
What do you want?
No, no! No!
Wait... Who? Who is that?
Who is she? Who?
- Who?
- I don't know!
[Principal's Office]
So...
...what did you touch?
- Well... I just...
- You touched something, didn't you?
Well... yes.
So where was it?
Where?
You touched somewhere you can't say, huh?
Who are you?
I...
It spoke.
...belong to Fukai Heita.
- No, no, no...
- Hey! What's the meaning of this?
I don't know! Kyuuto is just saying that...
- Kyuuto?
- It's her name.
How do you know that name?
There was this countdown, and I freaked out...
...I had no choice...
Kyuuto...
...is sleepy.
Huh? What?
Wait! Hey!
What?
Honestly... What?
Out of energy, huh?
Speaking of... I have no idea what kind of energy it runs on...
What?
This is not human strength...
Well...it is a robot.
Robot?
She's a robot?
What... What? What is it?
This is...
What?
What is it? Hey! Hello?
It really was a robot...
Yes. It is indeed.
What a gallant little thing, isn't it? Though I don't quite understand it...
It's dutifully running along, isn't it?
What?
A robot?
Do you suppose... we've all seen something we shouldn't have?
Maybe we should call the police after all...
The police, yes... We've learned too much of this secret...
If the owner is from some underworld organization... I wonder if they'd just let us go...
Underworld organization?
A plug converter...
So it runs on electricity...
We might get it working.
What should we do?
Well, if we tell the police that I picked up a girl...
...do you think they'd tell my wife?
Well... It probably wouldn't be just your wife.
It would be in papers and things?
Weekly magazines, talk shows, network news...
There it is.
Okay.
Excuse me!
How much longer do I have to stay like this?
How would I know something like that?
What?
You've gotta be kidding me...
- Nishimura-kun.
- Here.
Fukai-kun.
Fukai-kun isn't here?
He disappeared with a girl and hasn't come back!
Quiet down. Quiet down!
- Okay! Fukushima-san...
- Here.
- Miyazawa-kun.
- Morinaga-kun.
- Here.
- Yamamoto-san.
I wonder what's going to happen to me...
[Fujioka Makoto]
He just...
What?
Nothing. Just...
How did this happen?
I don't know.
I don't know anything at all.
Who did that to my chair?
Haven't a clue...
You must have seen the person's face, right?
Well...
...I don't...think I did.
Huh? Wait! What? Wait! What's going on?
Kyuuto... is awake.
That's great.
This robot is a secret between the four of us, so...
...let's put it in the school and watch it for a while.
Does "4 of us" mean you're including me?
We've decided to put it in your class. You'll look after it, won't you?
- Me? Why?
- You've got it good.
I have to take it home.
What is this?
A ball.
Ball.
Shouldn't we take it to the police?
We could... but then we'd have to tell the police that you'd touched a girl's molars...
Is that all right?
How did you know that...
She told us.
Are you okay with that? Your parents will find out you're a pervert...
That's so embarrassing. I'd bite my tongue and die first.
And it wouldn't just be your parents... it'll be all over network news. You watch.
This is the roof.
The roof.
It must be a learning-type robot.
It's like it's just been born, so... Hey, you!
Teach it lots, okay?
Why do I have to do all this work? This has nothing to do with me.
Can't be helped, can it?
You're the one who woke her, after all.
Then... shouldn't we just push the reset button?
There must be one, right? She's a machine.
Then... All of us can just pretend we never saw anything. Right?
Once we've flipped the switch... there's no going back to the way things were.
Okay?
What?
I only promised to look after you...
...until classes are over for the day. Got it?
Leave that alone. It's just someone's scribbles...
Scribbles.
That's right.
See you.
What is that?
Look. My time with you is done.
What?
What is it?
The city?
City.
So look... Okay? That big one is the supermarket...
...then there's the steel tower...
...and that's the shopping district with the greengrocer that a perverted old man runs...
...and over there is the coffee shop with the really good egg-salad sandwiches, London...
...there's also this really dingy zori shop...
Anyway... all of this is the city.
All of this is...
...the city.
That's right.
It's our city.
It's our...
...city.
Whoa! What are you looking at?
You saw, didn't you...
No.
- You did, didn't you?
- What?
- Don't tell anyone!
- All I saw was a video of Kawai...
I'm saying... Don't tell anyone that...
What? What? You...
You're in love with Kawai?
- I'm telling you not to tell anyone...
- I see. You've been going out.
Going out with Kawai would completely destroy my image.
You're not... It's not like you can do anything threatening, right?
Don't tell anyone!
There's no door...
Why? Why isn't there a front door?
[Until you pay your rent, we have confiscated your front door. - The Management]
That greedy little landlord...
Oh my!
Someone save me!
What have you done?
When someone calls for help...
A robot. She's a robot?
The principal found it...
A robot?
If you wanted to buy it... it'd take at least a hundred million yen.
For the robot?
Well... It can talk...and walk...
Even though it's a robot...
That's right.
Did you change the light bulb?
Hm? No.
Oh. I get it.
Even in this house... with a young lady here, the whole place gets brighter, right?
Even if she's a robot...
Maybe...
...I'll get married.
To a robot?
To a human.
Oh. I'm taking a bath now.
Why are you telling me every little thing?
It's been a long time since I saw the scar from Heita's surgery.
I wonder if he's really going to have it his whole life...
What are you looking at?
Heita's pet fish.
Mom killed them.
What?
They looked sort of dirty, so I cleaned them.
Then, it turns out, I used boiling water...
What? Of course they died.
That's why she bought new ones, so he wouldn't notice.
But... They look completely different.
Now that you mention it, weren't they striped?
He'll definitely notice. I'm not responsible.
What do I do?
It'll be fine! Once they're mixed in...
What?
See! You can't tell.
See?
It's completely obvious.
Oh! Hey! H-how was the h-hospital?
Hm?
The same as always.
Did they say you've gotten better?
Yeah. They said there's no need to worry.
Oh. But... How was the hospital?
I said... it was the same as always.
Honestly...
Did you notice the fish tank?
Of course I did.
They look completely different.
Why didn't you say anything?
They're dead anyway, right?
So it's not like they'll come back or anything.
You...
You really are cold-hearted.
[Angelfishes' Grave]
If something bad happens to Heita...
...what will we do?
It'll be okay.
We'll just think that these guys gave themselves in his stead.
If someone is to be punished for this, let it be me and not Heita.
No, me. It has to be me.
Take-chan...
[Science Preparation Room]
Better than a place with no front door, right?
Everyone's pretending nothing happened.
I can't make a fuss if no one else is.
Good morning.
Hey.
I was wondering...
...do you have a reset button?
I do.
My left molars.
You do have one.
How can you tell something that important to someone so easily?
Are you stupid?
Why are you angry?
Is that... from yesterday...
That's right! She blew the door off...
But she's cute, isn't she?
Honestly, Kawai-san. Do you see her as your rival?
Okay. Quiet down.
She's a transfer student.
I am looking forward to learning with you.
Let's see... Where should she sit...
Well, next to Fukai-kun, of course. Right?
She can have my seat.
She talks funny too, doesn't she?
- It's weird, right?
- Oh. No! It's not like that...
She's only just returned to Japan.
And so... you know?
She ran into Fukai-kun, after not seeing him for a long time.
By "a long time" I mean... well...
They're actually... childhood friends.
What?
Right?
What? Really?
Yes.
It's such a huge coincidence.
- Se... Sensei!
- Yes?
Her name.
Name? Oh!
That's right. Her name.
I am Kyuuto.
Kyuuto?
Is that your last name?
Last name... Last name...
This is Kyuuto Karen-san.
- Karen?
- That's so pretty...
He used the characters for "flower" and "love"?
Okay, okay. Now all of you introduce yourselves too. Okay?
We'll start there.
Taki Reiji. Nice to meet you.
Souda Rika.
Nakao Jun.
Kotegawa Yui.
Fujioka Makoto.
Gojou Takuya.
- Akagawa Shiori.
- Kageyama Satoshi
- Miyazawa Saburou.
- Okazaki Asuka.
Nishimura Tomorou.
Hey! Guys, if you say your names that quickly Kyuuto-san won't be able to remember them, right?
Do not worry.
I remember them.
Taki Reiji, Souda Rika, Nakao Jun...
...Kotegawa Yui, Fujioka Makoto, Gojou Takuya, Akagawa Shiori...
...Kageyama Satoshi, Miyazawa Saburou...
...Okazaki Asuka, Nishimura Tomorou.
That's amazing...
What an overwhelming memory... She might be more amazing than Kawai.
Did you see that? Kawai-san's expression looked strained, didn't it?
The head of the class may be facing a fall...
- If she falls, she'll just be another ugly girl, right?
- Hey. Honestly...
Please... continue.
Here. Now...
Anyway... standing out is bad.
Standing out is bad.
That's right. At school, it's best to let things just flow by calmly, without standing out.
Why?
It's a rule for school.
And...
This is your name...
Try writing it.
Hey!
You can write!
That's right...
Just like that. Huh?
This...is the same as mine! You have to write the characters differently!
Differently?
The characters are all the same, but... they're different for each person.
The same... but different.
That's right. So... try changing them when you write them this time.
Good.
That's backwards!
Man, this is such a pain...
Will you press...
...the reset button?
You will not push it?
Kubo! Kubo, come here a sec...
Hey. What's up?
Write "Kyuuto Karen."
Huh? Why don't you just ask a classmate?
It'd be bad to ask someone in my own grade, so...
Sorry.
I'll just... look for someone else.
Heita!
Hm?
I'm having the surgery again.
I'll be a second-year again next year.
Here.
There! Stay there! Keep it!
Second-years are so carefree, aren't they?
Your class is all on edge from entrance exams, right?
Hey, Kubo! Hurry up! This is crazy!
Run! Dash! Hurry up! Dash!
Hey, Heita...
The world isn't fair, is it...
But...
...they say humanity will be destroyed in the year 2012.
No way. It's not gonna get destroyed.
Wanna ask for it?
Ask who?
There used to be that rumor, right?
They said that if you wrote down your wish and buried it under the steel tower it'd come true, right?
But... it's the destruction of humanity, you know...
Too much, huh?
Right now...
...we can't even go to the tower to bury it.
Good work everyone...
Heita...
...you do not run with everyone?
I cannot run with them.
My heart is defective.
Well...
...they did repairs, so...
It's not perfect though.
W-what?
I will reset you.
That's not possible.
Humans don't have reset buttons.
We don't have them.
Then...what do you do?
When humans wish to reset...
...what do they do?
Fukai?
Oh. Here.
- Fukushima.
- Here.
- Let's see... Miyazawa.
- Sensei.
- Yes?
What is it?
Sensei, you did not call Fujioka Makoto's name.
- That's right. He didn't.
- Why'd you leave Fujioka out?
Why didn't you call on him?
Well... there are certain circumstances, you see.
- What circumstances?
- It's a little tough to...
Hey. What's going on? What did Fujioka do?
He hasn't paid his tuition.
Because of stuff at home, he can't.
That's why his name has been taken off the attendance roster.
That's horrible...
Sensei... is that true?
Well, this is a private school, right? And all of you are, you know...
Your parents are paying your high tuitions. Let's get back to class now.
Kyuuto. You sit down now too.
Let's see...
Hey. Wait. Wait!
Where are you going?
I am going to find Fujioka Makoto.
Just leave it alone.
But Fujioka Makoto has not had his name called.
All humans have something that no one else can understand.
No matter how hard we try, we won't be able to understand, so...
...it's better to pretend we don't notice.
That's what's called "kindness."
I will look for Fujioka Makoto.
And then I will have his name called.
Hey, wait. Where are you going?
Hey!
Don't go too far.
Make sure to come back.
I just... Just... Excuse me. I'm sorry.
Fujioka...
What are you doing?
This is a secret, okay? A secret.
I found some bread flour, so we're making bread.
Ready, and...
It's very therapeutic. You want to do it too?
I'm scared of waking up, every morning.
Things at my house are getting worse and worse...
At this rate, I feel like I'll lose myself.
I'd come to school and feel like I could hold on to myself.
For me...
...school is the only place I can be normal.
But...
...when I think about what's to come, I don't know what to do.
Telling people that...
...would only cause them trouble, right?
When people act differently out of consideration it makes me feel worse...
You think so?
I think it might be okay to cause a little trouble...
I don't want to.
I don't want to see everyone looking troubled...
Sorry.
I saw you.
I want to just disappear.
It would have been better if I'd never existed in the first place.
Don't say stuff like that.
Humans do not have a reset button.
That is why, when humans wish to redo something, they ask for help. Correct?
I will show you.
Please pull this.
Huh?
Please pull it.
Pull this?
Okay.
Oh my!
Someone save me!
When you yell in a loud voice...
...someone will come to save you.
That is a rule among humans.
That's...
Have I made a mistake in what I have said?
It'd be nice if it were true, right?
If you scream at the top of your lungs, someone will come to save you.
If that really were a rule for people, that'd be nice, wouldn't it?
Here you go.
Is anyone there?
Someone, please save me!
Anyone!
Please, save me!
Someone, please save me!
Huh? What's going on?
- What's that?
- It's them.
What are they doing?
- They're asking for help, right?
- Why?
How should I know?
They seem super serious, don't they?
Hey, Sensei. Do something for them.
I'm just an employee here. I can't do anything.
Okay. Back to our lesson.
- You're so petty.
- Don't call me petty!
Please, save us!
- Let's get back to class now. Hurry up.
- Please, save us!
You know...
They're asking for help, and we're just going to ignore them?
That's not cool, is it?
- Then, should we scream with them?
- To who?
Well... to...
...the sky!
The sky? Like asking God for help?
We don't even know if gods exist. Why would we ask them?
If only a news helicopter or something were flying by... we'd scream then.
Yeah...
There was one the first day it snowed!
That's right! And a picture of our class was in the paper, right?
- But it's not gonna snow...
- We'd have to solve a crime or something...
Yeah. That'd be impossible...
One might fly.
Today in Shibuya they're having a surprise concert, "Monolith."
What? Seriously?
What? Did you say, "Monolith"? Those are rock bands!
All of Shibuya will be in a panic!
Okay! Let's tell the newspaper about the concert and get that helicopter to fly!
Yeah!
What are you getting excited about? We're in the middle of class!
Please, save us!
Hey, you!
You're not loud enough!
Unless you yell louder, they'll never hear!
Hey! Go get your desks. Go on. Hurry up.
Go on.
All right. Let's go!
Excuse us.
What're they doing?
They said they're all going to say, "help" together.
I see...
A wig?
The teacher and everyone in class knows.
But they all pretend not to notice, for me.
Is that coldness...
...or kindness?
Probably both.
Maybe it's not coming...
They might not send up a helicopter just for a surprise concert...
Looks like we may have to take it down without a big climax, huh?
There it is!
Ow! Hot! Hot, hot...
Hot, hot...
It really did fly...
Tamiko...
They said it's canceled.
Someone must've told them about the concert today.
This is the worst. I was really looking forward to it...
Right?
Yay! You feelin' the love?
No one came to save us.
No one came to help.
We know that.
Everyone understands.
Hey!
Huh?
No way! Seriously?
Ow...
Split it up! That's your share!
Kubo!
Hey.
What you did today cracked me up.
And my hospitalization date's been finalized.
When do you go in?
Tomorrow.
Tomorrow, huh?
I'll be causing trouble for everyone again...
Do you remember?
...that night we thought about destroying the world...
You know, I...
...I thought everything was my fault.
Having to go to the hospital...
The fact that because of that Mom and Dad got more and more exhausted...
That my sister's grades dropped...
It was all my fault...
It hurt so much... I couldn't carry that responsibility...
A world like that... I thought it'd be better for it to disappear.
The truth is it wasn't our fault.
I'm certain...
...it isn't anyone's fault.
Do you know her?
Dingy zori shop.
- Stupid! Stupid! You're too loud!
- Perverted old man's grocery...
- Bridge. Shopping district.
- Quiet! Yes, yes...
- Yes. That's right. Okay.
- Cafe with delicious egg sandwiches, London.
Real estate agency's flag... flag... flag...
All of this is our city.
Yes. That's right. It's our city.
Sorry. She's a little weird...
That's... a gacha-gacha machine.
When you put money in a toy comes out.
She's never seen one?
I really don't want for humanity to be destroyed.
I want this city to keep going, even after I die.
That's what I think too, now.
It has been born.
Not here...
Here! Found it!
It's here! I found it!
But...
That's disgusting!
It's here, but... it's gross...
Can't tell anything with this... Nothing.
This part looks legible, doesn't it?
See?
It's been born.
"...world..."
The "world" has been born.
Why won't you call his name for him?
I don't want to do anything irresponsible...
You are such a small person.
That's right. I am a small man.
In that case...
"Fujioka-kun... How are you today?"
...you can say that if you want to, can't you?
I can't do that...
That's what I'd do...
Since I've gotten old...
...I never want to do anything that makes me think, "I wish I would have..."
You're not old at all.
What is that?
I received it from Kubo-kun.
Huh? Man, he really doesn't miss a trick.
What's he trying to do?
Why...
...did you throw it away?
Sorry.
It's okay. I know his number, so...
I still have the number in my memory.
It was the paper.
You want paper?
Paper... paper...
The characters are different.
If Kubo-kun did not write it... it is not the same.
I'm sorry.
Kyuuto...
Since that day, Kyuuto...
...hasn't spoken a single word.
- Kawai.
- Here.
Kyuuto.
Kyuuto Karen.
Hey.
What happened?
Please, don't ask me.
- Kotegawa.
- Here.
I didn't know that not being spoken to...
...was this painful.
Shigematsu.
Fujioka.
Fujioka Makoto.
You doing okay?
Yes.
Oh. Just now, I was just chatting, so...
Okay. Time for class...
Oh dear...
Of course you can't talk like this...
You don't have any saliva, so if you chew gum your teeth will stick together. Understand?
[...world...]
Oh, right...
You gave Kyuuto your cellphone number, right?
Huh?
It's just... it seems she lost that paper, so...
...write it again for her.
Huh? Why? You know it, right? Just tell her...
No. Somehow...
She said she wants the one you wrote.
What's that mean?
She said she wants the one in your handwriting.
Just write.
What?
What is this feeling?
Don't look so happy.
She's a robot.
She's not a person...
...just an object.
If you get too excited, you'll just be embarrassed later.
I wanted to tell him then, that second.
There.
Thanks.
What is this?
...my heart is filling with spite...
That girl's kinda weird, isn't she?
She's totally weird.
To try to keep him from seeing that...
...I gritted my teeth and forced a smile.
As I did...
...deep inside...
...I realized a switch had been flipped.
A switch I didn't know existed... one no one had told me about...
...had been flipped.
[Kaidan no katasumi ni...]
In a corner, on the stairs...
[...suwari uzukumaru no ano hito ni...]
...that person cowering, crouched...
[...nani ga atta n darou]
...I wonder what happened.
[Ittai nani wo mitekita n darou]
What did that person see?
[Hitogomi no naka de...]
In a crowd of people...
[...niramiau danjou no aida ni...]
...that man and woman glare at each other...
[...nani ga okottarou]
...I wonder what happened between them.
[Ittai donna jijou ga atta n darou]
What circumstances led them there?
[Itsuka boku wo yobidashita...]
Once, you called me outside...
[...sensei ga donatteta sono scene ha...]
...and the teacher yelled. That scene...
[...donna dattarou]
...I wonder what it looked like.
[Ittai boku ha nani wo shitta n darou]
What on earth did I learn from it?
[Itsu kara ka tsuzuiteru...]
On the other side...
[...sensou no hate ni donna koto ga...]
...of this war that's lasted since who knows when...
[...matteru n darou]
...I wonder what waits for us.
[Soushite boku ni nani ga dekiru n darou]
And what can I do?
[Koto no shinsou ha nani mo...]
The truth of things...
[...shitteiru you de shirienai...]
...we feel like we know, but we can't learn...
[Sore demo dou ni ka kou ni ka...]
Even so, somehow or another...
[...ikiteita naka ga nai]
...It's like we were never here.
[Muda ga atteba tarirarenai]
It's not enough to meet with futility...
[Demo shinjirareru mono mo sukunai]
But there are too few things to believe in...
[Tada hitotsu tashika na no ha boku no kimochi]
The only certain thing is my feelings...
[Kimi no sono koe wo kikashite yo]
Let me hear that voice of yours
[Shinjireru mono ga soko ni aru yo]
That's where I find something to believe in
[Tada hitotsu tashika na no ha omae to no toki]
The only certain thing is my time with you...
[Kimi ga suki]
I love you
Love is a revolution.
Everything you know to be true gets flipped upside-down...
People can fall in love with whomever they like.
Is this a place you can keep living?
That's it.
I...
...am in love.