Some time ago, the Brown War raged.
Strong winds were blowing in winter.
Next?
Oh! Next.
What the...? Will this never end?
Did we win? Are we defeated?
I have no idea.
By the way, against whom are we fighting?
If we knew that, what would it matter?
And how are we going to win?
Huh?
Oh.
We're doomed.
Kyuuto-san, it's dangerous!
Don't worry. She'll be fine.
Why?
Huh?
Why? Why?
That is...
Why? Why? Why?
Because...
Why? Why?
Because Kyuuto is...
Because she's a robot!
What's wrong with you?
Yeah, Yeah, Ok...let's pay attention again.
Well, those kinds of interruption happen, right?
Still, he continued to write poems, even though he was aware he was dying...
Nakao,
I still haven't got your career sheet.
Career sheet?
Right, your career sheet.
I don't care about that.
What?
There's something far more important going on right now.
What is it?!
Something more important than your career?
I can't tell.
Even under torture I can't tell!
Hey!
Eh? What next stage?
Kissing, of course.
It's kissing, right?
What are you talking about?
How far have you guys gone?
"You guys"?
I mean.. you and Kyuuto...
How far have you gone?
Ah!! Perhaps you went straight to Level 4!?
I knew it! Isn't it so? You did it with her?
Wha... You went right in...
Wow! Right in? Right in?
There is no next level.
Kyuuto is a robot.
And I am a human.
No matter how far we go, we can't unite with each other.
What are you listening to?
It's because we follow the God of Heaven and Earth...
Rakugo? Why?
Because I've been told that the way I talk is strange.
I'm studying by listening to rakugo (comic stories).
Yeah, your way of speaking is getting better.
Ah, your career sheet? What do you mean by "Making Efforts"?
Young Master...
"Young Master"?
What did you write?
I... nothing yet.
As for the God of Heaven and Earth
do you think he will watch over you forever?
Young Master, when the grain of rice does not make an effort,
the God of Heaven and Earth will not watch over it.
Well... just a minute, ok? It seems really strange.
Imagine,
even Kyuuto has something like a goal.
And because of that she is trying really hard.
I wonder what I should do next.
Show me!
Take it off and show me!
Hey! Hey!
What are you doing, Nakao?!
You're disgusting!
Stop! Stop!
Ow!
Hey, you! Don't act like a stalker!
Fukai.
Kyuuto-san... You've touched her before, right?
What do you mean?
You have, right?
Well, yeah...
How was it?
"How"?
Just a minute, hold on!
It felt like a human.
Well, ... I mean....
I knew it!
She isn't human, is she?
What're you saying?
She's human!
Can't you see? She's human!
And besides... It's not like we were holding hands.
Show me the evidence if you have any!
What do you mean, "evidence"?
You're saying, "She's human."
What do you mean? For example?
Something like crying.
Something like crying...
She probably cries a lot. She's a human being!
I'm sure she cries a lot! She's a human being!
What're you saying?
You want to make Ogawa-sensei cry?
No! I mean Kyuuto.
Why that?
Nakao said that she's a robot. He seems to suspect something.
And if she cries, then he'll believe she's a human?
She can't cry, right?
Technically speaking, I don't think
it will be very difficult to make her cry.
She should be able to do it.
Hey, you can cry, right?
Tears are ready for action.
No way! You can cry?
Puff.
Then... cry! Can you cry now?
Ok. I'll ask Nakao to come here.
Young Master, without a reason it's not possible.
First you have to say something to make me cry.
Something to make you cry?
Quick!
But I can't do that. I might hurt her feelings.
I will not be hurt.
After all, Kyuuto is a robot!
Come on! Some sort of insult should come to your mind.
Just say it!
Young Master, please say it anyway.
Is it alright?
Really? Well, don't be angry.
Here I go.
This...
Ah!
I can't say it! I can't say it!
This is human.
Puff.
Oh man! I want to become a beast!
Think of all the things we're missing.
I want to charge ahead.
Is that the power of the beast, or what?
"Love beast."
Wow... What the...?!
It says "Love" and "Beast".
On the other side of that door...
What do you think does happen there?!
I guess
this sort of thing,
and that sort of thing, and...
Hold on!
Let's take a picture!
What an amazing store!!
Look, someone went in. That guy...
Pretty brazen to go there in the middle of the day.
I got it!
I'm home!
I did it!
Show me! Show me!
This is pretty good.
Ta-daa!
Hey, it's pretty good, isn't it.
What? You got it enlarged?
Sure, it's the first time we're in a photo together with a celebrity.
But I'm not in it, am I?
Well, that's true.
That's because you're the one who took the picture.
Right, but...
But imagine, even you were properly added to the photo.
You're kidding. I'm there? Where, where, where?
I'm the lion?!
Somehow this resembles our family, doesn't it?
It really does. Absolutely fitting.
Are we going to send this to Grandpa too?
Either way is fine.
Oh! Oh! Oh...
Ok!
An unemployed, homeless man was arrested. The suspect said, "Anyone would have been fine"...
"Anyone would have been fine", you say. No way! You...
Ok, Ok.
Hello?
You keep saying, "Me, Me", don't you?
And you keep whining about everything!
But that isn't going to work with me!
Do you really think anyone would be fine?
Hey! Wait.. Don't cut me off!
Coward!
Why don't you even recognise your own son's voice?
You should listen to a person till the end.
I've just realized it.
What?
Without you I can't go on.
Oh, that's certainly not true.
It is! I need you.
Eh?!  What?
Can you come with me for a moment?
No, no, that won't be good.
Only for a little while.
I guess it should be about 3 cm to the right.
Ok.
That's it! Yes, yes.
Please don't move!
Just as I thought!
What is it?
When you are sitting there
my computer runs smoothly!
And what is the reason for that?
I have no idea.
Well, I'm pretty busy, so...
You can't go!
Well...  You don't really need me, right?
Of course I've made several tests. I'm a scientist, after all.
But unless you are here, it doesn't work.
Well, if I end up getting a job transfer, what will you do?
Then I'd be in trouble.
When you get married, I'll bring it!
Y.. you mean to me?
I'll bring it!
You haven't written anything yet?
Ah, my career sheet?
Whatever. I don't care.
I have to chose between things that do not interest me
and things I'm not capable to do.
I have been seriously thinking about these options but I guess it can't be helped.
There's no job waiting only for me.
Anyway. For me, anything is fine.
Well ... Well ... Wait.
What? Did I say something wrong?
Fukai did say something to her.
I wonder what?
Probably awful things.
What!?
Maybe she should be treated like a human.
"Treated"?
Like embracing and stroking her head.
Are you saying I should do it?
You made her cry, didn't you?
What!
Hurry! Do it!
Here??
It's impossible.
Impossible.
Impossible...
Perhaps.
I'm a love beast!
Okay.
I have
decided to go to the same university as you.
What? Why?
Eh? It's no good?
No, not that. But you have a higher ranking, right?
You can choose to go wherever you like.
If you're not at the same university, there's no meaning for me.
But I can't take responsibility for that.
Ah... No... well... But, given my nature...
even if I could go to a good university, I might not go, you know...
So, let's talk about this later.
Don't talk like that!
No, but... um....
Am I a burden to you?
No... that...
I see. I am a burden.
No, I didn't mean it that way.
How's it going?
Still nothing!
Why doesn't he wipe her tears?
Here I go.
Oh! I'm sorry!
Are you ok? I'm sorry.
I am fine.
Ah! I'm glad.
You shouldn't make such a pretty girl cry.
Did you stop crying because of what just happened?
Puff.
It can't be! It can't be! Eh...!?
It can't be. You're lying, right?
In other words, it hadn't to be me?
That is how I have been configured.
What the...
Shall I modify the settings?
Enough already.
Are you angry?
I'm not angry!
Young Master.
What is it?
You're a pure human, aren't you.
Where do you want to go?
Whereever you want, Ken-chan.
Mom?
Hey! Are you alright?
Why is dad going to that store?
Don't you think that's disgusting?
Take-chan is working there.
Working there?
Why don't you stop him?
See, it's the "Love Beast"!
Our financial situation isn't good, you know.
Because of my hospital bill?
No, it's not just that. Other things, too.
I tried to get a part-time job,
but I'm bad at such things, aren't I?
Then Take-chan said, "It's alright. I'll do something myself."
Even so...there are probably other jobs.
Why "Love Beast"?
"It's a place where one's appearance does not matter", Take-chan said.
In order to protect important things,
amazingly he never gives up.
Thank God, you weren't hurt.
Good, good.
Even when everything had fallen to pieces,
he came to pick up the small fragments,
struggling to put back things the way they were before.
I trust him.
Although I'm uneasy about his job at "Love Beast",
I'm still going to believe in Take-chan.
Good morning.
Say! Why did you cry yesterday?
Because of Young Master.
Young Master?
Young Master did it violently.
Huh?
Young Master!
You did it violently? You!?
How indecent!
I didn't do anything!
I'm telling the truth... I didn't do anything.
Young Master has absolutely no understanding of other people.
Why?
Didn't I say, "Anything would be fine"?
Eh?! You really said, "Anything would be fine"?
It's not what you think! That's not it!
Eh? Why are you thinking that way?
Apologize to her!
Why can't this person with beauty and brains write decently?
These days, no one says "beauty and brains" any longer.
Now it's "science combination"!
"Science combination"?
It's a beautiful woman who's good at science.
Just like me!
"Let us drink this thick syrup."
That's a Nakahara Chuuya poem, isn't it?
I'm also good at literature. Do you want to drink something?
Yes!
"Make it cool and drink it through thick straws."
"Without glancing aside let us drink gently."
What is this?
It's mozuku (seaweed) soda.
"There's nothing more that I would ask."
I've decided!
What is it?
My career.
I'll proceed to engineering.
But you're not doing good in mathematics at all!
From now on, I'm going to focus more on math!
I'll do my best!
Why this, all of a sudden?
Why don't you try arts and literature?
Literature is no use!
Why?
I want to construct robots!
Robots!
Why Robots?
I will construct a robot that can cry.
No, no. You know, it's already November....
People don't become what they're able to become,
they become what they want to become.
Am I wrong?
Even if I am tortured, I won't change my mind!
What's that all about!
Is this the place,
where students who can't decide on their careers are detained?
Yes, it is.
Who are you?
Just a nobody. I'm Fujino Tsukiko.
Ah... I thought you had a darker aura.
Looks like you can't make up your mind about your career, right?
For your information, I have already decided.
No way! Eh?
Really?
Wait a minute, show it to me.
No way!
It's ok, we have about the same rank in class.
Huh?! Something this difficult?
There are lots of reasons.
But...
There's no other way.
What are you up to?
Yamamoto? You too?
You guys are too strange.
You have to decide what you want to do with your life today.
You have neither the courage to write something down,
nor the courage to go home.
Sorry I took so long.
Ogawa-sensei, I made a great discovery.
The computer also works with a rubber tree. Look!
Even if you don't come anymore, it's ok.
Ah ... A rubber tree.
"My life that day was like an empty chair."
That's enough for today.
See you, then.
See you later.
Bye, bye!
Bye!
Let's eat ramen afterwards...
Ramen?
Huh? The wig?
You're not wearing it today?
I only wear it in school.
You have a medical check-up today?
I'm visiting a friend.
See you.
Isn't this yours?
Ah! Just leave it there.
Leave it?
But you have to submit this, right?
It's ok. Whatever I write will just be a lie.
Then, what about that?
Rock?
I can't write that. There's no way I can write something like that.
Why?
Our homeroom teacher would get mad.
But I can't think of anything else I want to be.
And I can't write anything adequate enough.
But can't you express your true feelings somehow?
I'm impatient, I'm frustrated.
I wonder what will happen in the future.
I want to express openly what I am thinking, but
I'll be more troubled if I say those things.
I want to say things like "I'm alright" not just to comfort someone.
I want to be able to say "Thank you. I'll try my best".
Maybe your teacher won't understand you.
Yet, say it somehow.
Even if it's annoying.
To sing about such things...
That's Rock.
Hey, are you going to play today?
Yeah.
Can I come with you?
Are you allowed to go out?
It's alright if I drive by taxi.
I'm ok with it.
The patients are waiting.
Go! Hurry hurry!
Yes.
Ok. I'll go.
Can somebody go to Ishida-san, please?
I'll go.
Be careful. He's nervous.
Strong-flavored diet is not good for him.
The prescribed painkiller doesn't have any effect.
I get it.
I'm here for a test.
Sorry I took so long.
Is something wrong?
I wonder if it's right.
What about?
"Why can't anyone understand the truth?",
you said, but
that's probably not true.
In your case,
there are people who are seriously thinking about you.
Who?
The people who are working here.
Everyone here is thinking about and working solely for the patients.
Although they are all mature adults, they are warm-hearted.
In front of those hard-working people
you can say things like that?
Can you betray their trust?
There's no way I could do that.
I can't do that.
Great. This looks like a Japanese wordplay.
Ogawa-sensei...
I see... He's not here.
Ah, I wan't to talk to someone!
Luna-chan's collectibles.
Hey, young boy right there.
You won't be able to sell with such a low voice.
Wait. I'll help you selling.
This is good~
Although made poorly,
I'll buy everything.
These two you will sell yourself.
With a loud voice, right?
Thank you.
I'm home. Ryuto?
You're late.
What have you been doing?
Why are you here?
Just asking what's with your career sheet.
"What's with it"?
I can't graduate anyway.
There you go again.
I don't care whether I graduate.
I'm home.
Where have you been? It's already late.
How about you? You always come home late.
By the way, seems like your father and mother are late.
Who is he?
Our principal.
They're not coming home anymore recently.
Is that so?
They got divorced.
Divorced?
By the way, do you eat curry?
I've cooked it.
You don't have to do that, sensei.
You came all the way here, but I still don't know what to do in the future.
You're just wasting your time.
But
when will you make a decision?
You're running out of time.
When I was young,
I hurt the girl I loved.
I suspected her of double-dating with a friend of mine.
After we had broken up, I ate bread with bean jam.
I came from a poor family,
and it was the best bread I ever had.
It was sweet and fluffy.
It kept me thinking "So, there is something this good in the world".
I promised myself to take back my accusations
and bought that bread for her,
but when I reached her home,
I heard that she had died in a car accident.
Later, when I came back to the place that sells the bread, I bought lots of it.
I wanted to eat it,
but I couldn't.
I couldn't stop crying.
If only I had known she'll die, I could have done something.
Therefore, say something like "I'll do what I can".
Then think of something that you can do and do it.
Something that I can do?
First, before your mom and dad come home,
clean up this mess.
Wash the glasses until they shine brightly.
Wash the dirty clothes and fold them neatly.
With a smiling face say "Welcome home" when they come back.
After that,
serve them a warm meal.
Such a thing...
Just do it!
By such things people's hearts are won.
Eat!
Your mother wrote this with a lot of effort.
Useless! I'm finished!
I think I'm going blind.
I can't decide on what to do. I'll be doomed in eternity!
There's no such thing as eternity.
There's no forever in this world.
Even the universe will have an end.
The universe will have an end?
The universe consists of 23% dark matter
and 73% invisible energy.
So most of it is invisible?
All other substances are only 4%.
Unfortunately, as time progresses, energy keeps on increasing.
Eh? How does it increase?
Matter is falling apart.
Falling apart?
All atoms are falling apart until
they turn into small particles.
Small particles...what do you mean?
The desk,
the blackboard,
the windows,
the corridor, the courtyard,
the lawn, the athletic field,
the flowers, the clouds,
me and you.
Even now, the quantity of energy is increasing.
It just happens.
There's nothing we can do.
The energy keeps on increasing,
even if this is beyond our understanding.
The atoms fall apart
until only small particles are left.
In other words, the darkness keeps on increasing
until the Earth is dust?
Before that happens, the Sun will have collapsed.
The Sun also?
Of course, the Sun will also vanish.
No way...
Well, it will happen in 100 billion years.
This theory will be confirmed in year 2016.
In year 2025, the word "eternity" will be erased from the national language textbooks
and
we won't use the word "eternity" any more.
You understand?
There is no eternity.
Someday, everything is over.
Eh! What happened to your hair?
"Nurse"?
You want to become a nurse?
That will be the name of our rock group.
Oh, I see ... Eh?!
You want to be a rocker?
Yes.
Are you serious?
Man~ you as a rocker?
Well, it can't be helped. I understand.
I have a friend who works in that business.
I'll try asking him.
What is it?
I just remembered something.
Something?
Something I didn't take serious then.
"People don't become what they're able to become,"
"they become what they want to become."
Who told you that?
Nakao.
Me too...me too.
Do you know "maneyozu"?
That's a joke, right?
There is no eternity in this world.
Even the universe will have an end.
All atoms are torn apart into tiny particles.
Someday, everything is over.
What's wrong?
The universe will have an end.
What?
Everything in here will be torn into pieces.
Are you alright?
Hey! Where are you going?
Hey! The meal?
So cute!
That boy's peak was at 5 years.
No no... later it get's worse and worse.
Excuse me.
Yes?
Where's Kyuuto?
She went out.
She said she wants to watch a rakugo and learn from it.
Do you know that play "The Pumpkin Shop"?
When she meets Young Master again, she wants to be able to talk properly.
Where is she?
Kyuuto!
It's terrible!
It's not only the rice.
The God of the rice paddies will apparently disappear too.
And not only the God of the rice paddies,
everything will disappear when the Earth turns to dust.
I don't understand it completely, but me and you
are just like the other 4% of the universe.
Even now it's happening.
It's called dark energy.
This is....
Now I understand.
Most people in this world
think that "anything is fine" and
there's nothing they can do.
While we
keep on saying "anyhow" and such,
the darkness keeps growing bigger and bigger
and the universe is gradually torn to pieces.
Therefore, we should root our most important things
deep in our hearts,
so that they can't be easily dispersed.
Embracing them tightly,
so as not to lose them.
I know that eventually they will disappear,
but I'll strive harder.
Young Master,
do you have something on your mind?
Yeah,
I'll never say something like "anything is fine".
Right now, I am
embracing my 4% of the universe.
Sorry.
She hasn't come home yet.
It's ok. I'll come visit again.
Are we neighbours?
Yes.
Do you serve rice here?
We only have yaki-udon.
That's ok.
Then... please.
Sensei, I have decided.
This important 4% part that I embraced,
from now on, I'll live for it.