What are you doing?
Huh? Repairing.
Repairing the robot? Stop doing things whenever you like!
Who do you think you're talking to?
Well, I haven't seen anyone from NASA.
I own a bicycle shop.
So what about it?
I repair flat tires for so many years..
no..no...
Repair flat tires? ah...ah!
You're noisy.
Therefore, as long as I repair in the shop,
it will be alright.
What about you.
What about me?
I'm a high school teacher.
I am curious.
Where?! Why?!
I am curious how do you teach your students.
I am really a teacher!
With that short hand of yours?
What do you mean of that?
What am I?
Bicycle shop.
High school teacher.
Well, aren't you a robot?
Right?
I am a robot~!
Wait a minute! As for you...
you are a high school girl.
But, I'm a robot...
Well, yes you are but..
you have to remember that you act as high school student in this world.
Yes! That's it! Yes!
You have a face of a high school student.
I am a high school girl.
That is not how high school girls sound
It should be I am a high school girl~~
Just forget what you're doing right now.
I made this with a lot of effort
You will eat this right?
Right?
Uhhh...ok.
sigh~~
Whoa~~ High school girls alright...
Waah!! What do you want?
Q10 is a high school girl right?
Yes..isnt it obvious?
How can you tell?
Well, you're even wearing a high school uniform.
What will I become if I remove my uniform?
As for that…
You're a robot right?
Well, no one calls me that.
If that is the case, then what am I?
You have to go out first. This is a men's toilet.
I saw that.
You saw?
Oh well this is given to me….
Not that one..
Kyuto.
Q10?
I have seen a sort of machine under the skin of her broken arm.
She's a robot right?
≪ Right! right! ≫
Just as i thought. She really is.
That's not it!
So it's a secret?
Uh..you are mistaken.
I understand. I'm not going to tell anyone.
So, can you give Kyuto to me?
Huh? What do you mean give to you?
Even though you say that. Besides, I don't own her ..
Is that so?
I don't have anything to do with her.
Then, you will give her to me right?
Give her to you?
Young master pinch it.
During this time, it's useless to pinch your mouth. You must have a poker face.
She even has a poker face even if you don't tell her
But Nakao-kun can see right through you right?
Even though Nakao-kun can see right through you that far
He can't hear you right?
Eh?
By the way, he has no other choice right?
Even if it will be his, he wont even tell.
Wait a minute please.
Well then, do you mean he will press the reset button?
Yes. Nakao-kun must press again the molar switch
But, in real life, there is no such thing as reset button
For the adults,
there are certain things that the eye cannot see.
Yes there is.
There is. There is.
But...well...
Up until now, I'm still wondering how did it happen
Such thing does not exist.
Now you mention it
Maybe there is a back up...
Puff.
Puff?
Then, there is no problem.
Sorry that I spent more time caring.
But!
This round has been decided...
Wait a minute!
Do you always have time to make things come?
What are you talking about?
Don't force yourself.
I'm not forcing myself!
It will be fine if she's with Nakao.
For me, no one can replace you
But, just like a situation today which is happening slowly..
Just like a harmless child and a cool bad person
That's right. Even if it wasn't me, that will be great.
What is it?
Your switch
I just happened to press it accidentaly
But Heita was the one who pressed it
And then I met Heita..
And then I am walking with you here.
Is that a mistake?
I thought I'm going to lose you
Just like when the sun sets
I'm not going to see Kyuto's ugly uniform..
I can't hear the strange way of your talking
Where then can I hear your voice that sounds like a brass of a school band
Kyuto.
What is the meaning of that?
Well, it is a joke.
Joke?
I mean, when you play..
Right now, everything that happened has given me a chance
I thought I'm going to lose you
Thanks for waiting. Here is Yaki-udon.
Oh, that's right.
What is this?
I asked a favor from a friend
However, this is a trial product.
Perfume?
It is perfume for dogs.
For the dogs?
Recently, a herbivorous type of dog is increasing
For the dogs..
I recovered the original type of Hindu dog and returned it to
Kainushi-san you know.
Hmmm
Ah!
Oh man it stinks!
What's wrong? Why are running away from me?
Because she's scared of you
Sensei,
She thinks that you're a beast.
I am a beast?!
Ah! Chiro-chan! Chiro!
So what do you think of this?
Hey.
Mou~~
I am a high school teacher
Well, yes you are..
Chiro-chan~~
This is a misunderstanding ~~
How can I be a beast? Jeezz
There you are! There you are!
Chiro-chan~! You found her.
I found her because of the beating of her heart.
Beating of her heart?
Her heart beat is like one, two, one, two..Is that wrong?
So you can identify by using such thing.
Puff.
Awesome.
Next time, tell me what sound it is.
"Fukai Heita's sound" What is that?
My sound??
≪ This is bad ≫
≪ Self centered person≫
≪ So cool! ≫
That is the girl in the internet that is found out to have red eyes
Eh? "Red eye"? It's not red hair?
It's a wig! Wig!
Eh? Really?
((It seems that there is a fight happening in the internet))
((I've seen it. I've seen it. She's hanging out with dangerous people))
((I saw Takashi and midlle-aged man entering the Love Hotel))
((What kind of friends does she have))
((It seems that, that high school student has very bad character))
((It's really worst!))
Where's the manual?
There is none.
None?! Why?
Well, you can ask her anything.
Oh~oh~..
There is an outlet in her waist. You can try charge her.
Really really?~ Ehhh~
You can charge her at least 17 hours in a day
But, there will come a time that she will suddenly turn off.
So, you have to carry her on your back when you go home.
Carry her on my back when going home.
I wonder if you know what I know
Where's the startup switch?
Uh..the switch?
The molar
The reset button is in the left molar.
Take care of her.
Molar?　You mean molar?!
What do you mean molar?
Why molar?
Are you ok?
I have transferred Kyuto to Nakao right now.
Bussiness completed.
Fuu~ it seems that you can't do poker face.
Say you don't want it if you really don't want it.
I don't want it.
If Kyuto will be found out
there will probably be a terrible thing going to happen
That is why if only I can hold it further,
then it will be ok. But then I can't
By the way professor, you didn't think that I can do such thing right?
Well that's your opinion. I have also an opinion in my position
But, I am standing somewhere else while you are standing in your place.
There is no need for us to stand in the same place.
Where are you standing firmly right now professor?
Ummm
Probably in a place where truth is
A place where I can do everything for someone else
Can do everything?
Yup
Hey Fukai.
What is it?
I can't reset her
Hurry reset her!
OK
It should be fine wherever I stand right?
It is up to you to decide.
Eh?
I can't give Kyuto to you
Why?! Why?
You promised, right?
I will say something about her on the internet.
I will say that Fukai's lover is a doll!
Then do it.
I'm going to reveal it!
I'm serious!
What am I going to do?
Nakao is seriously going to do it!
I'm really an idiot.
It'll be ok.
It is not ok!
Rumors spreads so fast.
There will come a day that everybody will stop talking to me.
Everybody will think that I don't exist.
Maybe its not perfect. I don't have much time.
But Heita kun is here.
What is this?
Heita-kun's sound.
My sound?
This is the sound of Heita-kun's heart.
[Earphone] (heart beat)
Heita-kun is here
[Earphone] (beat)
Whatever sound it is.
Heita is here.
There it is~
Just as I thought. It's good.
Inhaling with mere sleeping chill.
Who do you think you are talking to?
But, you're a doctor right?
I have read everything about Iryu manga.
Your lip has a good color.
Good!
Ok. Breathe please.
Hmm... There's nothing wrong.
Do you really think there's nothing wrong?
I said, it's ok.
Ok. Let's listen at the back.
Whoa~~
What's wrong?
Well, I got fascinated for a while...
Eh?
Fascinated by it? No way..
You came back with a good back.
No way! Do you really think so?
You're lying right?
Can I take a picture of it?
Picture?
Eh...well sure you can,
Ok..
Whoa~ This is good.
After all, it's a back of a man right?
Hey hey..Is it really true that Kageyama is going to Canada?
Eh?
Where else? Nanpa?
Stop doing that in front of Kawai-san.
Hey!
What?　What happened?
It's too terrible. Terrible.
It's really terrible.
What are you saying?
That you're going to Canada.
A...
So, you're going
It's ok wherever you go. But it would be better if you have told me 1 week ahead of time.  I don't have a problem with it.
Well, you should have asked me first..
It could be longer than that.
Longer than 1 week?
Well, therefore...
That high school that I have told you
An acquaintance from work helped me apply to working in videos
What about college? Let's go together...
About that...
I'm sorry.
But, I really want to do it.
I want to go back to a place wherein you are there.
In the past, I have no expectations nor hope. And I was fine with it.
I thought that I won't get hurt forever
I was wary, but still I wanted to live
Do you think I am being punished?
Maybe because of my ugly voice.
Why do you think of that? You are not ugly at all...
You are going to break up with me right?
What are you talking about? I don't understand what you're saying.
Don't be mad.
I'm not mad.
You're angry.
Jeez...
Now you're thinking that I am troublesome.
You're thinking like that right?
I'm not thinking of that!
You don't like poker face?
Why?
It is cute if you keep doing that.
Because I cannot make anyone lively right?
You want to uplift someone spirit?
Puff.
Why do you always say "puff"?
Hm?
You might be able to do it!
You will be able to do it!
Are you bothered Heita?
Well..
During this time, let's get depressed together.
Together?
With a robot….?
Kyuto is depressed.
Was I not depressed enough?
Gan~~
Did your spirit came back?
Yea~
That's good
It would be nice if we could go together
Just the two of us.
Far away from here forever
Open it.
Eh?
Hmm?
When you open that, something terrible happens
The power is scary.
Once it will be ours, we want to do something out from it.
Isn't it?
Yes.
I was thinking that someone with power can do everything
to the world right now which is broken
You want to break it right?
The world right now.
Our world right now?
To really break the so called great world
Never
Do not break a world.
If you are person who cannot make it happen.If you cannot get hold of great power
But I really want it.
I'm telling you I really want a hell of it.
Really?
But I am, just like you, wanted to have more great power.
Use the telephone
Write it in the internet,
Even if you tell someone about it.
They will not believe you.
I'm just telling you this.
Oi! What are you?!
sigh
((Red eye, she's happy right?))
((I have seen that red haired girl))
((It's not red))
((That is a wig))
((Lie ~ I'm ignoring everyone))
((Is that true. I'm really pissed off))
((What?　She must be living well as high school.))
Yo!
Are you perhaps that one?
The one abused in the internet.
Doing such things without asking permission
Everyone will eventually get tired of it.
You are the only one telling me this face to face.
Everybody knows it. Nobody tells me about it.
There is no voice that will come out to say..
"That's not true"
I will always say I'm not lying...
Where will I be?
They might think that "there is no such human being.."
"that is able to face someone by being like that" right?
I want to laugh out loud!
I want to shout out loud!
Don't look down on me!
But I can't reach it
Me who has no name..
And has no face to look at them.
How am I able to do that?
By this.
You can say "I'm not like that!" in a song right?
You can use it by knocking the rumors one by one.
So, let me hear you sing.
This is our band.
Ok.
Before you can listen to it, I'm going to give it to you.
Really? Thank you.
This is so good.
You're giving me something that you like.
Why do you think I dyed my hair red?
Hmm..because it's cool?
That's not it. It's because I'll stand out.
Sensei advised it..
Everyone looked at me, surprised.
And then at that time, I was able to think that "I am here"
And then rock after that.
So that was it
Really.
But right now, you have a partner right?
What do you mean partner? I am a stand up comedian.
I see.
What is this?
That is something to cover the face.
What?　Is this the latest trend?
Huh?
What are you looking for?
Hmmm..medicine.
Medicine??
Ah! Is this the one?
Thank you.
Now..
Let me see you angry.
You're angry!
Hey, I have a question..
Hmm?
Was there a time that you lose your patience?
Of course there is..there is.
Like this foot.
So you have
A, keep it a secret.
Although we want to have it. Living is a proof that we have it.
You know, during that time when you were hospitalized,
You said you don't want anything,
But then suddenly, you said, "I want to eat tomato"
And then there is some guy who bought it.
The aisle that sells vegetables look lively.
Although, the supermarket looks the same as usual,
You said "I still want it.."
You're always completely different.
You said that you want to listen to a tale of death
But what you really want to hear is "I have a long way to live"
Damn it!
Chiro-chan~~!
Chiro-chan~! Where are you?
You still able to smell it?
Oi! It's me you know! It's me!
Come back Chiro-chan~!
I am going to present an incredible invention you know!
Tada! "All about poverty"
When I paste whatever expensive in here
It will instantly look poor.
What do you think? Isn't it great?
Next...Where will I paste the rest~~?
Sensei,
Aren't you afraid of poverty?
You know, as for poverty,
What do you think if you see something like this?
For Fujioka-kun, this is just a lot of paper that I keep.
But it's not like that.
If you really care for it, it will grow like Hagasen right?
I know that.
As long as it is pasted thoroughly, It'll be completely fine.
I believe in myself.
What is it?
Please give me Kyuto.
Wait a second...
Please!
I can't do it.
Please! I am begging you!
Ummm...
She is not a thing.
For me, Kyuto is...
someone that I can't give to anyone
Because of that, I can't give her up
I know that for Nakao, Kyuto is..
a thing that you have to own...
I used to think that way
Kyuto is a thing!
If you're not going to her to me,
I am going to jump from here!
What the...
I'm going to ask you..
Between human life and robot, who do you think is more important?
Which one?!
I mean it.
Who is more important?
It's Kyuto
What are you doing?!
Stop it!　Stop it!
Eh?
It's broken.
From now on, you must continue to live
In my broken world.
Fukai Heita fell down. How are you going to face reality?
In other words, you have used force in it.
Eh?
Why? Why?
From now on, I'm going to throw back Fukai Heita
Eh? No way..
Nakao-kun please catch him.
Just a minute...
That's impossible! I'm telling you! That's absolutely impossible!
I'm just kidding.
Hmm?
Oh!　Chiro-chan!
You came back~~
Yosh..yosh. You really came back!
Hmm? A!
You came back because of my smell.
I see! Yosh..yosh!
Umm...
It seems that I was not of myself.
Just as I thought, I still love you
I will give anything you want...
But, in order to become someone,
I want to do it my way
I want to move forward..
So...
I'm going to a place far away for a while
Well..no..
So, I am going to get that cue..
Are you mad?
What do you mean angry?
Fukai almost died because of me...
Well, maybe I was really about to die
Whichever it is...
We are the worst.
This is the room
where I found Kyuto.
I haven't entered the switch yet and
she was sitting there.
I just happen to found her first
Therefore, I understand what you feel.
I know it's unfair right?
You don't like unfairness right?
“Why is it only me?"
Within me, I am resenting like an idiot
Why are you thinking like that?
Hmm?
Well that…disease.
It wasn't your fault. Still you have a lot of resentment?
I have a lot of resentment.
Although I have resentment, there's nothing I can do about it.
I know that I'm terrible
Therefore “the world's unfairness" is a good thing..
That's what I think
And then I realized,
it's not only me that saw all this
So I'm doing it,
Being resentful or being jealous...
Even those rocks
Little by little they are collapsing. That's what I thought.
But as for small things, I know
That it will still be there.
I will surely think of it somewhere.
Just like us.
Me and you
That is just like us.
Dad, here is the CD set.
Hmmm?
New song of Ohaku.
Mom, it's not yet done?
It's done.
Turn off the lights.
OK!　Mom, it's starting.
Here we go. Yosh!
What is this? That's a performace?
Sorry. This is a mistake.
What is this?
"Fukai Heita's sound"?
Sound of Heita's heart beat?
Yup
It's moving properly.
Yes it is.
It's sincerely moving properly.
I see. So this is the sound of Heita
♪~ I am here
♪~ I am crying hard enough
I am going to tell a story although it can't be heard.
I know that it's a long story.
You will write in a blackboard?
By the way, when I look back,
The classroom is empty.
I think there are times that it's empty.
Who is the one who will act as villain or something
There is no empty classroom.
That's just a metaphor, metaphor
For example! Do you understand?
There are no empty classrooms
What is this?
Since when did you decide to take a bath?
I am a high school teacher.
What came up to you suddenly.
Because I am a high school teacher!
I know that everytime I see your back.
Eh?
What do you mean?
((Between human life and robot, which do you think is more important?))
((Kyuto))
Even small things that fell have
entered to a small opening
What shall I do?
Even nonexistent thing such as myself
will become bigger to the extent that I won't be able to manage it...
I was uneasy last night. I hate it.
You have always felt that way.
Just like the night before your surgery
That night when a patient died in the same room
That night when you were waiting for the test results
Did you forget it?
Sorry..I have forgotten all about it.
Then...You were happy.
You are happy right now.
I see...
So there is a day that you have forgotten all about it.
This is not the place for you already
Where is the place for me then?
You have to decide a place for your own
((That is for you to decide))
Can I really decide it for myself?
Of course
For example, even to a dangerous place?
You have no choice if that place is really meant for you.
That will be the best place for you. Right?
Well then...I...
That tower it is
Kyuto said that "a world is born"
It is that tower
I was thinking that wherever place is ok as long as I am with Kyuto
If my place is that tower
That is probably also Kubo's place
Over there is Kageyama's place
That one is Yamamoto's place
That is Fujioka's place
Nakao's place
Kawai's place
We are all standing facing towards the same sky
As we are all facing towards the sky screaming
no voice is coming out
I don't understand the meaning of feeling good sinking deeply down the root
As I extend my hand mutually,
We are connected only by an unreliable electric wire..
I was always alone...
But I am standing on this ground trying hard
I am right here. Standing right here.
Aaaa...that's right..
We are all here
This drama theme song is "Honto no Kimochi" by Takahashi Yu CD
We will give presents to those first 100 people who buy this CD
Please send your postcards to the address shown below
We are looking forward to it