Huh?
He's back again.
I think that's Nakao...
You know him?
He's in my class.
- He came yesterday too.
- You're kidding!
Huh? What? Why...
He must be suspicious of you, right?
Stop that.
Huh? What?
He must be after Kyuu-chan.
What?
A robot has come to our class.
The principal says we have to keep it a secret, at all costs, but...
...a crazy story like that...
...how would I be able to tell anyone?
To say, "my classmate is a robot"...
What do you want?
You... film over that way.
Ah, yes... that...
- Sorry. That was just a passing fancy.
- Huh?
I was just a little infatuated...
But... after I thought about it, she isn't even really my type...
What're you talking about?
- Which means, I'm free too.
- Okay. What're you doing?
Quit filming. Don't film me.
- 'Morning, Kageyama!
- 'Morning!
'Morning! See you there!
Again, today, we see a scene no different than any other day...
- Right?
- Yeah.
Good morning!
Too bad!
Huh? What is it?
- A stalker.
- What?
Someone's following Kyuuto.
That would never happen...
Nakao?
This is bad.
If he keeps following her like this... Just look...
He'll find out Kyuuto's a robot!
But... he's an otaku. He's not interested in girls, is he?
- Make Nakao give up on her.
- How?
- Figure it out!
- What does that... What?
- I'm counting on you.
- I can't.
- I'm counting on you, okay?
- No. Wait. I can't. It's impossible...
Wait! I can't. What?
"Into the sluggish, endless everyday..."
"...suddenly something sparkling has appeared..."
What?
"Always, we strive frantically to grasp that which shines..."
"...but if we hold it, for even a moment..."
"...we'll only return, once again, to the meaningless classroom."
"Sparkling"?
That's love.
Love?
But... we're talking about Nakao here...
I probably should have done that too...
- Fallen in love?
- Yeah.
It doesn't really matter with who... Just...
...going on a date.
A date?
You know, Ray Bradbury talks about them in his books...
Walking together at night holding hands...
And that night becomes once-in-a-lifetime...
Once-in-a-lifetime...
The only date you go on...
...a stroll at night...
Yeah.
I see... That's crazy.
Huh? Then what would you do?
I would...
I'd do something normal.
Normal?
Go see a movie together...
...then the two of us would laugh so hard we cry...
Huh?
I should've done it before I came...
That walk with someone at night...
That way, even if the surgery fails, I'd be able to think, "that's all right."
It's that big a thing?
Well... Anything that ties you to this world...
...is that big a thing.
Don't worry.
You'll be able to do it.
...that nighttime walk.
Then when I get back, it's a double date, right?
Something that holds me to this world...
- Wow! What should we choose?
- I don't know.
There's just too many.
- Hurry!
- Hold on. Hold on.
- Okay. On the count of three...
- Okay. Ready?
Ready, and... that one!
"Always we strive frantically to grasp that which shines..."
"...but if we hold it, for even a moment..."
"...we'll only return, once again, to the meaningless classroom."
I see.
Nakao...
...is in love.
[Kyuuto]
Episode 2
translation by sarujin
QC by sayochama
GIRIGIRI FANSUBS
NOT FOR SALE OR RENT
Hey. Filming me all the time. Is that really fun?
- Okay. Then I'll film some...
- Hey! Stupid. That's mine...
Let go!
Who was that? Do you know her?
Yamamoto?
Yamamoto...
It is Yamamoto!
That's Yamamoto...
Oh. That's a pick. It's probably Yamamoto's.
She plays guitar.
This is...
...a scale.
A... a scale?
A scale from what?
The Little Mermaid.
The Little Mermaid. Huh? Her?
Good morning.
Have you fallen in love with a human man?
Did you come to meet a human man?
Ogawa-sensei said to come right away!
- Excuse us!
- Did you lose your love?
For a human...
Okay.
Let's see...
Yamamoto is not the Little Mermaid. She's human.
She's always been human and always will be.
Understand?
But... the scale...
This is a pick. It's used to play guitar.
It's made of plastic.
- Plastic.
- Right.
So, you need to be sure to return it to Yamamoto. Okay?
- What about the Little Mermaid?
- She doesn't exist!
If you searched the whole world, you wouldn't find her anywhere!
She's made up! A complete lie!
But... in books...
There are lies written in books.
The Little Mermaid is... a lie.
That's right. A lie.
Complete nonsense.
Got it?
For what purpose?
What?
For what purpose... do humans write lies?
I don't know! How should I know?
Anyway, just don't call Yamamoto the Little Mermaid anymore!
Got it?
The Little Mermaid? Yes, I've heard of her.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Though she could only live in the sea she came on land.
I think that is extremely reckless.
Well, it's true it's stupid, but...
...I think she probably knew that she was pushing herself too hard by leaving the ocean to live on land.
But...
...she was completely infatuated with that human man.
"Infatuated"?
To be so in love that you forget things like eating and sleeping.
Is that a bad thing?
Well, you can't live a normal life that way...
But... if you don't have something like that, you can't keep going, right?
It's because you have that...
...that you think you'll be able to give it your best for another day, right?
Something I'm infatuated with? I guess, if I had to say, it'd be my work.
I love this place called "education" more than words can say...
That's who I am.
Vivian-chan, huh? She was a lovely girl...
Kouchou-sensei is...
...infatuated with work.
Well... I suppose that's what it means.
Sensei. Please return to your work.
Was I wrong to dispose of them?
No. I was getting rid of them, but...
...I wanted to say good-bye to each of them in turn.
Heita. Are you infatuated with anything right now?
Yeah...
Are you infatuated with Nakao-kun?
Yeah... Sorry. I have something to do, so...
Can you get home on your own?
Heita is infatuated with Nakao-kun.
What a coincidence.
You come here too?
What're you reading?
[Luna - Fullthrottle]
Wow...
Is it good?
She reminds me of someone...
Huh? What's wrong? Why are you running? Why are you running away?
Sorry.
I get it...
So that's why...
She looks like Kyuuto.
Hey.
Huh? What's wrong?
- What is it?
- No!
Wait! What?
What was that?
What kinds of things do women like to hear? What makes them happy?
"I will pay your rent."
What? No. That wouldn't...
Oh, and "I will pay for your health insurance."
No, that can't be...
If I could kiss you, hold you tight...
...would your inexperienced lips soften too?
You were so cool in your concert today!
Sorry.
This is private.
Let's go.
What do you think that was?
Who cares? Let's go.
I'm home.
Welcome home.
- Huh? What? What is it?
- Mom!
- Just... Just...
- What? What is it?
Right? Right?
What? What is it?
Under the light of the full moon...
...we'll blow out the 16th candle.
And after we've kissed for the 17th time...
Why did I never realize before now?
My little brother is Hajime!
It'll be our specialty...
This part!
This part.
Come on. Do that.
Huh? Me?
Come on. Just for a little while.
- "Our specialty..."
- What?
Come on. Do it!
"Our specialty..."
What is that? What is all this?
- Do it again!
- That's enough, isn't it?
Do it.
I've had enough!
- What do you think you're doing?
- Whose head do you think that is?
- It's my head!
- Shut up.
- Ow! Ow, ow, ow...
- Don't be so selfish...
Starting tomorrow you'll always wear your hair this way. It's decided.
Okay! I will! Ow!
Then, I'm going.
See you.
She's here.
You're so ugly. Do you really think Chaka is seriously going out with you?
Did you hear me? Say something.
- Hey, Ugly.
- Hey, Ugly! Stop right there!
You've gotta be kidding me. Why did you run, huh?
Don't ever go near Chaka again!
- You get it?
- Give me a break. Hello?
Don't try messing with us.
You think Chaka's serious about you?
- Don't come to his concerts.
- Don't ever get near him again.
You just stay away from him!
What's with you?
Ow, ow, ow!
Lemme go! What d'you think you're doing?
We surrender.
A white flag means "surrender."
What is wrong with you?
You cannot injure a person who has surrendered. That is a rule.
- She's freaking me out!
- We surrender.
We surrender!
Are you hurt?
That's not it.
I wanted to just die...
I seriously thought it'd be better if I died...
Is this place...
...the place you can go on living?
How is it?
What should I do?
I guess it'd be best if I came right out and told Nakao, huh?
Don't touch my woman.
"My woman"?
Hey.
I understand.
I'll stop.
Are you sure?
It wasn't as if it was Kyuuto-san that I liked in the first place, so...
Huh?
This is who I love.
Her. Right.
If, just if...
...you were able to go on a date or something...
Would that become a once-in-a-lifetime memory?
I mean, I say date, but I'm talking about going for a walk or something...
I-I-If...
...I were able to go on a w-walk with Luna-chan...
Luna-chan?
Ah. Luna-chan.
- I wouldn't mind paying 30 million yen!
- 30 million yen? You have that much?
How could a high school student have that much?
- But you said 30 million yen...
- I'm talking about a loan.
After I've graduated and gotten a steady job I'll pay you back in regular installments.
You...
That's amazing.
Huh?
What is?
Well, I mean... For going on a walk...
Then...
- ...I'll pay 40 million!
- Okay! I get it.
Then...
...as a final memory...
...you want to go on a date?
Then, after that, you can't ever follow her again.
Huh?
What? What? What is it? Huh?
I want to thank you, but I don't have anything, so...
No, no. I can't. It's too important.
Fukai, you may not understand this, but...
...this is how important this is to me!
- Fukai-kun!
- You scared me...
You aren't doing your hair like you did yesterday anymore?
You too?
- That Hajime guy...
- Fukai-kun, you're too loud.
- I'm never doing that again, ever.
- What? Please, just one more time!
- I'll do anything if you take pictures with me!
- No. No way.
- Please?
Not a chance.
Oh... For crying out loud...
Just a second...
Okay. Peace!
Like this?
That's enough, isn't it? Taking this many...
- A close up on Hajime.
- Huh?
I'm exhausted...
See you!
What? Is that Heita...
...taking pictures with a girl?
Here.
Thanks.
Now look... Okay?
I just look a lot like this "our specialty" idol. Okay?
That's why she asked me to take pictures with her. That's all.
That's all.
- It's fine. You don't have to try so hard...
- But I know you've got the wrong idea...
See? I know you've got the wrong idea about this.
Look, I told you didn't I?
Kawai doesn't mean anything special to me or anything...
No. She really doesn't. Really.
I had fun today.
You know...
Yes?
If it's okay with you, would you give me your phone's email address?
So that maybe I could get in touch with you...
Of course.
I don't really know how to...
Oh! Shall I do it?
I'm sorry. Thank you.
Why a telephone pole?
Well, I like them quite a bit, you see... telephone poles and stuff.
Oh. Really...
No, no. I don't really like them that much, but...
...sometimes I like the way the shape reminds me of the gates at shrines.
That's all.
Thank you for treating me to such a lovely day.
Oh. Would you like to go out for a few drinks after this? Just casually...
I'm sorry, today is a little...
- Please don't say that...
- No. It's true.
- Please!
- No, really.
I'll pay your rent!
What?
I'll pay for your health insurance too.
Oh! No! It's not like that! It's not!
It's not like that!
I'm sorry for calling you out here like this...
Well, it's about that thing, right? Taking pictures with Heita...
Don't worry. I won't tell anyone.
Oh. No. It isn't that...
It isn't?
The...
The fact that I like idols...
...I was hoping you wouldn't tell the others.
Because if people found out I'm an idol fanatic, they'd probably all be put off by it. Right?
I...
...I don't think you'd understand this, Kageyama-kun, but...
...but this is pretty serious.
I do understand.
What?
Because... I'm the same.
I mean, there's someone I like too, but...
...I know that if everyone found out, they'd freak out, so...
...I can't tell anyone the truth...
Kageyama-kun... You're not the way you appear, are you... You're gallant.
What?
You think so?
Could it be that the person you like...
What?
...is Hajime? Just like me?
No... Not exactly...
Then you like Yasu? That's great that we like different members.
- No... I...
- For a second I thought you'd copied me...
Oh. No. I didn't...
Oh. Then you know about Yasu's family, right?
Yasu's worked so hard all on his own, but his family ended up all split up...
The night I heard how long and hard Yasu's been working I cried!
Or maybe bawled?
- I cried too. Yeah.
- Right?
Because I mean on TV Yasu's supposed to be the funny one, but...
...behind the scenes he's suffered so much.
That's why... Unless we give him our understanding...
There's no other way to repay him, right?
Right. Yeah. You're right.
Right...
Huh? What's wrong?
I've never talked about this stuff anywhere but online, so...
Miracles do exist, don't they?
Right? They do don't they? Miracles...
Miracles. Miracles do exist.
Right?
Will you go on a date with Nakao?
Why?
It will make Nakao happy?
You're sure?
Heita loves Nakao-kun.
Huh? Why...
You are infatuated with Nakao-kun.
I told you you've got it wrong.
- Wrong?
- Yes.
Why would I be in love with someone like Nakao?
Then...
...why do you wish to make Nakao-kun happy?
Well...
Look.
There's a lot of stuff going on. Stuff you can't explain in a simple sentence.
Heita wishes to make Nakao-kun happy.
Again? That's true, but...
You love Nakao-kun.
- Okay. Then let's just leave it at that.
- Heita wishes to make Nakao-kun happy.
Heita is infatuated with Nakao-kun.
- Heita loves Nakao-kun.
- Okay! Let's just go home. Okay?
- Heita loves Nakao-kun...
- Okay. Yes, yes...
This part here... Make it round, very round, then pull this tight.
There. You see?
Hey! I'm taking a bath now.
What's this? He's already asleep, huh?
[Date. 10/22, 4 pm]
Sounds like fun... A date...
What's this? Kyuuto's going on a date?
Why didn't you tell me?
When did you get here?
You wouldn't be on a date?
Me? No, a singles-mixer.
You go on those...
Did you find anyone special?
"Special," he says.
Then what would you call it? Someone good?
"Someone good"...
No. That's not good enough.
Someone who complements you?
Now look...
Love is a revolution.
It turns everything you thought you knew upside-down and inside-out.
If it's just "someone who complements you" or "someone good"...
...nothing will turn inside-out, not in a million years.
I see...
Which means...
...love won't ever begin with someone of that caliber.
I see.
Give me a copy of those, okay? I want to check on Kyuuto.
See you!
E-excuse me!
Hm?
If... you did fall in love...
...and...
...everything you know turns upside down...
What happens to you after that?
There will be a different "you."
That... is love.
Chaka, what you love...
...isn't me, is it...
What?
White dresses...
...shoes with slender high heels...
...clean-cut shoulder length hair...
...small, cute bags...
What are you talking about?
I...
...the truth is, I'm not human.
What?
I'm a mermaid princess!
I've been forcing myself!
Chaka, can you come to this world?
You can't, can you?
After all, the places we live are different, right?
The place I can keep living...
Nakao-kun...
...do you think you will be able to give it your best for another day?
I do. Probably even the day after tomorrow, and the next day, and the day after that...I'll feel that way forever.
I promise.
It is a promise.
Here.
Oh. Welcome back.
These too...
I'll give you these later, when I've developed them.
Thank you.
I'll treasure them all my life.
Is this really enough to satisfy you?
It's more than enough.
Even if I become a useless, middle-aged businessman...
...as long as I have this, I think I'll be able to keep going.
This is really enough?
Well, there's no helping it, right?
The person I fell in love with...
...is 2-dimensional.
Heita.
Weeds!
Leaves.
Heita is infatuated with Nakao-kun.
Look, I've told you it's not like that, right?
Heita wishes to make Nakao-kun happy.
Now, look...
Kyuuto...
...is sleepy.
Huh? Wait... it's only a little further.
What? Wait... Wait! You're kidding me...
You've gotta be kidding me...
In a place like this?
Why do I have to be infatuated with someone like Nakao, huh?
The reason I wanted to make him happy...
...was that I thought he was admirable, better than me.
He can say, without hesitation, that he loves something that isn't human.
I'm probably...
...more of a coward than he is.
If it were me, I wouldn't be able to tell anyone...
...and I think I'd be afraid to admit that love even to myself.
What? Rain?
For a second...
...I thought it might be tears.
Moron.
That's not possible.
Nakao... said he wouldn't follow her around anymore.
Really? Thanks for that.
You like telephone poles?
What?
You gonna laugh?
No.
I'm a little bit moved...
By what?
I like steel towers.
What?
Really?
I always think people will laugh, so I never tell anyone though...
I completely understand. I'm the same.
I never tell anyone.
Most people don't understand this kind of stuff, right?
I wonder if it's okay...
Hm?
...to love something like that...
What're you talking about? Of course it is!
No matter what a person comes to love... it's fine.
What're you doing?
Hey there! It's n-nothing really.
Are you looking for something?
What are you looking for?
No. Well... it's a paper chopstick sleeve.
You wrote an important note on it?
No, no. It's sort of an old keepsake...
From what?
It's from a place I went to after my first paycheck, with a girl.
A date?
Yeah.
Wow... With Mom?
With someone else.
Not here, huh? Of course not...
I've had it all this time, never thrown it away...
...for it to get thrown out now...
You can't forget it, even now...
...even though it happened so long ago...
It's not like I'm still in love with her or anything.
But I want to hang on to the way I felt at the time.
I was so nervous, worried that the girl would see right through me...
But I wasn't afraid of anything.
I was completely fine, even with nothing.
I found it.
I found it!
Look. This is it! I found it!
I found the chopstick sleeve!
Just as Kubo had said...
...the things that tie us to this world...
...may be the smallest of things.
Here.
An evening stroll.
[It hurts when I laugh.]
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
"Always we strive frantically to grasp that which shines..."
There's a lot of depth to the world of idols...
"...but if we hold it, for even a moment..."
"...we'll only..."
"...return once again, to the meaningless classroom."
Good morning.
It seems that next week, Fujino, who has been on extended absence from school, will be returning, so...
...that desk, we'll need to clean it up, okay?
Who's Fujino?
I don't know.
Fujino's been out since the beginning of the semester, right?
Tsuki-chan...
Ogawa-sensei is here.
Fujino!
Let's give it our best, without pushing ourselves too hard, okay?
Tsuki-chan. Are you listening?
I'm sorry. Thank you for coming.
Hey!
You can come any time, okay?
Kyuuto-san.
Oh, right! Kyuuto-san, would you mind going like this for me?
Things that tie me to this world...
No matter what a person comes to love... it's fine.
It turns everything you thought you knew upside-down and inside-out.
That's adorable!
Ready, and... pose!
That's it...
So I...
...am in love...
[Kaidan no katasumi ni...]
In a corner, on the stairs...
[...suwari uzukumaru no ano hito ni...]
...that person cowering, crouched...
[...nani ga atta n darou]
...I wonder what happened.
[Ittai nani wo mitekita n darou]
What did that person see?
[Hitogomi no naka de...]
In a crowd of people...
[...niramiau danjou no aida ni...]
...that man and woman glare at each other...
[...nani ga okottarou]
...I wonder what happened between them.
[Ittai donna jijou ga atta n darou]
What circumstances led them there?
[Itsuka boku wo yobidashita...]
Once, you called me outside...
[...sensei ga donatteta sono scene ha...]
...and the teacher yelled. That scene...
[...donna dattarou]
...I wonder what it looked like.
[Ittai boku ha nani wo shitta n darou]
What on earth did I learn from it?
[Itsu kara ka tsuzuiteru...]
On the other side...
[...sensou no hate ni donna koto ga...]
...of this war that's lasted since who knows when...
[...matteru n darou]
...I wonder what waits for us.
[Soushite boku ni nani ga dekiru n darou]
And what can I do?
[Koto no shinsou ha nani mo...]
The truth of things...
[...shitteiru you de shirienai...]
...we feel like we know, but we can't learn...
[Sore demo dou ni ka kou ni ka...]
Even so, somehow or another...
[...ikiteita naka ga nai]
...It's like we were never here.
[Muda ga atteba tarirarenai]
It's not enough to meet with futility...
[Demo shinjirareru mono mo sukunai]
But there are too few things to believe in...
[Tada hitotsu tashika na no ha boku no kimochi]
The only certain thing is my feelings...
[Kimi no sono koe wo kikashite yo]
Let me hear that voice of yours
[Shinjireru mono ga soko ni aru yo]
That's where I find something to believe in
[Tada hitotsu tashika na no ha omae to no toki]
The only certain thing is my time with you...
[Kimi ga suki]
I love you
All that's left is passion.
A friend has poked their nose into dangerous business.
Being human or not doesn't matter...
Being able to worry for others, and being worried about by others...
Isn't that enough?
Nakao!
Fukai...
A mark? On Fukai's chest?
Say you aren't. Scream it at the top of your lungs.
I'm not ugly!
I'm Fujino.
The same wind never blows twice.
Amidst all of that... we live.